[
    {
        "id": 1,
        "Question": "Choose the incorrect statement regarding the need for quality.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Markets have become more competitive",
            "b) Quality provides sustained performance",
            "c) Quality provides customer satisfaction",
            "d) It is the trend nowadays to introduce quality"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Due to an increase in marketing competitiveness, quality is desired in any organization. Due to systematic standards and procedures involved, it will provide sustained performance. Consequently, we will have customer satisfaction. It is wrong to interpret that quality is necessary because it is a global trend.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 2,
        "Question": "Michael bought a new washing machine which is not performing its primary function of washing clothes properly. What should the executive at customer care suggest Michael?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To sell the washing machine",
            "b) To buy a new washing machine",
            "c) To assure the customer that a specialist will visit their house the following day",
            "d) To lease the washing machine"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A new washing machine is not washing clothes properly is definitely a disappointment for the customer. To ensure customer satisfaction the executive at customer care very rightly assured that the specialist will look into the reasons for malfunctioning of the washing machine. It is incorrect to suggest selling, buying or leasing the washing machine without even looking at the problem.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 3,
        "Question": "Quality is fitness for use. Identify the quality guru who said this.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Deming",
            "b) Crosby",
            "c) Juran",
            "d) Taguchi"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Juran said that quality is fitness for use. The concept of fitness for use is applied to all products and services.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 4,
        "Question": "How can quality be quantified? (Q=Quality, P=Performance, E=Expectations)",
        "Options": [
            "a) Q=P/E",
            "b) Q=P+E",
            "c) Q=P-E",
            "d) Q=P*E"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Mathematically, quality can be quantified as Q=P/E. Here, if Q is greater than 1, the customer has a good feeling about the performance of the product or service.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 5,
        "Question": "Quality is conformance to requirements. Identify the quality guru who said this.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ishikawa",
            "b) Crosby",
            "c) Ohno",
            "d) Deming"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Crosby said that quality is conformance to requirements. Here, requirements mean both product requirements and customer requirements.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 6,
        "Question": "Quality is a predictable degree of uniformity and dependability at a low cost and suited to the market. Identify the quality guru who said this.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ishikawa",
            "b) Shingo",
            "c) Deming",
            "d) Harrington"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Deming said that quality is a predictable degree of uniformity and dependability at low cost and suited to the market. Deming’s ‘14 points’ is widely used in quality improvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 7,
        "Question": "What does the abbreviation A.S.Q stand for?",
        "Options": [
            "a) American Society for Quality",
            "b) American Standard of Quality",
            "c) Asian Society for Quality",
            "d) Asian Standard for Quality"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A.S.Q. stands for American Society for Quality. It is a community of quality professionals. It was established on February 16, 1946. George D. Edwards was its first president.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 8,
        "Question": "Quality is in its essence, a way of managing the organization. Identify the quality guru who said this.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Deming",
            "b) Juran",
            "c) Feigenbaum",
            "d) Shingo"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: According to Deming’s Quality Chain Reaction, quality improvement results in improved productivity, profits, customer satisfaction, and market share. It also results in reduced prices and costs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 9,
        "Question": "Quality is the minimum loss imparted by a product to society from the time product is shipped. Identify the quality guru who said this.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Shingo",
            "b) Taguchi",
            "c) Crosby",
            "d) Juran"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Feigenbaum said that quality is in its essence, a way of managing the organization. He developed the concept of Total Quality Control which in turn led to the concept of Total Quality Management.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 10,
        "Question": "Shawn ordered pizza online. He received the pizza 15 minutes before the scheduled delivery time. He also received cash back on the amount he had paid for the pizza. What can you infer?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer expectation of the service is less than customer perception of the service",
            "b) Customer expectation of the service is equal to the customer perception of the service",
            "c) Customer expectation of the service is greater than customer perception of the service",
            "d) Customer expectation of the service and customer perception of the service cannot be compared"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Taguchi said that quality is the minimum loss imparted by a product to society from the time product is shipped. He also introduced the concept of the loss function.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 11,
        "Question": "The systematic activities and planned activities which provide adequate confidence that the manufactured products are meeting the requirements is called ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality assurance",
            "b) Quality control",
            "c) Inspection",
            "d) Sampling"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: This definition is given by the ISO (International Organization for Standardization). It is a universally accepted definition of quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 12,
        "Question": "Choose the incorrect statement related to quality improvement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reduces rework",
            "b) Leads to greater uniformity of product",
            "c) Increases output with lowered cost",
            "d) Increases machine time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The primary service was to deliver the pizza within the scheduled delivery time in good condition. By arriving early and providing cash back, the customer expectation of the service must be less than the customer perception of the service.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 13,
        "Question": "A senior quality engineer during a training session trains his juniors about a particular common defect that has been found in their assembly. He has formulated a plan which will rectify the defect and ensure that the same defect does not pass further to the customers.  Which of the following inference is incorrect?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The organization has ensured that customer satisfaction is retained",
            "b) The juniors will be capable of preventing the defect to pass further to the customers",
            "c) The senior has understood that quality is correcting and preventing the loss, not living with loss",
            "d) The customer forced them to rectify the defect"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Quality assurance is the systematic activities and planned activities which provide adequate confidence that the manufactured products are meeting the requirements. Quality control is a system of routine technical activities to measure and control the quality of products. Inspection is the formal evaluation of certain characteristics in a product to determine its acceptability. Sampling is a statistical analysis process.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 14,
        "Question": "The two categories of products are _____ and _____",
        "Options": [
            "a) Goods, Services",
            "b) Media, Education",
            "c) Pencil, Car",
            "d) Hospitality, Calculator"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Product is the output of any process. Goods and Services are the two types of products. A pencil, car, and a calculator are types of Goods. Similarly, media, hospitality, and education fall under the category of Services.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 15,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not fit in the category of Goods?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cell phone",
            "b) Television",
            "c) Insurance",
            "d) Bike"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Cell phones, television, and bike are considered as Goods. Insurance fits into the category of Service.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 16,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not fit in the category of Services?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Banking",
            "b) Transportation",
            "c) Pen",
            "d) Health care industries"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Banking, transportation and health care industries come under the Service category of a product. A pen fits into the Goods category of a product.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 17,
        "Question": "The property that is possessed with a product and that is intended to meet certain customers’ needs and thereby provide customer satisfaction is called _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Product Tree",
            "b) Product Feature",
            "c) Product Cycle",
            "d) Product Design"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Service is performed for someone else. Service also includes support activities within companies, e.g., payroll preparation, secretarial support, and plant maintenance.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 18,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not fit in the category of Product Feature?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Fuel consumption of a vehicle",
            "b) Dimensions of a mechanical component",
            "c) The owner of the product",
            "d) The viscosity of a chemical"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The property that is possessed by a product and that is intended to meet certain customer’s needs and thereby provide customer satisfaction is called a product feature. It refers to the quality of design.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 19,
        "Question": "Someone who receives or is affected by the product or process is called a _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer",
            "b) Manager",
            "c) Founder",
            "d) Co-founder"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Fuel consumption of a vehicle, dimensions of a mechanical component, the viscosity of a chemical, the uniformity of the voltage of an electric power supply are some of the examples of product features. The owner of the product is not a product feature.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 20,
        "Question": "The two types of customers are ______ and ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Founder, Co-founder",
            "b) Internal, External",
            "c) Government, People",
            "d) CEO, CFO"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The customer is someone who receives or is affected by the product or process. It can be a person or it can also be a company.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 21,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not fit in the category of External Customers?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Clients/end users who buy the product",
            "b) Government regulatory bodies",
            "c) Manager of a company",
            "d) Public"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Customers can be either internal or external. The customers outside the company who pay for the goods or services offered are called external customers. The customers who are related to the company and who may or may not pay for the goods or services offered are called internal customers.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 22,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not fit in the category of Internal Customers?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stakeholders",
            "b) Public",
            "c) Shareholders",
            "d) Employees of a company"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The manager of the company is an internal customer. He doesn’t make any purchase for the goods or services offered by the company but his presence and his responsibilities hold tremendous importance to the company.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 23,
        "Question": "Sam purchased a pen from the market. The pen was not working clearly, legibly and smoothly. Where did the manufacturer fail in terms of satisfying the needs of the customer?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The manufacturer failed to satisfy the implied need of the product",
            "b) The manufacturer failed to impress his boss",
            "c) The manufacturer failed to maintain the reputation of the company",
            "d) The manufacturer failed to impress his supplier"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The public pays for the service they receive and hence they are external customers. The stakeholders and shareholders are indirect internal customers. The employees of the company are direct internal customers.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 24,
        "Question": "The state of affairs in which customers feel that their expectations have been met by the product features is known as ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer Satisfaction",
            "b) Customer Attraction",
            "c) Customer Loyalty",
            "d) Customer Reputation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The manufacturer failed to satisfy the implied need of the product. Every product has certain stated and implied needs associated with it. The manufacturer may have failed to impress his boss, maintain the reputation of the company but all these failures do not have a relation with customer satisfaction. The manufacturer could have actually complained to the supplier if the raw materials were found defective.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 25,
        "Question": "The state of affairs in which deficiencies (in goods or services) result in customer annoyance and complaints is known as ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer Compliance",
            "b) Customer Needs",
            "c) Customer Trust",
            "d) Customer Dissatisfaction"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For example, the price range of a car is a stated need. Similarly, a specific function of the car can also be considered to be a stated need of the customer.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 26,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a measure of Product Deficiency?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Errors",
            "b) Defects",
            "c) Off-specification",
            "d) Mass of the mobile phone"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The state of affairs in which customers feel that their expectations have been met by the product features is known as customer satisfaction. A newly bought laptop performing all its intended functions will bring in customer satisfaction.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 27,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a dimension of ‘product quality’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Machinability",
            "b) Probability",
            "c) Customer Satisfaction",
            "d) Durability"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: There are 9 dimensions of ‘product quality’. The dimensions of product quality are performance, features, conformance, reliability, durability, serviceability, responsiveness, aesthetics, and reputation.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 28,
        "Question": "The nominal size of a product is 30 mm. The acceptable industrial limits are from 29.98 mm to 30.02 mm. After manufacturing, the quality engineer finds the lower limit of the manufactured product to be 29.00 mm while the upper limit is 30.01 mm. What can you infer from the given scenario?",
        "Options": [
            "a) There is no failure because both the upper and lower limits of the manufactured product are within the industrial standard limits",
            "b) There is a failure because the upper limit is below 30.02 mm",
            "c) There is a failure because the lower limit is below 29.98 mm",
            "d) We cannot comment on the failure of the dimensions of the manufactured product"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The manufactured product fails to comply with the industrial standards of the product. The lower limit of the manufactured product has to be within the range of 29.98 mm to 30 mm. The upper limit of the manufactured product has no issues because 30.01 mm lies between 30 mm and 30.02 mm.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 29,
        "Question": "Priyanka bought a new mobile phone for herself. She explained to her friend that the mobile phone has a camera, Facebook facility, and music facility in addition to the basic functions like phone calls and messaging. Which dimension of ‘product quality’ is Priyanka referring to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Aesthetics",
            "b) Conformance",
            "c) Features",
            "d) Reputation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Features are the secondary characteristics of a product. Here, camera, Facebook facility, and music facility are the features of a mobile phone. The facility of phone calls and messaging are its primary characteristics.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 30,
        "Question": "Suresh calls up the customer care to complain regarding his new earphones. He can’t listen to the other side when his earphones are connected to his mobile phone. Which dimension of ‘product quality’ has the earphones failed to comply with?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Performance",
            "b) Features",
            "c) Aesthetics",
            "d) Reputation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ‘performance’ of the new earphone is not acceptable. The primary function of an earphone is not met here.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 31,
        "Question": "Andrew bought a new mobile phone from the market. While studying its specifications, he realizes that the mobile phone fails to comply with the national standards. Which dimension of ‘product quality’ has the mobile phone failed in?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reputation",
            "b) Aesthetics",
            "c) Durability",
            "d) Conformance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Every product has to meet certain applicable standards. Here, the mobile phone fails to comply with the national standards and hence ‘conformance’ is not met.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 32,
        "Question": "Which dimension of product quality tells you about the probability that a product will perform its function for a given period of time under specified conditions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Aesthetics",
            "b) Reputation",
            "c) Reliability",
            "d) Conformance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Reliability is the probability that a product will perform its function for a given period of time under specified conditions. It can be measured with the help of mean time between failures.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 33,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the primary characteristic of an electric kettle while referring to its ‘performance’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It should boil water efficiently",
            "b) It should indicate the pouring temperature of the water",
            "c) It should be red in color",
            "d) It should be white in color"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The primary characteristic of an electric kettle is to boil water effectively. The color of its outer surface is the aesthetic aspect of it. The pouring temperature of the water could be an additional feature in it.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 34,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the best MTBF for a newly purchased laptop?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 month",
            "b) 2 years",
            "c) 3 years",
            "d) 5 years"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: MTBF refers to mean time between failures for a repairable product. Higher value of MTBF of the laptop is desired for customer satisfaction. So, MTBF for a newly purchased laptop which is least here is 1 month. It is ruled out as it is not the best.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 35,
        "Question": "Ramesh called customer care to complain about his defective printer. The customer care tells him that it takes 2 months to repair the kind of defect Ramesh is facing with the printer. Which dimension of ‘product quality’ is poorly reflected here?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Features",
            "b) Aesthetics",
            "c) Reputation",
            "d) Serviceability"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The ‘serviceability’ of the product is poorly reflected. A defect in a printer taking 2 months is not acceptable. The service must be faster.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 36,
        "Question": "Paul found a defect in his newly purchased television set. He called the customer care to tell about the problem. The customer care told him to write an offline application and send it to the retailer. The retailer will then take it forward to the service center. After this, it will take 2 months to repair the television set. Which dimension of ‘product quality’ is poorly reflected here?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Features",
            "b) Aesthetics",
            "c) Serviceability",
            "d) Reputation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The service of the product must have been easier. The service of the television set is not only slow but it is also very difficult for the customer as he has to first write an application for his problem and then send it to the retailer. He has to also then wait for the retailer who will carry forward his problem to the service center.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 37,
        "Question": "Surya inspected his newly purchased bicycle and found a defect on its saddle. He tells the manufacturer about it. The manufacturer charges ₹5000 for repairing it.  Which dimension of ‘product quality’ is poorly reflected here?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Aesthetics",
            "b) Features",
            "c) Serviceability",
            "d) Reputation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The serviceability of the bicycle must have been economical. But here the manufacturer is charging too much for a defect in a newly purchased bicycle.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 38,
        "Question": "Which dimension of ‘product quality’ is best reflected when a manufacturer ensures multiple slots in a mobile phone for different sized sim cards?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Responsiveness",
            "b) Serviceability",
            "c) Aesthetics",
            "d) Reputation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: People use nano – sim cards, micro – sim cards as well as regular size sim cards. Multiple slots in a mobile phone ensure the use of multiple sim cards in a single mobile phone.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 39,
        "Question": " Rajesh went to the market to purchase a khadi cloth for his father. The khadi cloth which the shopkeeper showed him was white in color, but it had patches of dust over it at many places. Which dimension of ‘product quality’ was poorly reflected by the shopkeeper?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reputation",
            "b) Serviceability",
            "c) Durability",
            "d) Aesthetics"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The presence of patches of dust resulted in customer dissatisfaction. The shopkeeper must have looked at the ‘aesthetic’ aspect of the product before displaying the khadi cloth to Rajesh.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 40,
        "Question": "The dimension of ‘product quality’ which appreciates agile manufacturing is ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Aesthetics",
            "b) Reputation",
            "c) Responsiveness",
            "d) Conformance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Agile manufacturing refers to techniques that are being utilized by an organization to respond quickly to customer needs and also be prepared for market changes while still holding its quality standards. Responsiveness also appreciates the techniques used to satisfy the changes in customer needs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 41,
        "Question": "Nancy went to purchase a new refrigerator for her house. She finds scratches on most of the refrigerators at the shop. Which dimension of ‘product quality’ is poorly reflected here?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Aesthetics",
            "b) Reputation",
            "c) Durability",
            "d) Reliability"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The presence of scratches will affect Nancy’s choice of purchasing the refrigerator. The shopkeeper should ensure that all the products are ‘scratch-free’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 42,
        "Question": "Company X, Company Y, and Company Z are mobile manufacturers. They have been in the market for 10 years. Company X has the record of solving all the problems reported by their customers while Company Y and Company Z have the record of solving 80%  and 85% of the problems reported by their customers respectively. Which company will have the highest reputation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Company X",
            "b) Company Y",
            "c) Company Z",
            "d) Reputation cannot be compared"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: As Company X has solved all the problems reported by its customers, it has the highest reputation. Company Y and Company Z must study the methods adopted by Company X to solve customer complaints.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 43,
        "Question": "Rahul had booked a room in a 5-star hotel. After he checked in at his hotel room he was angry on finding that his bed sheet was filthy. Which dimension of ‘service quality’ was poorly reflected?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Tangibles",
            "b) Reliability",
            "c) Responsiveness",
            "d) Empathy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Tangibles refers to the appearance of the service that is being provided. It is a dimension of ‘service quality’. By providing a dirty bed sheet the customer got angry and this resulted in customer dissatisfaction.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 44,
        "Question": "Manoj went to buy a washing machine. On top of the washing machine, it was mentioned that free service will be provided every 3 months until one year is completed. Manoj approached the shopkeeper to get a confirmation on the authenticity of the statement. Which dimension of ‘service quality’ was Manoj focusing on?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Empathy",
            "b) Aesthetics",
            "c) Reliability",
            "d) Reputation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Reliability as a dimension of ‘service quality’ focuses on the authenticity of the promised service. Here, Manoj wanted a confirmation from the shopkeeper that free service will be provided to him. An assurance from the shopkeeper will convince Manoj to buy the washing machine.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 45,
        "Question": "At Bengaluru Airport, Karan was surprised by the help he received from the staff at the airport. He was worried about the standard procedures like collecting boarding pass and security check-in. But the staff overwhelmingly helped him overcome all the difficulties. Which dimension of ‘service quality’ was strongly promoted by the staff at the airport?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Aesthetics",
            "b) Features",
            "c) Empathy",
            "d) Reputation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Empathy refers to the care that is provided to customers. Here, the staff proved to be a great help for Karan. By overcoming his difficulties by providing individual attention, empathy was strongly promoted.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 46,
        "Question": "Manish had purchased a ticket from a famous airline for his upcoming business meeting in London. He had injured his left leg a couple of days back and needed wheelchair assistance. He called the airline customer service and asked for wheelchair assistance. He was not only promised wheelchair assistance but also pick-up and drop facility. Which dimension of ‘service quality’ was strongly promoted here?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Assurance",
            "b) Features",
            "c) Aesthetics",
            "d) Reputation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Assurance refers to the knowledge and courtesy of the staff who provide customer service and their ability to convey trust and confidence.  By assuring Manish of wheelchair assistance, a sense of confidence was promoted. In addition to this, pick-up and drop facility was also provided which augmented customer satisfaction.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 47,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a technique to study the ‘service quality gap’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Surveys",
            "b) Online Research",
            "c) Focus Groups",
            "d) Asking the boss of the company"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Surveys, Online Research, and Focus Groups are exploratory research techniques to identify the service quality gap. The difference between customer expectations and customer perceptions at the time of service is called service quality gap.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 48,
        "Question": "Which of the following is incorrect while referring to challenges faced while ensuring service quality?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer expectations change over a period of time",
            "b) Different customers can have different expectations",
            "c) Customer expectations do not change at all",
            "d) Knowledge of all customers about the service may not be the same"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Customer expectations change over a period of time and different customers can have different expectations. These results in variation in service quality desired. In addition to this, all customers do not have the same knowledge of the service being provided.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 49,
        "Question": "If the time taken to respond to customer complaints is less, which dimension of ‘service quality’ is strongly promoted?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Responsiveness",
            "b) Aesthetics",
            "c) Empathy",
            "d) Durability"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The responsiveness refers to the quickness with which customer problems are dealt with. With a short response time, the responsiveness of the service is strongly promoted here.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 50,
        "Question": "Company A and Company B are two social networking service companies. It has been found that Company A shares a user’s private information with undetectable sources while Company B is not accused of any such activities. Which dimension of ‘service quality’ is at stake?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Security",
            "b) Empathy",
            "c) Responsiveness",
            "d) Durability"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The security of all the users who have an account in company A is at stake. The user could have many personal details that are not supposed to be shared with anybody. Definitely, Company B has provided security and will be most preferred.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 51,
        "Question": "Amit is a Hindi speaking person. He resides in Chennai. He had to visit the Passport Office in Chennai to rectify some of the problems he was facing. He was surprised to find the staff at the Passport Office speaking in different languages. Name the dimension of ‘service quality’ which was enforced.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Communication",
            "b) Security",
            "c) Timeliness",
            "d) Durability"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ability to inform the customers in the language they understand is promoted here. Amit will now have no problem in understanding the technicalities involved in rectifying the errors in his passport.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 52,
        "Question": "Company P and Q are two famous clothing companies in the city. Customers have complained that the staff at Company P are unaware of modern trends and seem to take no interest in understanding customer expectations. The staff at Company Q is knowledgeable and is aware of modern trends. What can you infer?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Company P is more competent than Company Q",
            "b) Company Q is more competent than Company P",
            "c) Company P is at the same level as Company Q in terms of competency",
            "d) Competency cannot be compared"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Company Q is more competent than Company P. The fact that Company Q has a knowledgeable workforce provides customer trust and confidence to buy cloth. Company P must ensure that its staff become more knowledgeable and know the modern trends. Employee training can solve the issue.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 53,
        "Question": "If all the service promised according to the time commitments are met then __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Timeliness is established",
            "b) Durability is found",
            "c) The service looks attractive",
            "d) Empathy is considered"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Consider the pizza that you order online. If the person who is assigned to deliver your food comes early you are overjoyed. Hence, timeliness, the quality of being on time is important to establish customer satisfaction.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 54,
        "Question": "If an organization commits to 10 promises and if all the promises are met, then which ‘service quality’ dimension is strongly promoted?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Completeness",
            "b) Timeliness",
            "c) Competence",
            "d) Tangibles"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If all the promises are met then completeness is achieved. By meeting all the promises committed, the organization has ensured completeness is achieved. We cannot comment on the timeliness because we have no information about the time taken to meet the promises. Competence refers to the skill and knowledge possessed by the organization. Tangibles referto the appearance of the service which is received.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 55,
        "Question": "If an organization focuses on trustworthiness and belief considering the customer’s best interests, which dimension of ‘service quality’ is focused on by the organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Credibility",
            "b) Aesthetics",
            "c) Durability",
            "d) Timeliness"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Every successful organization has always focused on credibility. Credibility ensures that in times when the organization’s reputation is at stake the trust of the customer remains intact. It helps them in re-establishing themselves.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 56,
        "Question": "Raju goes to the office from 9 am – 6 pm. He had enrolled himself at a gym center near his office. The gym is open from 6 am – 10 pm. Consider the timings of engagements of both Raju and the gym center, which dimension of ‘service quality’ is strongly promoted?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Timeliness",
            "b) Accessibility and Convenience",
            "c) Credibility",
            "d) Reputation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: With reference to the timings, Accessibility and Convenience are strongly promoted. Raju can choose to go to the gym either before his time at the office or after his office hours are over. This flexibility in timings ensures customer satisfaction not just for Raju but also for all the office going people registered at the gym center.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 57,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a dimension of ‘service quality’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Durability",
            "b) Serviceability",
            "c) Conformance",
            "d) Consistency"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Consistency is a ‘service quality’ dimension. It refers to the act of committing to the same level of customer service every time irrespective of who the customer is. Durability, Serviceability, and Conformance are dimensions of ‘product quality’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 58,
        "Question": "What is TQM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Total Quality Management",
            "b) Total Quality Maintenance",
            "c) Total Quality Mitigation",
            "d) Total Quality Managers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Total means made up of ‘whole’. Quality means the degree of excellence that needs to be achieved keeping customer satisfaction in mind. Management refers to the activities that are involved in establishing the highest degree of quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 59,
        "Question": "TQM is the management approach of an organization, centered on quality, based on the participation of all its members and aiming at long-term success through customer satisfaction, and benefits to all members of the organization and to society. Which organization had given this definition of TQM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Total Quality Forum of USA",
            "b) Indian Statistical Institute",
            "c) ISO",
            "d) ASQ"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: According to ISO, TQM is the management approach of an organization, centered on quality, based on the participation of all its members and aiming at long-term success through customer satisfaction, and benefits to all members of the organization and to society. ISO refers to the International Organization for Standardization. It was founded on February 23, 1947, to promote worldwide proprietary, industrial and commercial standards.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 60,
        "Question": "TQM is an integrated organizational approach in delighting customers (both internal and external) by meeting their expectations on a continuous basis through everyone involved with the organization working on continuous improvement in all products, services, and processes along with proper problem-solving methodology. Which organization had given this definition of TQM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Total Quality Forum of USA",
            "b) ISO",
            "c) Indian Statistical Institute",
            "d) ASQ"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: According to the  Indian Statistical Institute, TQM is an integrated organizational approach in delighting customers (both internal and external) by meeting their expectations on a continuous basis through everyone involved with the organization working on continuous improvement in all products, services, and processes along with proper problem-solving methodology. ISI was established on 17 December 1931 and is an academic institute of national importance focusing on statistics.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 61,
        "Question": "TQM is a people-focused management system that aims at a continual increase in customer satisfaction at a continually lower cost. TQM is a total system approach (not a separate area or program), and an integral part of a high-level strategy. It works horizontally across functions and departments, involving all employees, top to bottom, and exceeds backward and forward to include the supply chain and the customer chain. Which organization had given this definition of TQM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Total Quality Forum of USA",
            "b) ISO",
            "c) Indian Statistical Institute",
            "d) ASQ"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to Total Quality Forum of USA, TQM is a people-focused management system that aims at a continual increase in customer satisfaction at a continually lower cost. TQM is a total system approach (not a separate area or program), and an integral part of a high-level strategy. It works horizontally across functions and departments, involving all employees, top to bottom, and exceeds backward and forward to include the supply chain and the customer chain. This definition has been accepted by many academic papers and is considered to be one of the best definitions of TQM.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 62,
        "Question": "Which ‘pillar of TQM’ is referred to when the study of customer needs is done, the requirements of the customer are gathered, and customer satisfaction is measured and managed?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process Management",
            "b) Employee Empowerment",
            "c) Continuous Improvement",
            "d) Customer Focus"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Customer Focus is one of the pillars of TQM. In customer focus, customer satisfaction remains an organization’s highest priority. The other pillars of TQM are Process Management, Employee Empowerment, and Continuous Improvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 63,
        "Question": "Which ‘pillar of TQM’ refers to the act of developing a production process that reduces product variations, and by application of this process, the same product with the same level of quality is produced every time?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process Management",
            "b) Employee Empowerment",
            "c) Continuous Improvement",
            "d) Customer Focus"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Process Management is one of the pillars of TQM. The relationship between the teams and internal customers plays a crucial role in developing the production process that reduces product variations. The focus of the management is on controlling the overall process, and rewarding teamwork.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 64,
        "Question": "Which ‘pillar of TQM’ refers to TQM’s environment of a committed and well-trained workforce that participates in activities involving quality improvement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process Management",
            "b) Employee Empowerment",
            "c) Continuous Improvement",
            "d) Customer Focus"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Employee Empowerment is one of the pillars of TQM. It is the human side of quality. Employee Empowerment is achieved with the help of training of employees to achieve customer satisfaction.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 65,
        "Question": "Which ‘pillar of TQM’ recognizes that product quality is a result of process quality?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process Management",
            "b) Employee Empowerment",
            "c) Continuous Improvement",
            "d) Customer Focus"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Continuous Improvement is one of the pillars of TQM. The output of a production process must not only satisfy customer needs but the customer must feel satisfied with the product. Hence, continuous improvement in the production process plays a crucial role in delivering quality products.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 66,
        "Question": "Company M has short-term goals like achieving the predicted quarterly profit. Company N has long-term goals like achieving sustained customer satisfaction. What can you infer about the management culture?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Company M follows traditional management, Company N follows TQM",
            "b) Company N follows traditional management, Company M follows TQM",
            "c) Company M and Company N follows traditional management",
            "d) Company M and Company N follows TQM"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In traditional management, quality is determined by the organization and it has its own quality standards. Every product is compared to this standard to determine if it is acceptable or not. In TQM, the customer is the judge for product quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 67,
        "Question": "The manager of a company is known to threaten his employees for the presence of a defect. What can you infer about the management culture?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Traditional Management",
            "b) Total Quality Management",
            "c) Supply Chain Management",
            "d) Sales Management"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Company M has a short term goal to achieve the predicted quarterly profit which is one of the characteristics of traditional management. Company N has a long term goal which is to sustain customer satisfaction. Customer satisfaction is TQM’s highest priority.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 68,
        "Question": "A company is known to have a reward policy for its employees. The manager gives its employees a chance to improve if a mistake is conducted by them. What can you infer about the management culture?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Traditional Management",
            "b) Total Quality Management",
            "c) Supply Chain Management",
            "d) Sales Management"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In traditional management, individual employees are held accountable for the presence of a defect and those employees are identified by the managers. In TQM, managers and employees focus on improving the process to ensure that defects don’t occur in the future in order to ensure customer satisfaction.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 69,
        "Question": "In Company A, the workers who are involved in producing a product are responsible for its quality. In Company B, everyone in the organization including the top executives is responsible for producing quality products. What can you infer about the management culture?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Company A follows traditional management, Company B follows TQM",
            "b) Company B follows traditional management, Company A follows TQM",
            "c) Company A and Company B follows traditional management",
            "d) Company A and Company B follows TQM"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Here, the act of threatening employees is the traditional management approach. As a result of this, there is a void in the relation between the workforce and the manager. The manager may even fire its employees.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 70,
        "Question": "In Company E, the supervisors and employees solve problems based on their individual knowledge, skills, and instincts. In Company F, everyone in the organization solves problems based on substantive data. What can you infer about the management culture?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Company E follows traditional management, Company F follows TQM",
            "b) Company F follows traditional management, Company E follows TQM",
            "c) Company E and Company F follows traditional management",
            "d) Company E and Company F follows TQM"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The working environment, in this case, is suitable for the employees. There is a strong bonding between the managers and employees. The reward policy keeps the employees motivated towards achieving organizational goals focusing on customers. The chance to improve themselves when a mistake is committed helps employees to introspect themselves.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 71,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a principle of TQM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Product-centered system",
            "b) Customer-focus",
            "c) Intermittent improvement",
            "d) Decisions made by top executives only"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: TQM is a management approach that aims to attain customer satisfaction and plans for long-term success. It is a process-centered system, focuses on continuous improvement and decision-making involves the involvement of all the employees.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 72,
        "Question": "To attain customer satisfaction, which of the following is mandatory in TQM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Total employee involvement",
            "b) Manager involvement",
            "c) Founder involvement",
            "d) Co-founder involvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The customer is the judge of the quality of goods or services. Even though a company may have excellent training facilities, it may have improved its processes or upgraded its technology, but if customer satisfaction is not attained then it is of no use.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 73,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a principle of TQM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process-centered",
            "b) Product-centered",
            "c) External customer focus only",
            "d) Internal customer focus only"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Total employee involvement is one of the principles of TQM. Employee involvement can be fully utilized to its full potential when there is no workplace fear, empowerment is done, and when a proper working environment is established.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 74,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a principle of TQM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Product-centered system",
            "b) Integrated system",
            "c) Intermittent improvement",
            "d) Decisions made by top executives only"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: TQM is a process-centered system with continuous improvement philosophy. Decision-Making involves everyone in the company. The focus is towards both external and internal customers.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 75,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the kind of planning approach a company following TQM follows?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Strategic, random approach",
            "b) Strategic, systematic approach",
            "c) Random approach",
            "d) Normal approach"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: It is a TQM technique in which a company is compared with other companies with the aim to improve the deficiencies in internal processes. The best standards are determined and the scope for improvement is recognized. It can be used as a performance measuring tool also.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 76,
        "Question": "What is the kind of focus put in a company’s processes in TQM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Unsteady improvement",
            "b) Passive improvement",
            "c) Continual improvement",
            "d) Steady improvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Traditionally, organizations are organized into vertically structured departments. But TQM keeps the departments horizontally and focuses on interconnecting importance. The various departments and their functions have interdependence on each other. This becomes TQM’s focus.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 77,
        "Question": "Decisions in a company which follows TQM is _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Taken on the basis of the manager’s knowledge",
            "b) Taken on the basis of the founder’s knowledge",
            "c) Taken on the basis of the co-founder’s knowledge",
            "d) Fact-based"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The systematic and strategic planning that considers quality as a vital component in TQM’s focus. It is done to achieve the company’s vision, mission, and goals. It requires the involvement of everyone in the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 78,
        "Question": "For proper implementation of TQM, we need ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) To form a confidential group within the company",
            "b) To have two managers in the company",
            "c) To have effective communication between employees",
            "d) To have intermittent communication between employees"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: TQM is a process centered system. The main focus is to attain customer satisfaction. To achieve this, continuous process improvement is required to attain the highest degree of excellence in one’s goods or services.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 79,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an idea that can be incorporated by top management in a company to develop the Total Quality Program of a company?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Management meetings",
            "b) Focus on products and not processes",
            "c) Company magazines",
            "d) Company newsletters"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The top management must relay messages to every employee of the organization and make them understand about the company’s TQM program. Company magazines and Company newsletters will add value to the TQM program. Customers will come to know very easily about the company’s objectives and their dedication towards delivering a quality product or service.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 80,
        "Question": "What happens when the top management does not effectively communicate about the company’s TQM program properly from top to bottom?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The TQM program fails to achieve the desired target",
            "b) The TQM program successfully achieves its desired target",
            "c) There is no need to communicate messages",
            "d) Nothing happens to the company’s progress"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: TQM’s goal is to attain customer satisfaction. The focus should be both on internal and external customers. To achieve this, the company focuses on continuous improvement of its internal processes.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 81,
        "Question": " In TQM suppliers are treated as _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Enemies",
            "b) Partners",
            "c) Managers",
            "d) Employees"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: As TQM requires everyone’s involvement, it is a necessity that effective communications take place in the company. The decision taken by the top management must be effectively communicated within the company. The organizational goal then will be easy to attain.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 82,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a performance measure to ensure the highest degree of quality?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Productivity",
            "b) Number of company newsletters published in a year",
            "c) Absenteeism",
            "d) Sales turnover"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: TQM gives recognition to every employee of the company and that each person is responsible for the quality of his work and for the work for the group. The focus of everyone is to improve the processes that end up in delivering quality products or services to the customer.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 83,
        "Question": "Ryan works in a company that follows TQM and produces nuts and bolts. The company has not moved much from its old design of nuts and bolts. Ryan’s creativity leads him to a better and effective design of nuts and bolts at the same production cost as before. It can increase the productivity without compromising quality. Should the company implement Ryan’s design?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes, everyone is recognized in a company which follows TQM",
            "b) No, everyone is not recognized in a company which follows TQM",
            "c) Design implementation is the responsibility of the design team only",
            "d) Modern trends must not dominate and make the company lose its originality"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In TQM, suppliers are treated as partners. Since the quality of supply is crucial in delivering quality products, it is important that suppliers are treated well and assigned the responsibility of delivering quality raw or intermediate materials.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 84,
        "Question": "In tradition management, Inspection philosophy is followed, and in TQM ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) No philosophy is followed",
            "b) Inspection philosophy is followed",
            "c) Prevention philosophy is followed",
            "d) Manager’s philosophy is followed"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The need to measure productivity, absenteeism and sales turnover is important to gauge the performance level of the company. All these performance measures help in continuous improvement. As a result of this, the highest degree of quality product or service can be delivered to the customers.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 85,
        "Question": "A company producing biscuits implemented TQM philosophy. It collected feedback data for the age group 50 to 60 years and determined the number of people using the company’s biscuits and how satisfied they were with the product. Where did the company go wrong in its analysis?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Identified the wrong age group",
            "b) It must take into consideration a larger age group",
            "c) It should not determine the number of people using their product and their level of satisfaction",
            "d) There is no mistake in their TQM approach"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Incorrect measurements in the TQM approach can lead to data misinterpretation. The company must gauge the level of customer satisfaction for a larger age group, maybe 10-60. This will help the company in continuous improvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 86,
        "Question": "A company including its manager has 50 members. TQM philosophy is followed by 40 members only. Did the company properly implement TQM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yes, only 25 members were sufficient for TQM implementation",
            "b) No, TQM implementation requires the participation of all members of the company",
            "c) Yes, only 14 members were sufficient for TQM implementation",
            "d) We cannot comment on TQM implementation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If a company follows the traditional management culture for a long time it will be difficult for the company to change its organizational structure. This, therefore, is a barrier to TQM implementation. Benchmarking can be a tool used to change the mindset of the organization to move towards TQM.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 87,
        "Question": "The 10 years performance of a company was analyzed. The company followed TQM philosophy for the first two years and moved back to traditional management. What can you conclude about the management culture of the company?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lack of management commitment to follow TQM",
            "b) Lack of management commitment to follow traditional management",
            "c) The management of the company is properly functioning",
            "d) We cannot comment on the management culture of the company"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The need for proper training is necessary in order to have proper TQM implementation. The company can then follow TQM philosophy for a long time and can very easily attain customer satisfaction. All employees must follow the same standard procedures to determine the level of customer satisfaction.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 88,
        "Question": "A defect in a product produced by a company was reported to the quality division. The quality division rectified the defect and presented the solution to the rest of the members of the organization including its manager. But the organization delayed the implementation for more than a month. What will be the consequence of this act?",
        "Options": [
            "a) There is no problem in delaying the implementation",
            "b) The company will start to fail in satisfying customer needs and hence customer satisfaction",
            "c) The customer will respect the delay in implementation",
            "d) The manager will be sacked by the founder of the company"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The highest priority of TQM is customer satisfaction. The main focus of the company is to collectively put in efforts to develop quality goods or services and attain customer satisfaction. So, all 50 members must participate in TQM implementation.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 89,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a tangible benefit of following TQM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reduction in employee grievances",
            "b) Increase in employee grievances",
            "c) No change in employee grievances",
            "d) We can’t comment on employee grievances"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The company failed to comply with TQM philosophy after the first two years. As a result of this, it will gradually find it difficult to retain customer satisfaction. In addition to this, if the goods or a service provided by the company no longer follows the changing customer needs then the customer will even stop using the goods or services provided by the company.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 90,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a tangible benefit of following TQM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increased profitability",
            "b) Increased market and customers",
            "c) Improved productivity",
            "d) Increase in quality costs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: TQM by its definition involves achieving the degree of excellence by delivering quality goods or services. All this is done to attain customer satisfaction. If the company discovered the solution to the defect it should implement it without further ado.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 91,
        "Question": "The product quality after using TQM philosophy _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increases",
            "b) Decreases",
            "c) Remains the same",
            "d) We cannot comment on product quality"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In TQM, every employee in the organization is focused towards one goal and that is satisfying customer needs by providing customer satisfaction. As everybody is treated in the same unbiased manner, employee grievances are reduced when an organization follows TQM.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 92,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an intangible benefit of following TQM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Better company image",
            "b) Enhanced problem-solving capacity",
            "c) Enhancement of job interest",
            "d) Reduction in customer satisfaction"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Cost of quality or Quality costs is the cost incurred by a company to prevent poor quality goods or services. By using TQM philosophy, the degree of excellence in goods or services increases and hence quality increases. When we have high-quality goods or service the cost that is required to prevent poor quality goods or services decreases.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 93,
        "Question": "The working relationships after using TQM philosophy _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Declines",
            "b) Remains the same",
            "c) Improves",
            "d) We cannot comment on working relationships"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The product quality improves on using TQM. TQM is focused on customer needs and hence recognizes them. Therefore, there is no additional cost incurred. The concept of continuous improvement in TQM improves product quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 94,
        "Question": "Employee participation after using TQM philosophy _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Declines",
            "b) Remains the same",
            "c) Improves",
            "d) We cannot comment on working relationships"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: TQM is focused on customer satisfaction and hence using TQM customer satisfaction increases. When the customer is happy with the goods or services, the image of the company is good. Due to the involvement of all the employees in a company, problem-solving capacity increases. The job interest also enhances.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 95,
        "Question": "Who among the following is not an American Quality Guru?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Crosby",
            "b) Ishikawa",
            "c) Juran",
            "d) Deming"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Crosby, Juran, and Deming are Quality Gurus from America. Ishikawa is from Japan and is famous for his development of quality initiatives. He is famous for quality circle development and Ishikawa diagram.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 96,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a contribution made by Deming?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Deming’s 14 points",
            "b) System of Profound Knowledge",
            "c) Deming Cycle",
            "d) Taguchi Loss Function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Deming’s 14 points, System of Profound Knowledge, Deming Cycle, and Seven Deadly Diseases of Management was Deming’s contribution. Taguchi Loss Function was developed by the Japanese Quality Guru Taguchi.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 97,
        "Question": "According to Deming’s 14 points, which of the following is the meaning of ‘Adopt the new philosophy’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To adopt the new philosophy that was displayed in the newspaper",
            "b) To hire new philosophy for the company",
            "c) To be aware of new challenges, responsibilities and to adopt them",
            "d) To sell old philosophy and start a new philosophy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The management must be aware of new challenges and actively respond to them. The leadership for change must be taken. As a result of this, new responsibilities will be assigned to everyone.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 98,
        "Question": "According to Deming’s 14 points, which of the following is the meaning of ‘Cease dependence on inspection to achieve quality’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Eliminate the need for inspection on a mass basis",
            "b) Inspection is not good for the product",
            "c) Inspection is independent",
            "d) Inspection cannot bring quality in products"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The need for inspection on a mass basis must be eliminated. We need to develop quality products in the first place. This is the meaning of Deming’s point – Cease dependence on inspection to achieve quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 99,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not belong to Deming’s 14 points on route to quality?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Create constancy of purpose towards improvement of product and services",
            "b) Adopt the new philosophy",
            "c) Cease dependence on inspection to achieve quality",
            "d) Start the practice of awarding business on the basis of price tag"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: According to Deming’s 14 points, we should end the practice of awarding business on the basis of the price tag. Instead, we should minimize the total cost. We should move towards the concept of a single supplier for our item based on loyalty and trust.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 100,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not belong to Deming’s 14 points on route to quality?",
        "Options": [
            "a) End the practice of awarding business on the basis of the price tag",
            "b) Improve constantly and forever the system of product and service",
            "c) End the concept of training",
            "d) Institute leadership"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Institute training on the job is one of Deming’s 14 points on route to quality. Training will enable the employees to know about the proper functioning of the organization. It will also help the employees to try out their creative ideas but well within the rules followed by the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 101,
        "Question": "What is the other name of Deming’s cycle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) PDCA",
            "b) ADCA",
            "c) MDCA",
            "d) SDCA"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: For a company to work effectively there shouldn’t exist any fear within its employees. This will lead to an unhealthy working atmosphere. If fear exists, employees having creative ideas are prevented from proposing their ideas to their seniors. In addition to this, employees don’t work to their full potential.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 102,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not belong to ‘Seven Deadly Diseases of Management’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lack of constancy of purpose",
            "b) Emphasis on short term profits",
            "c) Reliance on performance appraisals and profits",
            "d) Immobility of top management"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Break down of barriers between departments is one of Deming’s 14 points on route to quality. The research, design, production, and sales team must work together cohesively. The idea of working together will help foresee problems and develop techniques to tackle them.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 103,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not belong to ‘Seven Deadly Diseases of Management’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reliance on financial figures",
            "b) Excessive medical costs",
            "c) Excessive legal costs",
            "d) Absence of reliance on financial figures"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The other name of Deming’s cycle is the PDCA cycle or the PDSA cycle. PDCA cycle means Plan, Do, Check, and Act. PDSA cycle means Plan, Do, Study, and Act. Deming’s cycle is a continuous quality improvement model.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 104,
        "Question": "What do you mean by ‘System of Profound Knowledge’ described by Deming?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Management by positive co-operation",
            "b) Management by negative co-operation",
            "c) Management by unstable co-operation",
            "d) Management by pessimistic co-operation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The mobility of top management belongs to the ‘Seven Deadly Diseases of Management’. If the top management itself is unstable and moves to different companies then the progress of the company is prevented. It takes time to build a long term relationship.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 105,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a key element of the ‘System of Profound Knowledge’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hatred for a system",
            "b) Knowledge of statistical theory",
            "c) Theory of knowledge",
            "d) Knowledge of Psychology"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The concept of running a company on visible figures alone is considered to be one of the ‘Seven Deadly Diseases of Management’. Although there is a payroll to meet, suppliers to pay, taxes to pay, and so on, the determination of happy customers takes time and the results are apparent after some time.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 106,
        "Question": "According to Deming’s 14 points, the barrier to the pride of workmanship should be ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Removed",
            "b) Promoted",
            "c) Established",
            "d) Encouraged"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The system of profound knowledge is described by Deming. It means management by positive co-operation. There are four key elements of the system of profound knowledge. They are Appreciation for a system, Knowledge of statistical theory, Theory of knowledge, and Knowledge of Psychology.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 107,
        "Question": "According to Deming’s 14 points, the vigorous program of education and self – improvement must be ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Instituted",
            "b) Removed",
            "c) Discouraged",
            "d) Demoted"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The appreciation for a system is one of the key elements of the ‘System of Profound Knowledge’. There is a need for managers to understand the relationships between functions and activities. The long term aim for everyone is to win – employees, shareholders, customers, suppliers and the environment.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 108,
        "Question": "Which among the following is not a contribution made by Juran?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Juran’s Quality Control Handbook",
            "b) Quality Planning and Analysis",
            "c) Juran on Leadership for Quality",
            "d) Quality is Free"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Juran has authored many papers and twelve books including ‘Juran’s Quality Control Handbook’, ‘Quality Planning and Analysis’, ‘Juran on Leadership for Quality’. ‘Quality is Free’ is authored by Philip Crosby.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 109,
        "Question": "Which among the following is not part of Juran’s ‘Three Role Model’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Supplier",
            "b) Process",
            "c) Customer",
            "d) Deming"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: According to Juran, the focus should be given to internal customers also. Each person along the chain is a supplier and a customer. In addition to this, the person will be a process, carrying out some transformation or activity.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 110,
        "Question": "Which among the following is not a contribution made by Juran?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Internal Customer",
            "b) Cost of Quality",
            "c) Quality Trilogy",
            "d) Quality Loss Function"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Juran’s contributions can be studied under five topics. They are internal customer, cost of quality, quality trilogy, Juran’s 10 steps for quality improvement, and the breakthrough concept. Quality Loss Function is a contribution made by Taguchi.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 111,
        "Question": "Which among the following does not belong to the classification of Cost of Quality done by Juran?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Failure Costs",
            "b) Appraisal Costs",
            "c) Prevention Costs",
            "d) Variable Costs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: According to Juran, the cost of quality can be classified into three classes. They are failure costs, appraisal costs, and prevention costs. Variable costs are associated with the concept of Break-Even Analysis.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 112,
        "Question": "Which among the following does not belong to Juran’s Quality Trilogy?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality Planning",
            "b) Quality Control",
            "c) Quality Improvement",
            "d) Quality Assurance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Quality Planning, Quality Control, and Quality Improvement are part of Juran’s Quality Trilogy. Quality Assurance is the act of maintaining a desired level of quality in a product or service by providing attention to every stage of process of delivery or production.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 113,
        "Question": "Which among the following does not belong to Juran’s ten steps to quality improvement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Build awareness of the need and opportunity for improvement",
            "b) Set goals for improvement",
            "c) Organize to reach goals",
            "d) Adopt the new philosophy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Juran has suggested ten steps for quality improvement. ‘Build awareness of the need and opportunity for improvement’, ‘Set goals for improvement’, and ‘Organize to reach goals’ are part of Juran’s ten steps to quality improvement. ‘Adopt the new philosophy’ belongs to Deming’s fourteen points on route to quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 114,
        "Question": "Identify from Juran’s ten steps to quality improvement a statement which implies providing a morale boost.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Organize to reach goals",
            "b) Adopt the new philosophy",
            "c) Give recognition",
            "d) Provide Training"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘Carry out projects to solve problems’ is a statement belonging to Juran’s ten steps to quality improvement. Large, break-through improvements through interdepartmental or even cross-functional teams can be achieved. We need to deal with chronic problems for break-through improvements.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 115,
        "Question": "‘Communicate results’ is a statement from Juran’s ten steps to quality improvement. Which of the following is the odd one out with respect to it?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lessons learned",
            "b) Provide training",
            "c) The steps that have been taken to improve quality",
            "d) The feedback that has been given to the manager of the company"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘Report progress’ is a statement belonging to Juran’s ten steps to quality improvement. The progress achieved should be compared with the progress expected. Information on progress is important for quality improvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 116,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not mean to ‘Keep score’ from Juran’s ten steps to quality improvement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Track progress",
            "b) Report achievements",
            "c) Report short-falls",
            "d) Set goals for improvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ‘Give recognition’ is one of the statements of Juran’s ten steps to quality improvement. It means providing a morale boost. This will ensure that the confidence level in the employees’ increases and they are rejuvenated.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 117,
        "Question": "Which among the following is not a contribution made by Crosby?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality is Free",
            "b) Quality without Tears",
            "c) Let’s Talk Quality and Leading: The Art of Becoming an Executive",
            "d) Quality Planning and Analysis"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘Quality is Free’, ‘Quality without Tears’, ‘Let’s Talk Quality and Leading: The Art of Becoming an Executive’ are contributions made by Crosby. ‘Quality Planning and Analysis is authored by Juran.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 118,
        "Question": "Which among the following is not a contribution made by Crosby?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Four Absolutes of Quality",
            "b) Fourteen Steps for Quality Improvement",
            "c) Quality Vaccine",
            "d) Quality Trilogy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘Four Absolutes of Quality Management’, ‘Fourteen Steps for Quality Improvement’, ‘Crosby’s Quality Vaccine’ are contributions made by Crosby. ‘Quality Trilogy’ is a contribution made by Juran.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 119,
        "Question": "According to Crosby’s First Absolute of Quality, quality is _______ to requirements, not goodness.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Conformance",
            "b) Negligence",
            "c) Carelessness",
            "d) Betrayal"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to Crosby’s First Absolute of Quality, quality is conformance to requirements, not goodness. There are four absolutes of quality proposed by Crosby. Crosby was the founder and chairman of the board of Career IV, an executive management consulting firm.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 120,
        "Question": "According to Crosby’s Second Absolute of Quality, quality is achieved by _______not appraisal.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Prevention",
            "b) Inspection",
            "c) Suspension",
            "d) Retention"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to Crosby’s Second Absolute of Quality, quality is achieved by prevention, not appraisal. There are four absolutes of quality proposed by Crosby. He believed in the concept of zero defects.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 121,
        "Question": "According to Crosby’s Third Absolute of Quality, quality has a performance standard of ________not acceptable quality levels.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Zero defects",
            "b) Five defects",
            "c) Nine defects",
            "d) Two defects"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to Crosby’s Third Absolute of Quality, quality has a performance standard of zero defects, not acceptable quality levels. There are four absolutes of quality proposed by Crosby. Crosby founded the Philip Crosby Associates Inc. and Quality College.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 122,
        "Question": "According to Crosby’s Fourth Absolute of Quality, the measurement of quality is the price of ______not indexes.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Conformance",
            "b) Non-conformance",
            "c) Adherence",
            "d) Performance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: According to Crosby’s Fourth Absolute of Quality, the measurement of quality is the price of non-conformance, not indexes. There are four absolutes of quality proposed by Crosby. Crosby served in the US Navy in the Second World War.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 123,
        "Question": "Which among the following does not belong to the five sections of Crosby’s Quality Vaccine?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Communication",
            "b) Operations",
            "c) Policies",
            "d) Conformance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are five sections in Crosby’s Quality Vaccine. They are integrity, systems, communications, operations, and policies. Integrity is crucial to attain customer satisfaction. Companies must consider quality seriously as the measurement of quality is the price of non-conformance.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 124,
        "Question": "According to Crosby’s Fourteen Steps for Quality Improvement, what do you mean by QITs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality Injustice Teams",
            "b) Quality Inspection Teams",
            "c) Quality Injection Teams",
            "d) Quality Improvement Teams"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to Crosby, there are five sections in Quality Vaccine. They are integrity, systems, communications, operations, and policies. The need of proper ‘Systems’ is crucial to sustain quality in the whole business.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 125,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not belong to Crosby’s Fourteen Steps for Quality Improvement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Establish quality measurements",
            "b) Establish a zero defect committee and program",
            "c) Hold a zero defects day",
            "d) Create constancy of purpose towards improvement of product and service."
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Communications, Operations, and Policies are part of Crosby’s Quality Vaccine. The other two sections are Integrity and Systems. According to Crosby, ‘vaccine’ is explained as medicine for management to prevent poor quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 126,
        "Question": "According to Crosby’s Fourteen Steps for Quality Improvement, what do you mean by obstacle reporting?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To communicate to management about obstacles employees’ face in attaining quality improvement",
            "b) To report about the no of steps employees’ climb on their way to office",
            "c) To write an article on the topic ‘Obstacle’",
            "d) To write an essay on the topic ‘Obstacle’"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: According to Crosby’s Fourteen Steps for Quality Improvement, QITs refer to Quality Improvement Teams. They are needed for quality improvement process planning and administration. There is a need to establish and ensure management commitment also.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 127,
        "Question": "Which among the following is not an element of quality statements?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vision Statement",
            "b) Mission Statement",
            "c) Quality Policy Statement",
            "d) Submission Statement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Vision Statement, Mission Statement, and Quality Policy Statement are elements of Quality Statements. It is important for an effective leader to communicate the vision and mission of the organization to its employees.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 128,
        "Question": "The aspiration of the company in a short declaration is called the ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vision Statement",
            "b) Mission Statement",
            "c) Quality Policy Statement",
            "d) Submission Statement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The aspiration of the company in a short declaration is called the vision statement. It tells about the goals of the company targeted by the company in the near future. It may be ideal in nature but the company tries to achieve it.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 129,
        "Question": "The declaration which lists the functions of an organization and mentions about the purpose of its employees, customers, and suppliers is called the _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer Statement",
            "b) Mission Statement",
            "c) Supplier Statement",
            "d) Employee Statement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The declaration which lists the functions of an organization and mentions the purpose of its employees, customers, and suppliers is called the Mission Statement. It tells about the way the company is planning its workforce involvement, supplier relationship, and to attain customer satisfaction.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 130,
        "Question": "The guide for the organization as to how the organization would provide products and services to its customers is called the _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality Policy Statement",
            "b) Product and Service Statement",
            "c) Product Statement",
            "d) Service Statement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The guide for the organization as to how the organization would provide products and services to its customers is called the Quality Policy Statement. It tells about the quality goals set up by the organization and its delivery pathway.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 131,
        "Question": "The quality policy is approved by the __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality Improvement Team",
            "b) Quality Council",
            "c) Quality Control Team",
            "d) Quality Assurance Team"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The quality policy should be written by the CEO and feedback from its employees is needed. It is used as a guide by the managers to plan their actions. The quality policy is a guide for everyone in the organization describing the pathway in which the organization will deliver its products and services.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 132,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a key element of a Mission Statement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Obligation to Stakeholders",
            "b) Scope of the Business",
            "c) View of the Future",
            "d) Quality Policy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The quality policy is approved by the Quality Council. It is an important requirement of the ISO 9000 quality systems, the international standard for quality assurance. The quality policy is a guide for everyone in the organization describing the pathway in which the organization will deliver its products and services.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 133,
        "Question": "Vision Statement talks about the _______ future of the company and Mission Statement talks about the organization’s ______ leading to the future.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Long term, Present",
            "b) Short term, Future",
            "c) Long term, Future",
            "d) Short term, Present"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Obligation to Stakeholders, Scope of the Business, Sources of competitive advantage, and View of the Future are the key elements of a Mission Statement. Quality Policy of the organization is declared in the Quality Policy Statement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 134,
        "Question": "The ______ and _______ can be together used in daily decision making.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vision Statement, Decision Statement",
            "b) Mission Statement, Decision Statement",
            "c) Vision Statement, Mission Statement",
            "d) Decision Statement, Progress Statement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Vision Statement must remain intact even if the market changes. It represents the core values the organization would like to have in the future. It describes what the organization represents and not just what it does.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 135,
        "Question": "An organization gave a declaration on its opening on 16th June 2019 that it wants ‘To eradicate poverty by 2025’. Which quality statement is it referring to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vision Statement",
            "b) Mission Statement",
            "c) Quality Policy Statement",
            "d) Submission Statement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Vision Statement talks about the long term future of the company even though expecting marketing changes. It represents the organization. The Mission Statement talks about the present leading to the future and represents the functions of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 136,
        "Question": "The cost associated with NOT producing quality products or services is called ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cost of Quality",
            "b) Cost of Poor Quality Product",
            "c) Cost of Mistake",
            "d) Cost of Poor Quality Service"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The cost associated with NOT producing quality products or services is called the Cost of Quality. It is commonly mistaken as the cost associated with producing quality products or services.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 137,
        "Question": "Costs associated with improving quality or cost of conformance is called _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cost of Good Quality",
            "b) Cost of Poor Quality",
            "c) Cost of Improvement",
            "d) Cost of Planning"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Costs associated with improving the quality or cost of conformance is called the cost of good quality. It is a component of the cost of quality. The cost of quality can be used as a standard measure to study an organization’s performance.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 138,
        "Question": "Costs associated with non-conformance or the costs due to poor quality is called ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cost of Good Quality",
            "b) Cost of Poor Quality",
            "c) Cost of Improvement",
            "d) Cost of Planning"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Costs associated with non-conformance or the costs due to poor quality is called the cost of poor quality. It is a component of the cost of quality. The cost of quality is used to understand, analyze, and improve quality performance.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 139,
        "Question": "Costs associated with the prevention of non-conformance to requirements is called _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Prevention Costs",
            "b) Appraisal Costs",
            "c) Internal Failure Costs",
            "d) External Failure Costs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Costs associated with the prevention of non-conformance to requirements is called Prevention Costs. It is a type of Cost of Good Quality. Cost of Good Quality is a component of the Cost of Quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 140,
        "Question": "Costs associated with appraising a product or service for conformance to requirements is called ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Prevention Costs",
            "b) Appraisal Costs",
            "c) Internal Failure Costs",
            "d) External Failure Costs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Costs associated with appraising a product or service for conformance to requirements is called Appraisal Costs. It is a type of Cost of Good Quality. Cost of Good Quality is a component of the Cost of Quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 141,
        "Question": "Mathematically, the cost of quality equals to _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Prevention Costs + Appraisal Costs + Internal Failure Costs + External Failure Costs",
            "b) Prevention Costs + Appraisal Costs + Internal Failure Costs – External Failure Costs",
            "c) Prevention Costs + Appraisal Costs + Internal Failure Costs * External Failure Costs",
            "d) Prevention Costs – Appraisal Costs + Internal Failure Costs + External Failure Costs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Mathematically, the cost of quality equals to Prevention Costs + Appraisal Costs + Internal Failure Costs + External Failure Costs. Prevention Costs and Appraisal Costs belong to the Cost of Good Quality. Internal Failure Costs and External Failure Costs belong to the Cost of Poor Quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 142,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not belong to Prevention Costs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Marketing research",
            "b) Customer/User perception surveys",
            "c) Design quality progress reviews",
            "d) Lost sales"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Marketing research, Customer/User perception surveys, and Design quality progress reviews fall under the category of Prevention Costs. Lost sales fall under the category of External Failure Costs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 143,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not belong to Prevention Costs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Design support activities",
            "b) Product design qualification test",
            "c) Service design qualification",
            "d) Downgraded end-product or service"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Design support activities, Product design qualification test, and Service design qualification fall under the category of Prevention Costs. Downgraded end-product or service fall under the category of Internal Failure Costs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 144,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not belong to Internal Failure Costs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Rework due to Design Changes",
            "b) Scrap due to Design Changes",
            "c) Design Corrective Action",
            "d) Returned Goods"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Rework, Scrap and Design Corrective Action fall under the category of Internal Failure Costs. Returned Goods fall under the category of External Failure Costs. Internal and External Failure Costs fall under the category of Cost of Poor Quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 145,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not belong to Internal Failure Costs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Uncontrolled Material Losses",
            "b) Purchased Material Replacement Costs",
            "c) Re-inspection / Retest Costs",
            "d) Supplier Reviews"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Uncontrolled material losses, Purchased material replacement costs, Re-inspection / Retest Costs fall under the category of Internal Failure Costs. Supplier reviews fall under the category of Prevention Costs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 146,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not belong to External Failure Costs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Complaint investigations",
            "b) Warranty claims",
            "c) Liability costs",
            "d) Supplier quality planning"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Complaint investigations, Warranty claims, and Liability costs fall under the category of External Failure Costs. Supplier Quality Planning falls under the category of Prevention Costs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 147,
        "Question": "Quality improvement, Quality education, and Quality performance reporting fall under the category of _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Appraisal Costs",
            "b) Prevention Costs",
            "c) Internal Failure Costs",
            "d) External Failure Costs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation:  Quality improvement, Quality education, and Quality performance reporting fall under the category of Prevention Costs. Prevention costs fall under the category of Cost of Good Quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 148,
        "Question": "Retrofit costs fall under the category of _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Appraisal Costs",
            "b) Prevention Costs",
            "c) Internal Failure Costs",
            "d) External Failure Costs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Retrofit costs fall under the category of External Failure Costs. Retrofit means to add a component or accessory to something that did not have it when it was manufactured. External Failure Costs fall under the category of Cost of Poor Quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 149,
        "Question": "Receiving or incoming inspections and tests fall under the category of ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Purchasing Appraisal Costs",
            "b) Operations Appraisal Costs",
            "c) External Appraisal Costs",
            "d) External Failure Costs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Receiving or incoming inspections and tests fall under the category of Purchasing Appraisal Costs. Appraisal Costs fall under the category of Cost of Good Quality. Cost of Good Quality and Cost of Poor Quality are the two categories of Cost of Quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 150,
        "Question": "Evaluation of field stock and spare parts fall under the category of ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Purchasing Appraisal Costs",
            "b) Operations Appraisal Costs",
            "c) External Appraisal Costs",
            "d) External Failure Costs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Evaluation of field stock and spare parts fall under the category of External Appraisal Costs. Special product evaluations and Field performance evaluations also fall under the category of External Appraisal Costs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 151,
        "Question": "Quality cost per hour direct labor is called ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Labor base index",
            "b) Cost base index",
            "c) Sales base index",
            "d) Unit base index"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The quality cost per hour direct labor is called the Labor base index. Bases used to compare with quality costs are labor base, production base, sales base, and unit base. Quality cost bases are used for measuring quality costs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 152,
        "Question": "Quality cost per rupee of production cost is called _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Labor base index",
            "b) Cost base index",
            "c) Sales base index",
            "d) Production base index"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The quality cost per rupee of production cost is called the Cost base index. Bases used to compare with quality costs are labor base, production base, sales base, and unit base. Quality cost bases are used for measuring quality costs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 153,
        "Question": "Quality cost per rupee of net sales is called _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Labor base index",
            "b) Rupee base index",
            "c) Sales base index",
            "d) Unit base index"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The quality cost per rupee of net sales is called the Sales base index. Bases used to compare with quality costs are labor base, production base, sales base, and unit base. Quality cost bases are used for measuring quality costs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 154,
        "Question": "Quality cost per unit of production is called _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Labor base index",
            "b) Rupee base index",
            "c) Sales base index",
            "d) Unit base index"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The quality cost per unit of production is called the Unit base index. Bases used to compare with quality costs are labor base, production base, sales base, and unit base. Quality cost bases are used for measuring quality costs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 155,
        "Question": "What is the other name of intangible costs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Hidden Costs",
            "b) Prevention Costs",
            "c) Appraisal Costs",
            "d) Internal Failure Costs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Timesheets, schedules and minutes of meetings are important sources for collecting/reporting quality costs in an organization. They form a part of the quality cost collection.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 156,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not fall under the category of Hidden Costs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Potential loss sales",
            "b) Loss of customer goodwill",
            "c) Offsetting customer dissatisfaction",
            "d) Marketing research"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation:  Expense reports, credit and debit memos and cost estimates are important sources for collecting/reporting quality costs in an organization. They form a part of the quality cost collection.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 157,
        "Question": "Which of the following describes best Juran’s model of optimum quality costs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It includes costs of internal and external failures curve, costs of appraisal and prevention curve and total quality costs curve",
            "b) It includes costs of internal and external failures curve and costs of appraisal and prevention curve",
            "c) It includes costs of internal and external failures curve and total quality costs curve",
            "d) It includes costs of appraisal and prevention curve and total quality costs curve"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The other name of intangible costs is Hidden Costs. They are the cost associated with providing a non-conforming product or service to a customer that is difficult to identify and quantify.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 158,
        "Question": "The commonly used techniques for measuring quality costs are __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Trend analysis and Pareto analysis",
            "b) Trend analysis only",
            "c) Pareto analysis only",
            "d) Trigonometry"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Potential loss sales, Loss of customer goodwill and  Offsetting customer dissatisfaction fall under the category of Hidden Costs. Some of the other hidden costs are customer dissatisfaction cost and loss of company image.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 159,
        "Question": "Who among the following is not a hidden customer?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Regulators",
            "b) Critics",
            "c) Opinion leaders",
            "d) Managers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The Square in red represents the product or service offered by the company. The Circle in yellow represents the customer needs. The Intersection in green represents customer satisfaction. The company should look forward to increasing the intersection portion.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 160,
        "Question": "Those who are not currently using the product but have the capability of becoming customers in future are called __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Potential Customers",
            "b) Hidden Customers",
            "c) Suppliers",
            "d) Processors"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Regulators, Critics, and Opinion Leaders are hidden customers. The media, corporate policy makers, labor unions and professional associations are other hidden customers. Hidden customers are a type of External Customers.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 161,
        "Question": "Organizations / People who use the product or output as an input for producing their own product are called _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Potential Customers",
            "b) Hidden Customers",
            "c) Suppliers",
            "d) Processors"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Those who are not currently using the product but have the capability of becoming customers are called Potential Customers. It is important to gauge potential customers so as to have a proper estimate of the number of customers that will use a company’s product or service in the near future.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 162,
        "Question": "Who among the following do not fall under the category of External Customers?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Purchasers",
            "b) Merchants",
            "c) Hidden Customers",
            "d) Quality Management Unit of a Company"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Organizations / People who use the product or output as an input for producing their own product are called Processors. For example, a refinery that receives crude oil and processes it further into different products.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 163,
        "Question": "According to ASQ survey, which of the following is not part of customer perceptions?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Performance",
            "b) Features",
            "c) Service",
            "d) Discredit"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Purchasers, Merchants and Hidden Customers fall under the category of External Customers. Quality Management Unit of a Company can be considered to be an Internal Customer.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 164,
        "Question": "Which among the following is not a factor influencing customer perception of quality before making a purchase?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Company’s brand name and image",
            "b) Opinions of friends",
            "c) Spare parts availability",
            "d) Published Test Results"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Performance, Features and Service are part of customer perceptions. Discredit is opposite to Reputation. The other customer perceptions are Warranty, Price and Reputation.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 165,
        "Question": "Which among the following does not fall under the category of factors influencing customer perception of quality before making a purchase?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Previous experience",
            "b) Advertised price for performance",
            "c) Store reputation",
            "d) Reliability"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the modern world, warranty attached to a product attracts and build markets. It imposes faith in a customer that if at all any problem is faced by them then they can claim for repair or exchange.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 166,
        "Question": "Which among the following does not fall under the category of factors influencing customer perception of quality at the point of making a purchase?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Performance specifications",
            "b) Comments of sales people",
            "c) Warranty provisions",
            "d) Service effectiveness"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Reputation of a firm brings the market to them and fetches them more customers. Customers prefer to choose companies offering similar products based on their reputation. So, organizations must look to ensure that they retain customer satisfaction for a longer period of time.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 167,
        "Question": "Which among the following is not a factor influencing customer perception of quality at the point of making a purchase?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Service and Repair Policies",
            "b) Support Programs",
            "c) Quoted Price for Performance",
            "d) Comparative Performance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Company’s brand name and image, Opinions of friends and Published Test results are important factors influencing customer perception of quality before making a purchase. Spare parts availability is an important factor influencing customer perception of quality after purchase.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 168,
        "Question": "Which among the following is not a factor influencing customer perception of quality after making a purchase?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ease of use",
            "b) Ease of installation",
            "c) Previous experience",
            "d) Handling of repairs claims and warranty"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Previous experience, Advertised price for performance and Store reputation are important factors influencing customer perception of quality before making a purchase. Reliability is an important factor influencing customer perception of quality after purchase.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 169,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the best way to gather information about customer needs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Information on competitor’s products",
            "b) Personal visits to customer locations",
            "c) Employees with special knowledge of the customer",
            "d) Threatening customers to tell their needs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Performance specifications, Comments of sales people and Warranty provisions are important factors influencing customer perception of quality at the point of making a purchase. Service effectiveness is an important factor influencing customer perception of quality after purchase.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 170,
        "Question": "Which of the following cannot be considered as a technique to gather information about customer needs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer meetings",
            "b) Tracking customer complaints",
            "c) Government or Independent Laboratory Data",
            "d) Waiting for customer to come and tell about their needs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Service and Repair Policies, Support Programs and Quoted Price for Performance are important factors influencing customer perception of quality at the point of making a purchase. Comparative Performance is an important factor influencing customer perception of quality after purchase.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 171,
        "Question": "Which of the following is false regarding the Kano Model of Customer Satisfaction?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Identifying customer needs",
            "b) Determining functional requirements",
            "c) Concept development",
            "d) Inability in analyzing competitive product"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The Kano Model of Customer Satisfaction is useful for Identifying customer needs, Determining functional requirements, Concept development and Analyzing competitive products. The Kano model categorizes customer needs into basic needs, performance needs and excitement needs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 172,
        "Question": "The customer needs that keep a company in the market are called ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Performance Needs",
            "b) Basic Needs",
            "c) Excitement Needs",
            "d) Excess Needs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Complaints, industry standards, and what your competitors are doing are techniques to gather information about Basic Needs. They are the needs that get a company in the market.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 173,
        "Question": "The customer needs that bring with them pleasant surprises and customer delight are called ________________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Performance Needs",
            "b) Basic Needs",
            "c) Excitement Needs",
            "d) Excess Needs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Performance needs are the customer needs that keep a company in the market. For example, customers would be willing to pay more for a building in an earthquake-prone area that offers greater preparedness in case an earthquake occurs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 174,
        "Question": "The expression of dissatisfaction with a product/service, either orally or in writing, from an internal customer or external customer is called _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) customer needs",
            "b) customer delight",
            "c) customer expectations",
            "d) customer complaints"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Market research, focus groups, Surveys, Clinics, Interviews, and Contextual Enquiry are techniques to gather information about Performance Needs. Customer’s happiness is related to how well the performance needs are met.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 175,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a tool used to collect customer complaints?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ask the manager of the company to list down potential reasons for customer complaints",
            "b) Social media",
            "c) Toll – free telephone numbers",
            "d) Customer visits"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The customer needs that bring with them pleasant surprises and customer delight are called Excitement Needs. Excitement needs if not fulfilled has no effect on customer satisfaction.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 176,
        "Question": "_________ is the set of activities performed by an organization used to satisfy the customer and their needs.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer satisfaction",
            "b) Customer service",
            "c) Customer needs",
            "d) Customer delight"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The expression of dissatisfaction with a product/service, either orally or in writing, from an internal customer or external customer, is called customer complaints. Customer complaints may be due to a genuine cause, misunderstanding or unreasonable expectations.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 177,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an element of customer service?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Organization",
            "b) Customer care",
            "c) Communication",
            "d) Co-founder"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Social media, Toll – free telephone numbers, Customer visits, Customer questionnaire, Post – transaction surveys and Focus groups are some of the tools used to collect information about customer complaints. Customer complaints may be related to the product or after-sales service.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 178,
        "Question": "________ defines activities which occur within an organization that ensures a customer is not only satisfied but also retained.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer care",
            "b) Customer satisfaction",
            "c) Customer needs",
            "d) Customer delight"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Customer service is the set of activities performed by an organization used to satisfy the customer and their needs. The service can be provided before the sale of the product, during the sale of the product and after the sale of the product.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 179,
        "Question": "The process of involving yourself and influencing others towards the accomplishment of goals is called _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Leadership",
            "b) Dictatorship",
            "c) Sportsmanship",
            "d) Autocracy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The process of influencing others towards the accomplishment of goals is called leadership. Leaders instill the will to do, show direction and help the group members in achieving company’s goal.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 180,
        "Question": "Leaders use _______ to create a sustainable competitive advantage for their organization.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ineffective strategy",
            "b) Effective strategy",
            "c) Papers",
            "d) Media"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Leaders use effective strategy to create a sustainable competitive advantage for their organization. Strategy means the decisions that determine and reveal a company’s goals, policies, and plans to meet the need of its stakeholders.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 181,
        "Question": "Quality leaders give primary importance to ___________ and their needs.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Internal and external customers",
            "b) Founder and co-founder",
            "c) Founder and internal customer",
            "d) Founder and external customer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Quality leaders give primary importance to internal and external customers and their needs. Leaders listen to customers, seek their opinion on the value of products or services, develop a close relationship with customers, implement joint improvement activity and lead the handling of complaints.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 182,
        "Question": "Which of the following is false regarding the supplier and quality leader relationship?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Support them when needed, Audit their capabilities",
            "b) Recognize quality improvements made by suppliers",
            "c) Encourage joint improvement action",
            "d) Scold them if there is lack of quality"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Quality leaders care about the development of people’s skills and capabilities. People are responsible for their work. Quality leaders monitor, appraise and recognize people’s performance.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 183,
        "Question": "Quality leaders focus on _____________ rather than maintenance.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Continuous improvement",
            "b) Discontinuous improvement",
            "c) Static improvement",
            "d) Aesthetics"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Quality leaders create awareness about the desired quality to suppliers. They audit their capabilities. They support the suppliers and recognize joint improvement action to instill quality improvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 184,
        "Question": "Quality Leaders _________ people rather than directing and supervising them.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Train and coach",
            "b) Scold",
            "c) Threaten",
            "d) Fire"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Quality leaders focus on continuous improvement rather than maintenance. Continuous improvement helps a company to adapt to changing customer needs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 185,
        "Question": "Which of the following is false regarding quality leaders promoting teamwork?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Multidisciplinary teamwork",
            "b) Create involvement",
            "c) Active participation of everyone",
            "d) Discourage involvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Quality leaders train and coach people rather than directing and supervising them. Directing and supervising is related to old tradition of management. Training and coaching is related to total quality management.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 186,
        "Question": "Quality leaders encourage _______ over ________ when we consider functions of various departments in a company.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Collaboration, competition",
            "b) Competition, collaboration",
            "c) Competition, threat",
            "d) Threat, collaboration"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Quality leaders promote teamwork by introducing multidisciplinary teamwork, creating involvement and active participation of everyone. Teamwork is essential in achieving company’s goal.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 187,
        "Question": "Which of the following is false regarding the kind of environment quality leaders try to build in a company?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Empowerment",
            "b) Innovation",
            "c) Agility",
            "d) Localized learning"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Quality leaders support benchmarking. They learn from their competitors and try to instill similar kind of ideas in their organization by learning how their competitors are more successful.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 188,
        "Question": "Which of the false regarding quality leaders reviewing organizational performance?",
        "Options": [
            "a) They review organizational performance but not their own performance",
            "b) They review organizational performance and also their own performance",
            "c) They don’t review organizational performance as they hate it",
            "d) They don’t review organizational performance as they don’t have time for it"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Quality leaders encourage collaboration over competition when we consider functions of various departments in a company. Collaboration results in improved communication and helps in resolving problems collectively. Competition results in unnecessary hatred sometimes.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 189,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an autocratic style of leadership?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Directing style of leadership",
            "b) Consultative style of leadership",
            "c) Participative style of leadership",
            "d) Delegating style of leadership"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Directing style of leadership is an autocratic style of leadership. For example, when the leader is more versed and has a wide range of the knowledge about the subject, he/she decides to have the final say and does not feel the need to consult his/her team.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 190,
        "Question": "In which of the following leadership styles the workforce have little input or feedback?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Directing style of leadership",
            "b) Consultative style of leadership",
            "c) Participative style of leadership",
            "d) Delegating style of leadership"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In directing style of leadership, the workforce have little input or feedback. It is having an autocratic style. This is due to the fact that the leader may be well versed in taking the final decision for the matter under concern.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 191,
        "Question": "The type of leadership style in which the leader seeks input from those working under him/her is called _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Indirect style of leadership",
            "b) Consultative style of leadership",
            "c) Direct style of leadership",
            "d) Delegating style of leadership"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The type of leadership style in which the leader seeks input from those working under him/her is called Consultative style of leadership. This kind of leadership encourages participation from the workforce of the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 192,
        "Question": "In consultative style of leadership, the _______ is the final decision maker.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Leader",
            "b) Workforce",
            "c) Founder",
            "d) Co-founder"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In consultative style of leadership, the leader is the final decision maker. The leader may take advice, suggestions and inputs from the workforce but the final decision is made by the leader.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 193,
        "Question": "Which of the following is false regarding Participative Style of Leadership?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Leader assigns work to the workforce",
            "b) Leader provides guidance during the work process",
            "c) Leader makes decision based on the conclusions made by the workforce",
            "d) Leader doesn’t assign any task to its workforce"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In Participative Style of Leadership, Leader provides guidance during the work process provides guidance during the work process and makes decision based on the conclusions made by the workforce. The leader is more likely to take the final decision of the matter based on the results produced by the workforce when compared to Consultative style of leadership.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 194,
        "Question": "In which of the following kind of leadership style the individual or team is given responsibility and authority to complete the task with minimum input from the leader?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Directing style of leadership",
            "b) Consultative style of leadership",
            "c) Participative style of leadership",
            "d) Delegating style of leadership"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In Delegating style of leadership, the individual or team is given responsibility and authority to complete the task with minimum input from the leader. The leader checks to verify successful completion of the assignment and participates only if he/she feels it is necessary.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 195,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a kind of leadership skill required for effective leadership?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vision",
            "b) Empowerment",
            "c) Intuition",
            "d) Threat"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Vision, Empowerment, Intuition, Self-understanding and Value congruence are the five core leadership skills required for effective leadership. A leader without skills can never impart effective quality into the system. A leader with skills can impart quality and also focus on continuous improvement. A leader should never threaten his/her workforce.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 196,
        "Question": "_______ occurs when leaders integrate their values into the company’s system.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Intuition",
            "b) Self – understanding",
            "c) Value congruence",
            "d) Vision"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Value congruence occurs when leaders integrate their values into the company’s system. Values are assumptions and beliefs related to the nature of the business, mission, people and relationships of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 197,
        "Question": "Which values does an effective leader focus on?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Trust and respect of individuals",
            "b) Openness",
            "c) Teamwork",
            "d) Disintegration"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: An effective leader focuses on the values of trust and respect of individuals, openness, teamwork, integrity and commitment to quality. He/she focuses on value congruence. He/she should realize that effective leadership needs to incorporate value congruence.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 198,
        "Question": "When did the Quality Council of India form?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1993",
            "b) 1997",
            "c) 1998",
            "d) 1999"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The Quality Council of India was formed in 1997 as an autonomous body. It was formed jointly by the Government of India and the Indian industry represented by ASSOCHAM, CII, and FICCI. The chairman of the QCI is appointed by the Prime Minister after a recommendation from the industry is sent to the government.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 199,
        "Question": "A _______ is a team that provides overall direction for achieving total quality culture.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality Council",
            "b) Quality Management",
            "c) Quality Chancellor",
            "d) Quality Commissioner"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A Quality Council is a team that provides overall direction for achieving total quality culture. For example, we have the Quality Council of India formed in 1997. Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam assigned a mission for QCI “The National Well Being”.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 200,
        "Question": "Who among the following is not part of a Quality Council team of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CEO",
            "b) Senior managers of functional areas",
            "c) Quality Council coordinator or consultant",
            "d) External customer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The objective of the Quality Council team is to establish quality into the work culture of the organization. An organization having a well-organized quality council team is bound to be successful.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 201,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a method that can be implemented by the Quality Council team to promote quality consciousness in the organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Seminars",
            "b) Study Tours",
            "c) Training",
            "d) Threatening the workforce to follow the quality policy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: CEO, senior managers of functional areas like design, marketing, production, quality, and quality council coordinators or consultants are part of the Quality Council team of an organization. An external customer receives the quality bound goods or services from the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 202,
        "Question": "In a production company, the testing and calibration facilities have not been upgraded. What is the duty of the Quality Council team?",
        "Options": [
            "a) There is no need to worry to upgrade the existing facilities",
            "b) Immediately plan to upgrade the existing facilities",
            "c) Planning to upgrade the existing facilities is a crime",
            "d) Wait for the existing facilities to fail"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The Quality Council team can promote quality consciousness in the organization by conducting seminars, organizing study tours and providing training. Threatening the workforce brings in fear within the workforce and due to this the working environment becomes submissive.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 203,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the responsibility of the Quality Council Coordinator?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To develop two-way trust",
            "b) To empower the team",
            "c) To share council expectations with the team",
            "d) To develop one-way trust"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The Quality Council team must immediately plan to upgrade the existing testing and calibration facilities. This will help the company deliver quality products to customers which is their prime duty.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 204,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the duty of the Quality Council?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To establish the core values and quality statements",
            "b) To end the planning of training and education programs",
            "c) To determine and monitor the cost of poor quality",
            "d) To establish the strategic long – term plan with goals"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: To encourage basic and applied R&D in the field of quality and sharing the results with the organization is one of the duties of the Quality Council team. This concept will foster continuous quality improvement within the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 205,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the duty of the Quality Council?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To perform and monitor the performance measure of each functional area",
            "b) To determine continually those projects that improve the processes affecting customer satisfaction",
            "c) To establish the multi-functional project and departmental teams and monitor their progress",
            "d) To prevent establishing/revising the recognition and reward system periodically"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The communication between the Quality Council Coordinator and his/her team is very important. To develop two-way trust, to empower the team, to share council expectation with the team and to brief the council on team progress are the essential responsibilities that the Quality Council Coordinator must perform.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 206,
        "Question": "The long-term direction of the organization in which it wants to proceed in the future is known as __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Strategic Planning",
            "b) Short-Term Planning",
            "c) Operational Planning",
            "d) Contingency Planning"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Strategic Planning is the long-term direction of the organization in which it wants to proceed in the future. It connects the present with the vision of the organization in the future.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 207,
        "Question": "Identify the correct option with respect to the activities involved in Strategic Planning.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Developing goals only",
            "b) Developing objectives only",
            "c) Developing action plans only",
            "d) Developing goals, objectives and action plans"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Developing goals, objectives and action plans are the activities involved in Strategic Planning. Strategic Planning involves the long term direction in which the organization wants to proceed.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 208,
        "Question": "Which of the following is correct in terms of the scope for Strategic Planning?",
        "Options": [
            "a) One month",
            "b) Two months",
            "c) Three months",
            "d) Four years"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Strategic Planning is a long term direction in which the organization would like to see itself in the future. Hence, one month, two months and three months are short time periods that cannot be associated with Strategic Planning. Hence, four years is the correct option.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 209,
        "Question": "The attempts that are made to improve an organization’s performance by making mission statements concrete are called ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Goals",
            "b) Objectives",
            "c) Plans",
            "d) Action Plans"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Strategic Planning is one of the critical aspects of leadership. A quality leader must focus on strategic planning estimating the kind of challenges that the organization may face in the future.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 210,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a best practice for an organization when it is planning its goals?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Improving customer satisfaction target",
            "b) Cost reduction targets in a year",
            "c) Improving market share",
            "d) Decreasing market share"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The attempts that are made to improve an organization’s performance by making mission statements concrete are called goals of an organization. The other important activities in strategic planning are goals, objectives and action plans.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 211,
        "Question": "The operational definition of goals is called __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Goals",
            "b) Objectives",
            "c) Plans",
            "d) Action Plans"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Improving customer satisfaction target, Cost reduction targets in a year, Improving market share and improving shareholders’ value are the best practices for an organization when it is planning its goals. The other important activities involved in strategic planning are goals, objectives, and action plans.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 212,
        "Question": "Which of the following describes special tactics, assigned responsibilities, how resource allocation is done, scheduled activities and efforts and specify vision target?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Goals",
            "b) Special Objectives",
            "c) Plans",
            "d) Objectives"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The operational definition of goals is called the objectives of an organization. They can be measured, they have a time dimension and they help in reducing conflicts.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 213,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an example of strategic planning in an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The planned growth rate in sales",
            "b) Diversification of business into new lines",
            "c) Types of products to be offered",
            "d) The planning for natural disasters"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Plans describe special tactics, assigned responsibilities, how resource allocation is done, scheduled activities and efforts and specify vision targets. The other activities in strategic planning are the goals and objectives of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 214,
        "Question": "Identify the correct option with respect to the goals and objectives of an organization having a strategic quality planning.",
        "Options": [
            "a) They are Process and Result oriented",
            "b) They are Process oriented",
            "c) They are Result oriented",
            "d) They are neither Process oriented nor Result oriented"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The planned growth rate in sales, Diversification of business into new lines and Types of products to be offered are examples of strategic planning in an organization. The planning for natural disasters is to be included in the contingency plan of the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 215,
        "Question": "Identify the correct option with respect to the goals and objectives of an organization having a strategic quality planning.",
        "Options": [
            "a) They are based on data and driven by trend or pattern analysis",
            "b) They are based on hunches or guesses",
            "c) They are based on neither data nor guesses",
            "d) They are based on social media"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The goals and objectives of an organization having a strategic quality planning are Process and Result oriented. The goals and objectives of an organization having traditional strategic planning are results oriented.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 216,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is incorrect with respect to strategic quality planning cycle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The identification of customer needs is the first step",
            "b) The determination of customer positioning is the second step",
            "c) It is necessary to predict the future and is the third step",
            "d) The study of gap analysis and how to open the gap"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The goals and objectives of an organization having a strategic quality planning are based on data and driven by trend or pattern analysis. The goals and objectives of an organization having traditional strategic planning are based on hunches or guesses.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 217,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an important aspect of employee involvement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Employee motivation",
            "b) Employee empowerment",
            "c) Team and Teamwork",
            "d) Keeping employee morale down"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Employee motivation, Employee empowerment, Team, Teamwork, Recognition, Reward schemes, and Performance appraisal are important aspects of employee involvement. Employee morale should always be kept high. A healthy mind leads to a healthy body.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 218,
        "Question": "Motivation is the process of stimulating people to accomplish _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Desired goals",
            "b) Desired homework",
            "c) Desired assignment",
            "d) Desired homework and assignment"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Motivation is the process of stimulating people to accomplish desired goals. It is an important aspect of employee involvement. Employee involvement leads to the quick and successful growth of the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 219,
        "Question": "Motivation is the process of attempting to influence others to do their work through the possibility of getting rewards. Who gave this definition of ‘motivation’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Edwin B. Flippo",
            "b) E.F.L. Breach",
            "c) Crosby",
            "d) Deming"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Motivation is the process of attempting to influence others to do their work through the possibility of getting rewards. The definition was given by Edwin B. Flippo. Also, according to Scott, Motivation is the process of stimulating people to accomplish desired goals.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 220,
        "Question": "Which of the options is incorrect with respect to the importance of ‘employee motivation’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It promotes employee involvement",
            "b) It promotes job satisfaction",
            "c) Reduces absenteeism",
            "d) Increases absenteeism"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Employee motivation leads to employee involvement. It promotes job satisfaction. It reduces absenteeism as the workforce is motivated to work for the growth of the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 221,
        "Question": "Motivation creates a congenial working atmosphere in the organization and promotes __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Internal hatred",
            "b) External hatred",
            "c) Interpersonal cooperation",
            "d) Internal and external hatred"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  Motivation creates a congenial working atmosphere in the organization and promotes Interpersonal cooperation. A congenial working atmosphere will improve interdepartmental communication also with fewer barriers involved.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 222,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not part of the basic needs mentioned by Maslow?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Physiological needs",
            "b) Safety needs",
            "c) Social needs",
            "d) Hazard needs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: According to Maslow, basic needs are physiological needs, safety needs, social needs, esteem needs, and self – actualization needs. According to him, human motivation is a hierarchy of five needs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 223,
        "Question": "According to Maslow’s hierarchy of needs, the biological needs required to preserve human life are called __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Physiological needs",
            "b) Safety needs",
            "c) Social needs",
            "d) Hazard needs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to Maslow’s hierarchy of needs, the biological needs required to preserve human life are called physiological or survival needs. The other basic needs are safety needs, social needs, esteem needs, and self – actualization needs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 224,
        "Question": "According to Maslow’s hierarchy of needs, the needs for food, cloth, and shelter belong to _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Survival needs",
            "b) Social needs",
            "c) Esteem needs",
            "d) Self – actualization needs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to Maslow’s hierarchy of needs, the needs for food, cloth, and shelter belong to survival needs. They are supposed to be met first. Survival needs are also known as physiological needs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 225,
        "Question": "According to Maslow’s hierarchy of needs, which of the following does not belong to safety needs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Protection from fire and accident",
            "b) Lack of economic security involving health and insurance",
            "c) The desire for an orderly and predictable environment",
            "d) The desire to know the limits of acceptable behavior"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Protection from fire and accident, economic security involving health and insurance, the desire for an orderly and predictable environment and the desire to know the limits of acceptable behavior belong to the category of safety needs. Safety needs are activated when physiological needs are reasonably satisfied.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 226,
        "Question": "According to Maslow’s hierarchy of needs, which of the following does not belong to social needs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Friendship",
            "b) Exchange of feelings and grievances",
            "c) Belongingness",
            "d) Economic security"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: According to Maslow’s hierarchy of needs, friendship, exchange of feelings and grievances and belongingness belong to the category of social needs. Social needs accompanied by survival needs and safety needs is very important.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 227,
        "Question": "Which of the following needs are also known as self – realization needs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Survival needs",
            "b) Safety needs",
            "c) Social needs",
            "d) Self – actualization needs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Self – actualization needs are also known as self – realization needs. They refer to the desire to become everything that one is capable of becoming.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 228,
        "Question": "Which of the following needs according to Maslow’s hierarchy belong to the category of low-level needs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Survival needs, Safety needs, Esteem needs",
            "b) Survival needs, Safety needs, Social needs",
            "c) Safety needs, Social needs, Esteem needs",
            "d) Social needs, Esteem needs, Self – actualization needs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Survival needs, Safety needs, Social needs are low-level needs. Esteem needs and self – realization needs are high-level needs. Self – realization needs are also known as self – actualization needs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 229,
        "Question": "Herzberg’s Two Factor Theory is also known as ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Motivation – hygiene theory",
            "b) Motivation theory",
            "c) Hygiene theory",
            "d) Maslow’s hierarchy of needs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to Maslow’s hierarchy of needs, the low-level needs can be satisfied by monetary and non – monetary compensations. The low-level needs are survival needs, social needs, and safety needs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 230,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a Motivation factor according to Herzberg’s Two Factor Theory?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Achievement",
            "b) Recognition",
            "c) Responsibility",
            "d) Pay and security"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Herzberg’s Two Factor Theory is also known as motivation – hygiene theory. Both Maslow’s hierarchy of needs and Herzberg’s Two Factor Theory are important theories related to motivation.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 231,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a Hygiene factor according to Herzberg’s Two Factor Theory?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Supervisors",
            "b) Working conditions",
            "c) Interpersonal relationships",
            "d) Advancement and Growth"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Achievement, Recognition and Responsibility are Motivation Factors. Pay and security belongs to the category of Hygiene Factors. Both motivation and hygiene factors are part of Herzberg’s Two Factor Theory.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 232,
        "Question": "According to Herzberg’s Two Factor Theory, Motivation factors and Hygiene factors are also known as _________ and _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Satisfiers, Satisfiers",
            "b) Dissatisfiers, Satisfiers",
            "c) Satisfiers, Dissatisfiers",
            "d) Dissatisfiers, Dissatisfiers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Supervisors, Working conditions and Interpersonal relationships are Hygiene Factors. Advancement and Growth belongs to the category of Motivation Factors. Both motivation and hygience factors are part of Herzberg’s Two Factor Theory.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 233,
        "Question": " According to Herzberg’s Two Factor Theory, Hygiene Factors are also known as ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Maintenance factors",
            "b) Motivation factors",
            "c) Mission factors",
            "d) Machine factors"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: According to Herzberg’s Two Factor Theory, Motivation factors and Hygiene factors are also known as Satisfiers and Dissatisfiers respectively. Both Maslow’s hierarchy of needs and Herzberg’s Two Factor Theory are important theories related to motivation.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 234,
        "Question": "Empowerment is the opposite of ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Motivated",
            "b) Accomplishment",
            "c) Helplessness",
            "d) Goal"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Empowerment is the opposite of helplessness or dependency. An empowered employee is capable of handling small obstacles without guidance. An employee who is feeling helplessness comparatively will be in urgent need of help and is dependent.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 235,
        "Question": "Which are the two important factors on which empowerment depend on?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Individual’s personal choices and his family choices",
            "b) Individual’s personal choices and his manager’s choice",
            "c) Individual’s personal choices and the organizational climate",
            "d) The organizational climate and his manager’s choice"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: An individual’s personal choices and the organizational climate are two important factors on which empowerment depend on. The organizational climate can either encourage dependency or faster autonomy.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 236,
        "Question": "In the work environment, what is the meaning of empowerment?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Providing people the means, ability and authority to do something they have not done before",
            "b) Discouraging people from doing something they have not done before",
            "c) Threatening people to do something they have not done before",
            "d) Threatening people to do something they have done before"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the work environment, providing people the means, ability and authority to do something they have not done before is known as employee empowerment. Employee empowerment is an essential component of a progressive organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 237,
        "Question": "Which of the following is odd one out with respect to the operational definition of empowerment?",
        "Options": [
            "a) People have ability to take responsibility and ownership",
            "b) People have the confidence in taking responsibility and ownership",
            "c) People are committed to take responsibility and ownership",
            "d) People fear to take responsibility and ownership"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In an empowered organization, people have the ability, confidence and commitment to take responsibility and ownership to improve processes. They have the ability to initiate the necessary steps to make sure that customer satisfaction is achieved.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 238,
        "Question": "Job ______ targets expanding the content of an individual’s job.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Enrichment",
            "b) Nourishment",
            "c) Empowerment",
            "d) Card"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Job Enrichment targets expanding the content of an individual’s job. The individual is motivated by assigning him/her with additional responsibilities. It is a technique to ensure the individual is having satisfaction in his/her work.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 239,
        "Question": "Job ______ targets expanding the context of an individual’s job.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Enrichment",
            "b) Nourishment",
            "c) Empowerment",
            "d) Card"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Job Empowerment targets expanding the context of an individual’s job. It is related to the interactions and inter-dependencies with other functions of the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 240,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a condition required to create the empowered environment?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Everyone must understand the need for change",
            "b) Some people must understand the need for change",
            "c) The system needs to change to the new paradigm",
            "d) The organization must provide information, education and skill to its employees"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The conditions required to create the empowered environment are that everyone must understand the need for change, the system needs to change to the new paradigm, and the organization must provide information, education and skill to its employees. An empowered environment allows the organization to reach greater heights.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 241,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of empowered employees?",
        "Options": [
            "a) They are responsible for their own task",
            "b) They are given a free hand in their work",
            "c) They balance their own goals with those of the organization",
            "d) They are not well trained, equipped, and creative and customer oriented"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: An empowered employee is an added asset to an organization’s growth and progress. They are responsible for their own task, they are given a free hand in their work, they balance their own goals with those of the organization and they are well trained, equipped, and creative and customer oriented.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 242,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of empowered employees?",
        "Options": [
            "a) They are critical, have self-esteem, and are motivated",
            "b) They are challenged and encouraged",
            "c) They monitor and improve their work continuously",
            "d) They do not find new goals and change challenges"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: An empowered employee is an added asset to an organization’s growth and progress. They are critical, have self-esteem, and are motivated, they are challenged and encouraged, they monitor and improve their work continuously and they find new goals and change challenges.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 243,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a way to empower employees in an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Telling them what their responsibilities are",
            "b) Giving them authority equal to the responsibility assigned to them",
            "c) Setting standards of excellence",
            "d) Closing all training opportunities"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The workforce in an organization can be empowered by telling them what their responsibilities are giving them authority equal to the responsibility assigned to them, setting standards of excellence and by providing them training that will enable them to maintain standards. It is essential nowadays to have an empowered organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 244,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a way to empower employees in an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Giving them knowledge and information",
            "b) Providing them with feedback on their performance",
            "c) Trusting them and creating trustworthiness in the organization",
            "d) Hurting their dignity and respect"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The workforce in an organization can be empowered by giving them knowledge and information, providing them with feedback on their performance, trusting them and creating trustworthiness in the organization and treating them with dignity and respect. It is essential nowadays to have an empowered organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 245,
        "Question": "A group of people working with common objectives or goals is known as a _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Team",
            "b) Teamwork",
            "c) Group",
            "d) Club"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A group of people working with common objectives or goals is known as a team. A team needs to inculcate teamwork. An empowered team showing teamwork is the characteristic of a successful organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 246,
        "Question": "The cumulative action of a team in which an individual member keeps aside his/her interests and opinions to fulfill the objectives or goal of the group is known as _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Team",
            "b) Teamwork",
            "c) Group",
            "d) Club"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The cumulative action of a team in which an individual member keeps aside his/her interests and opinions to fulfill the objectives or goal of the group is known as teamwork. An empowered team showing teamwork is the characteristic of a successful organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 247,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of teamwork?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Improved solutions to quality problems",
            "b) Improved ownership of solutions",
            "c) Improved communications",
            "d) Decline in integration"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Improved solutions to quality problems, improved ownership of solutions, improved communications and improved integration are benefits of teamwork. A team with teamwork also faces fewer problems in the future.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 248,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a classification of a team?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process improvement team",
            "b) Cross-functional team",
            "c) Natural work team",
            "d) Group-directed/group-managed work team"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Process improvement team, cross-functional team, natural work team, and self-directed / self-managed work team are four major classifications of a team. Every organization needs a team to attain success and teamwork must be paramount in it.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 249,
        "Question": "The team which focuses its attention on improvements of a process that is already operating to a satisfactory level is called the ______________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process improvement team",
            "b) Cross-functional team",
            "c) Natural work team",
            "d) Group-directed/group-managed work team"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The team which focuses its attention on improvements of a process that is already operating to a satisfactory level is called the Process improvement team. The other types of teams are Cross-functional teams, Natural work teams, and Self-directed / self-managed work teams.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 250,
        "Question": "The life cycle of a process improvement team is ________ and after the objective is reached the team is ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Temporary, Inaugurated",
            "b) Permanent, Disbanded",
            "c) Temporary, Disbanded",
            "d) Permanent, Inaugurated"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The life cycle of a process improvement team is temporary and after the objective is reached the team is disbanded. The internal or external supplier, as well as the internal or external customer, is also included in the team depending upon the location of the sub-process.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 251,
        "Question": "Cross-functional teams are _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Temporary",
            "b) Permanent",
            "c) Neither Temporary nor Permanent",
            "d) Either Temporary or Permanent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Cross-functional teams are formed to solve complex problems. Six to ten members are selected from various functional areas of management to constitute cross-functional teams.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 252,
        "Question": "The person from the quality council who provides support to the organization is known as ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sponsor",
            "b) Customer",
            "c) Founder",
            "d) Manager"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The person from the quality council who provides support to the organization is known as Sponsor. A sponsor is needed for effective liaison with the quality council.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 253,
        "Question": "A ________ is a document that defines the team’s mission, boundaries, the background of the problem, the team’s authority and duties, and resources.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Team",
            "b) Team Charter",
            "c) Team Work",
            "d) Work"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A Team Charter is a document that defines the team’s mission, boundaries, the background of the problem, the team’s authority and duties, and resources. It also mentions about the members and their assigned roles – leader, recorder, timekeeper, and facilitator.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 254,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a reason to train team members of an organization to make a successful team?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To train them in problem-solving techniques",
            "b) To train them in team dynamics",
            "c) To train them in communication skills",
            "d) To train them in threatening customers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Training is essential in an organization so that every team member is aware of his/her responsibilities towards the progress of the organization. We need to train them in problem-solving techniques, team dynamics, and communication skills.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 255,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of a successful team in an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Appropriate Leadership",
            "b) Balanced Participation",
            "c) Cohesiveness",
            "d) Mutual enmity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In an organization, the periodic status report of the team should be given to the quality council. A proper review system must be established so that team weakness can be understood and improvements are made to avoid them in the future.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 256,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a roadblock to team progress in an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Insufficient training",
            "b) Lack of planning",
            "c) Incompatible rewards and compensation",
            "d) Sufficient training"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In an organization, open communication should be encouraged in a successful team. Everyone must be free to let their progressive idea reach top management. If the idea can improve the organization’s performance, it must be implemented after proper review.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 257,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a roadblock to team progress in an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lack of management support",
            "b) Project scope too large",
            "c) Project objectives are significant",
            "d) No time to do improvement work"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Appropriate Leadership, Balanced Participation, and Cohesiveness are characteristics of a successful team in an organization. Mutual enmity should not exist and everybody should participate to create a friendly working atmosphere. Open communication must be encouraged.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 258,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not part of the forming stage of team development in an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Team’s purpose",
            "b) Members’ roles",
            "c) Acceptance of roles",
            "d) Hostilities and Personal needs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Insufficient training, Lack of planning, and incompatible rewards and compensation are some of the roadblocks to team progress in an organization. Sufficient training will let the team do well and as a result of a successful team, the organization will do well too.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 259,
        "Question": "During the norming stage of team development in an organization, ______ and _____ relationships get established among team members.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Formal, informal",
            "b) Informal, abnormal",
            "c) Formal, abnormal",
            "d) Informal, hate"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  Lack of management support, Project scope too large, and  No time to do improvement work are some of the roadblocks to team progress in an organization. If the project objectives are not significant then it becomes a roadblock too.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 260,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a stage of team development in an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Performing Stage",
            "b) Maintenance Stage",
            "c) Evaluating Stage",
            "d) Deforming Stage"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Team’s purpose, Members’ roles and Acceptance of roles are learned in the forming stage of team development. Hostilities and Personal needs emerge in the storming stage of team development.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 261,
        "Question": "The acknowledgement of an employee’s outstanding performance is known as _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Recognition",
            "b) Punishment",
            "c) Reprimand",
            "d) Rebuke"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The acknowledgement of an employee’s outstanding performance is known as Recognition. Recognition helps in providing boost to the hard work put up an employee at work.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 262,
        "Question": "Which of the following option is incorrect with reference to recognition of an employee at work?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It is a form of positive motivation",
            "b) The workforce feels accepted",
            "c) The workforce feels they are in winning role",
            "d) It will discourage the workforce"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Recognition is an acknowledgement of an employee’s outstanding performance. It is a form of positive motivation. The workforce feels accepted and in a winning role.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 263,
        "Question": "Recognition is a way of making the workforce work for __________ of the organization.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Continuous improvement",
            "b) Discontinuous improvement",
            "c) Continuous downfall",
            "d) Discontinuous downfall"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Recognition is a way to sustain employee’s interest. The workforce put a lot of effort in the organization’s progress. By recognizing them, it helps in sustaining their interest in the progress of the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 264,
        "Question": "Recognition in an organization can be __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Financial or psychological",
            "b) Financial only",
            "c) Psychological only",
            "d) Financial or psychological or both"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Recognition is a way of making the workforce work for Continuous improvement of the organization. Continuous improvement is the prime motivation for succeeding in the competitive world.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 265,
        "Question": "Rewards provided in an organization are ______ in nature.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Tangible",
            "b) Intangible",
            "c) Corrupt",
            "d) Corrupt and Intangible"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Recognition in an organization can be financial or psychological or both. It is important to recognize the workforce to motivate them to work for the continuous improvement of the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 266,
        "Question": "Which of the following are the types of reward system in an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Interior and exterior",
            "b) Intrinsic and exterior",
            "c) Interior and extrinsic",
            "d) Intrinsic and extrinsic"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Rewards provided in an organization are tangible in nature. Some of the examples of rewards provided in an organization are increased salaries, commissions, cash bonuses, and gain sharing.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 267,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a type of extrinsic reward?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Profit sharing",
            "b) Gain sharing",
            "c) Employment security",
            "d) Quality based promotions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Recognition is also a way in which a company shows its appreciation for better performance. It helps in establishing mutual trust with the workforce. An empowered and motivated organization will always be successful.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 268,
        "Question": "When the performance of an organization is driven by promoting awareness, alignment, teamwork, communication and involvement, it is known as ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Gain sharing",
            "b) Profit sharing",
            "c) Loss sharing",
            "d) Profit and Loss sharing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Intrinsic and extrinsic are the two types of reward system in an organization. Intrinsic rewards are related to feelings of accomplishment or self-worth. Extrinsic rewards are related to pay or compensation issues.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 269,
        "Question": "When an organization shares its financial success and encourages employee identity with organization’s success, it is known as __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Gain sharing",
            "b) Profit sharing",
            "c) Loss sharing",
            "d) Profit and Loss sharing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Profit sharing, Gain sharing, and Employment security are the types of extrinsic rewards provided in an organization. Quality based promotions belong to the category of intrinsic rewards.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 270,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an incorrect way of providing recognition in an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Create a ‘best ideas of the year’ booklet",
            "b) Feature the quality team of the month",
            "c) Develop a ‘behind the scenes’ award",
            "d) Feature the worst performer of the month"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When the performance of an organization is driven by promoting awareness, alignment, teamwork, communication and involvement, it is known as Gain sharing. The plan commonly applies to single facility or site.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 271,
        "Question": "The systematic process of assessing an employee’s job performance is known as _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Performance Criteria",
            "b) Performance Appraisal",
            "c) Bonus",
            "d) Discount"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The systematic process of assessing an employee’s job performance is known as Performance Appraisal. The criteria of evaluation is the projects on which the employee worked and the contribution towards the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 272,
        "Question": "Performance Appraisal is also known as _________ or __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Performance review, Annual review",
            "b) Performance review, Loss review",
            "c) Loss review, Annual review",
            "d) Discount review, Loss review"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Performance Appraisal is also known as Performance review or Annual review. It is the process of evaluation of an employee’s performance and his/her contribution towards the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 273,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of the performance appraisal system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Managers can assign the right job to the right employee based on his/her skills",
            "b) Employees can assess their performance",
            "c) Employees can compare their performance with fellow colleagues",
            "d) Employees feel demotivated after assessing their performance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: There are many advantages of the performance appraisal system. Managers can assign the right job to the right employee based on his/her skills. Employees can assess their performance and employees can compare their performance with fellow colleagues.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 274,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a performance appraisal factor?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Attendance",
            "b) Attitude",
            "c) Quality of work",
            "d) Number of social media handles"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Attendance, attitude, and quality of work are some of the performance appraisal factors. Some of the other performance appraisal factors are efficiency and amount of work.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 275,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a physical or objective performance appraisal factor?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Attendance",
            "b) Amount of work",
            "c) Efficiency",
            "d) Friendliness"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Attendance, amount of work, and efficiency are some of the physical or objective performance appraisal factors. It can be easily maintained by the Human Resource Development manager.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 276,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a subjective performance appraisal factor?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Attitude",
            "b) Behavior",
            "c) Amount of work",
            "d) Friendliness"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Attitude, behavior, and friendliness are some of the subjective performance appraisal factors. It is difficult to determine. But for proper evaluation of an employee’s performance, both subjective and physical factors are essential.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 277,
        "Question": "Quality Planning is also known as ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality by Design",
            "b) Process Control and Regulatory",
            "c) Lean Six Sigma",
            "d) Rapid Six Sigma"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Juran’s Quality Trilogy includes Quality Planning, Quality Control, and Quality Improvement. Quality Planning is also referred to as Quality by Design.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 278,
        "Question": "The development processes in an organization for product or service is referred to as _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality by Design",
            "b) Process Control and Regulatory",
            "c) Lean Six Sigma",
            "d) Rapid Six Sigma"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The development processes in an organization for product or service is referred to as Quality by Design. Quality by Design is also known as Design for Six Sigma.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 279,
        "Question": "Process Control and Regulatory is a part of _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality Planning",
            "b) Quality Control",
            "c) Quality Improvement",
            "d) Quality Assurance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Process Control and Regulatory is a part of Quality Control. The aim of Quality Control is to comply with international standards such as ISO 9000. Quality Planning, Quality Control, and Quality Improvement are part of Juran’s Quality Trilogy.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 280,
        "Question": "It is important to know about ________ for quality planning.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer needs",
            "b) Customer quality",
            "c) Customer satisfaction",
            "d) Manager satisfaction"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It is important to know about Customer needs for quality planning. If the product or service is not aligned with customer needs, then the product will not have any marketability.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 281,
        "Question": "Which of the following is associated with defining of product or service features and specifications?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality Planning",
            "b) Quality Control",
            "c) Quality Improvement",
            "d) Quality Assurance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Quality Planning is associated with defining of product or service features and specifications. The input to product or service specifications and features is taken from customer. The customer needs are translated to the product or service features and specifications.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 282,
        "Question": "Which of the following is associated with developing the processes that are needed to deliver quality products or services complying with customer needs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality Planning",
            "b) Quality Control",
            "c) Quality Improvement",
            "d) Quality Assurance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Quality Planning is associated with developing the processes that are needed to deliver quality products or services complying with customer needs. Customer needs are translated to the product or service specifications and features. The specifications and features then become the basis for developing the further processes involved.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 283,
        "Question": "The planning of periodic checks and inspection to ensure product specifications and features are met is associated with __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality Meet",
            "b) Quality Control",
            "c) Quality Planning",
            "d) Quality Improvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The planning of periodic checks and inspection to ensure product specifications and features are met is associated with Quality Control. It is done after Quality Planning in which processes are developed.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 284,
        "Question": "The process of checking the actual performance with the standard performance is associated with __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality Meet",
            "b) Quality Control",
            "c) Quality Planning",
            "d) Quality Improvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The process of checking the actual performance with the standard performance is associated with Quality Control. The metrics are determined as soon as the processes for production are developed.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 285,
        "Question": "The process of identifying the scope for process improvement is associated with ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality Meet",
            "b) Quality Control",
            "c) Quality Planning",
            "d) Quality Improvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The process of identifying the scope for process improvement is associated with Quality Improvement. Even though we try to ensure quality by planning and control but sometimes the scope of improvement develops. So, the organization must look at even Quality Improvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 286,
        "Question": "Juran’s Trilogy diagram is a plot between ______ and _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Time, percent defective",
            "b) Distance, percent defective",
            "c) Speed, percent defective",
            "d) Velocity, percent defective"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Juran’s Trilogy diagram is a plot between time and percent defective. It shows the way in which Juran’s Trilogy is designed to reduce the cost of quality over time.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 287,
        "Question": "According to Juran’s Trilogy diagram, errors made in the planning process give rise to _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Chronic waste region",
            "b) Waste region",
            "c) Temporary waste region",
            "d) Improvement region"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to Juran’s Trilogy diagram, errors made in the planning process give rise to chronic waste region. Quality control enables defects to be identified and controlled.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 288,
        "Question": " According to Juran’s Trilogy diagram, errors made in the quality control process give rise to ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Chronic waste region",
            "b) Waste region",
            "c) Temporary waste region",
            "d) Sporadic spike"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: According to Juran’s Trilogy diagram, errors made in the quality control process give rise to sporadic spike. The defects during such an event are close to 40%.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 289,
        "Question": "Juran’s Trilogy is a ______ and ______ continuous process improvement approach.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Open, never-ending",
            "b) Open, ending",
            "c) Cyclic, never-ending",
            "d) Cyclic, ending"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Sporadic waste can be identified and corrected through quality control. The defects according to the Juran’s trilogy diagram are close to 40% when a sporadic spike occurs.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 290,
        "Question": "Who gave the classification of five types of quality problems?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Deming",
            "b) Gerald F. Smith",
            "c) Crosby",
            "d) Juran"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: According to Gerald F. Smith, there are five types of quality problems. They are compliance problems, unstructured problems, efficiency problems, process-design problems, and product-design problems.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 291,
        "Question": "When a structured system having standardized inputs, processes, and outputs is performing unacceptably from the customer’s point of view, then we have _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compliance problems",
            "b) Unstructured problems",
            "c) Efficiency problems",
            "d) Product-design problems"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When a structured system having standardized inputs, processes, and outputs is performing unacceptably from the customer’s point of view, then we have compliance problems. It is a type of quality problem as described by Gerald F. Smith.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 292,
        "Question": "How are unstructured problems different from compliance problems?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compliance problems are not specified by standards",
            "b) Compliance problems cannot be collected by feedback process",
            "c) Unstructured problems are not specified by standards",
            "d) There is no difference, both are similar"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Compliance problems can be identified by comparing with standards or by collecting feedback from internal and/or external customers. It is a type of quality problem as described by Gerald F. Smith.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 293,
        "Question": "When the system is performing unacceptably from the owner’s point of view, then we have _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Compliance problems",
            "b) Unstructured problems",
            "c) Efficiency problems",
            "d) Product-design problems"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Unstructured problems are similar to compliance problems except for the fact that unstructured problems are not specified by standards. Unstructured problems are a type of quality problems as described by Gerald F. Smith.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 294,
        "Question": "Efficiency problems can be identified by ____________ and ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Benchmarking, Employee feedback",
            "b) Benchmarking, Founder feedback",
            "c) Benchmarking only",
            "d) Employee feedback only"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Unstructured problems can be identified through negative customer feedback. Unstructured problems are a type of quality problems as described by Gerald F. Smith.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 295,
        "Question": "Which of the following cannot be considered as a motivation behind identification of process-design problems?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Poor performance",
            "b) Introduction of new products",
            "c) Knowledge of benchmarking that we can do better",
            "d) The inherent desire to change the existing process"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: When the system is performing unacceptably from the owner’s point of view, then we have efficiency problems. Efficiency problem is a type of quality problem as described by Gerald F. Smith.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 296,
        "Question": "Process-design problems involve the revision of ___________ and the development of ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Existing processes, new processes",
            "b) Existing processes, existing processes",
            "c) New processes, existing processes",
            "d) New processes, existing processes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Efficiency problems can be identified by benchmarking and employee feedback.  Efficiency problem is a type of quality problem as described by Gerald F. Smith.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 297,
        "Question": "Product-design problems involve the improvement of ___________ and the development of ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Existing products, new products",
            "b) Existing products, existing products",
            "c) New products, existing products",
            "d) New products, existing products"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Poor performance, introduction of new products, and knowledge of benchmarking that we can do better are the motivation factors that lead to identification of process-design problems. Process-design problems are a type of quality problems as described by Gerald F. Smith.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 298,
        "Question": "Product-design problems arise due to changing ____________ or competitor coming up with a better product.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer needs",
            "b) Owner needs",
            "c) Manager needs",
            "d) Supplier needs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Process-design problems involve the revision of existing processes and the development of new processes. Process-design problems are a type of quality problems as described by Gerald F. Smith.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 299,
        "Question": "Who gave the Four R’s of Total Improvement?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Jack L. Huffman",
            "b) Deming",
            "c) Crosby",
            "d) Taguchi"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Jack L. Huffman gave the Four R’s of Total Improvement. They are Repair strategy, Refinement strategy, Renovation strategy, and Reinvention strategy.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 300,
        "Question": "The quality improvement strategy that aims at fixing the things so that they can perform their designed functions is called _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Repair strategy",
            "b) Refinement strategy",
            "c) Renovation strategy",
            "d) Reinvention strategy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The quality improvement strategy that aims at fixing the things so that they can perform their designed functions is called repair strategy. Jack L. Huffman gave the Four R’s of Total Improvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 301,
        "Question": "In which of the following quality improvement strategy, the customer’s faulty product is either replaced or repaired as a temporary or short-term measure?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Renovation strategy",
            "b) Refinement strategy",
            "c) Repair strategy",
            "d) Reinvention strategy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In repair strategy, the customer’s faulty product is either replaced or repaired as a temporary or short-term measure. Jack L. Huffman gave the Four R’s of Total Improvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 302,
        "Question": "The quality improvement strategy that involves activities that continually improve a process that is not broken is called ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Repair strategy",
            "b) Refinement strategy",
            "c) Renovation strategy",
            "d) Reinvention strategy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The quality improvement strategy that involves activities that continually improve a process that is not broken is called refinement strategy. The other quality improvement strategies are repair strategy, renovation strategy, and reinvention strategy.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 303,
        "Question": "In which quality improvement strategy, improvements to processes, products and services are achieved on an incremental basis?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Rejuvenate strategy",
            "b) Refinement strategy",
            "c) Renovation strategy",
            "d) Reinvention strategy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In refinement strategy, improvements to processes, products and services are achieved on an incremental basis. The other quality improvement strategies are repair strategy, renovation strategy, and reinvention strategy.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 304,
        "Question": "The combinations of ________ are involved in organizational programs such as process improvement teams, suggestion systems, and empowerment.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Repair and refinement strategies",
            "b) Refinement and renovation strategies",
            "c) Renovation and reinvention strategies",
            "d) Reinvention and repair strategies"
        ],
        "Answer": "vAnswer: a\nExplanation: Implementing refinement strategy improves efficiency and effectiveness. The other quality improvement strategies are repair strategy, renovation strategy, and reinvention strategy.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 305,
        "Question": "Renovation strategy is ______ compared to repair and refinement strategy.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equally costly",
            "b) Less costly",
            "c) More costly",
            "d) Cost cannot be compared"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The combinations of repair and refinement strategies are involved in organizational programs such as process improvement teams, suggestion systems, and empowerment. Jack L. Huffman gave the Four R’s of Total Improvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 306,
        "Question": "Re-engineering strategy is also known as ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Repair strategy",
            "b) Refinement strategy",
            "c) Renovation strategy",
            "d) Reinvention strategy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Innovation and technological advancements are two key factors in renovation strategy.  The other quality improvement strategies are repair strategy, refinement strategy, and reinvention strategy.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 307,
        "Question": "The quality improvement strategy which involves developing a new product, service, process, or activity using teams based on a complete understanding of the customer’s requirements and expectations is known as __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Repair strategy",
            "b) Refinement strategy",
            "c) Renovation strategy",
            "d) Reinvention strategy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Renovation strategy is more costly compared to repair and refinement strategy. It is usually done with teams rather than individuals.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 308,
        "Question": "PDCA cycle is used for _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Continuous improvement",
            "b) Discontinuous improvement",
            "c) Intermittent improvement",
            "d) Seldom improvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: PDCA cycle stands for Plan, Do, Check, and Act. It is a continuous improvement technique. It is a cyclic process and is repeated again and again for continuous improvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 309,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a use of the PDCA cycle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Starting a new project aimed at improvement",
            "b) For continuous improvement",
            "c) As a project planning tool",
            "d) For intermittent improvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: PDCA cycle stands for Plan, Do, Check, and Act. It is a continuous improvement technique. PDCA cycle can be considered as a project planning tool.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 310,
        "Question": "‘To define the problem’ is a part of which phase of PDCA cycle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Plan",
            "b) Do",
            "c) Check",
            "d) Act"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: PDCA cycle can be used when starting a new project aimed at improvement. It can be used as a project planning tool and as a tool for continuous improvement. It can also be used when we need to do data collection and analysis.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 311,
        "Question": "‘To determine the quality objectives and the critical factors’ is a part of which phase of PDCA cycle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Plan",
            "b) Do",
            "c) Check",
            "d) Act"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘To define the problem’ is a part of the ‘Planning’ phase of the PDCA cycle. We need to also analyze the causes of the problem and draft an action plan for solving the problem.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 312,
        "Question": "‘To generate possible solutions’ and ‘To select the most feasible solution’ is a part of which phase of PDCA cycle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Plan",
            "b) Do",
            "c) Check",
            "d) Act"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘To determine the quality objectives and the critical factors’ is a part of the ‘Planning’ phase of the PDCA cycle. We need to also define the performance indicators.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 313,
        "Question": "‘To train all employees in quality improvement methods and techniques’ is a part of which phase of PDCA cycle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Plan",
            "b) Do",
            "c) Check",
            "d) Act"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘To generate possible solutions’ and ‘To select the most feasible solution’ is a part of ‘Planning’ phase of the PDCA cycle. The other phases of the PDCA cycle are Do, Check, and Act.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 314,
        "Question": "‘To form project team that will focus on quality improvement processes’ is a part of which phase of PDCA cycle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Plan",
            "b) Do",
            "c) Check",
            "d) Act"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: It is recommended to try the plan made in the planning phase on a limited scale or conduct and experiment to test the proposed improvement. This is because corrections if necessary can be made in the initial stages. This will also reduce the cost associated with delivering a poor quality product.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 315,
        "Question": "‘To evaluate the trial project with the already decided performance indicators’ is a part of which phase of PDCA cycle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Plan",
            "b) Do",
            "c) Check",
            "d) Act"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘To train all employees in quality improvement methods and techniques’ is a part of ‘Do’ phase of the PDCA cycle. The other phases of the PDCA cycle are Plan, Check, and Act.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 316,
        "Question": "Which of the following decision is not part of the ‘Action’ phase?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Introducing the ‘Plan’",
            "b) Adjusting the ‘Plan’",
            "c) Rejecting the ‘Plan’",
            "d) Defining the problem"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘To form project team that will focus on quality improvement process’ is a part of ‘Do’ phase of the PDCA cycle. The other phases of the PDCA cycle are Plan, Check, and Act.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 317,
        "Question": "‘To document the standard procedures regarding improvement’ is a part of which phase of the PDCA cycle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Plan",
            "b) Do",
            "c) Check",
            "d) Act"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ‘To evaluate the trial project with the already decided performance indicators’ is a part of ‘Checking’ phase of the PDCA cycle. After evaluation, we need to also check whether the improvement has been successful or not.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 318,
        "Question": "In which country was 5S invented?",
        "Options": [
            "a) India",
            "b) Japan",
            "c) Vietnam",
            "d) Norway"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: 5S is defined as a housekeeping technique used to establish and maintain a productive and quality environment in an organization. A work place which is well organized will result in safer, more efficient and more productive operation.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 319,
        "Question": "What is the English equivalent of the Japanese word ‘Seiri’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sorting out",
            "b) Systematic arrangement",
            "c) Standardizing",
            "d) Self-discipline"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: 5S was invented in Japan. It stands for five Japanese words starting with SEIRI, SEITON, SEISO, SEIKETSU, and SHITSUKE.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 320,
        "Question": "What is the English equivalent of the Japanese word ‘Seiton’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sorting out",
            "b) Systematic arrangement",
            "c) Standardizing",
            "d) Self-discipline"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘Sorting out’ is the English equivalent of the Japanese word ‘Seiri’. The other Japanese words parts of 5S are SEITON, SEISO, SEIKETSU, and SHITSUKE.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 321,
        "Question": "Which of the following from the 5S technique means ‘to separate out all unnecessary things and eliminate them’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Seiri",
            "b) Seiton",
            "c) Seiso",
            "d) Seiketsu"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘Systematic arrangement’ is the English equivalent of the Japanese word ‘Seiton’. The other Japanese words parts of the 5S are SEIRI, SEISO, SEIKETSU, and SHITSUKE.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 322,
        "Question": "Which of the following from the 5S technique means ‘to arrange the essential things in order, so that they can be easily accessed’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Seiri",
            "b) Seiton",
            "c) Seiso",
            "d) Seiketsu"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘Seiri’ means to ‘sort out’. So, we need to separate out all unnecessary things and eliminate them from our workplace. The other Japanese words parts of 5S are SEITON, SEISO, SEIKETSU, and SHITSUKE.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 323,
        "Question": "What is the English equivalent of the Japanese word ‘Seiso’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sorting out",
            "b) Systematic arrangement",
            "c) Scrub, shine, sweep",
            "d) Self-discipline"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘Seiton’ means ‘systematic arrangement’. So, we need to arrange the essential things in order, so that they can be easily accessed. The other Japanese words parts of 5S are SEIRI, SEISO, SEIKETSU, and SHITSUKE.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 324,
        "Question": "What is the English equivalent of the Japanese word ‘Seiketsu’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sorting out",
            "b) Systematic arrangement",
            "c) Scrub, shine, sweep",
            "d) Standardizing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ‘Scrub, shine, sweep’ is the English equivalent of the Japanese word ‘Seiso’. The other Japanese words parts of 5S are SEIRI, SEITON, SEIKETSU, and SHITSUKE.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 325,
        "Question": "What is the English equivalent of the Japanese word ‘Shitsuke’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sorting out",
            "b) Systematic arrangement",
            "c) Standardizing",
            "d) Self-discipline"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘Standardizing’ is the English equivalent of the Japanese word ‘Seiketsu’. The other Japanese words parts of 5S are SEIRI, SEITON, SEISO, and SHITSUKE.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 326,
        "Question": "Which of the following from the 5S technique means ‘to clean the workplace, everything, everyday, without fail’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Seiri",
            "b) Seiton",
            "c) Seiso",
            "d) Seiketsu"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘Self-discipline’ is the English equivalent of the Japanese word ‘Shitsuke’. The other Japanese words parts of 5S are SEIRI, SEITON, SEISO, and SEIKETSU.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 327,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of implementing 5S technique?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To improve work efficiency",
            "b) To standardize work practices",
            "c) To improve work discipline",
            "d) To create a dirty workplace"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ‘Seiso’ means to ‘scrub, shine, and sweep’. So, we need to clean the workplace, everything, every day, without fail. The other Japanese words parts of 5S are SEIRI, SEITON, SEIKETSU, and SHITSUKE.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 328,
        "Question": "Kaizen refers to _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Continuous improvement",
            "b) Intermittent improvement",
            "c) Discontinuous improvement",
            "d) Stop improvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Kaizen is a Japanese word which refers to continuous improvement. In other words, it means improvement over improvement. In the process of Kaizen, improvements are accomplished gradually in small increments.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 329,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the aim of Kaizen process?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To make processes efficient",
            "b) To make processes effective",
            "c) To make processes controllable",
            "d) To make processes uncontrollable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: To make processes efficient, to make processes effective, and to make processes controllable are the aim of Kaizen process. Kaizen is a Japanese word which means continuous improvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 330,
        "Question": "Kairyo refers to improvements through ________, and does not allow ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Innovation, constant improvement",
            "b) Constant improvement, innovation",
            "c) Discontinuous improvement, constant improvement",
            "d) Innovation, discontinuous improvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the process of Kaizen, improvements are accomplished gradually in small increments. To make processes efficient, to make processes effective, and to make processes controllable are the aim of Kaizen process.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 331,
        "Question": "Kaizen works well in _________ and Kairyo works well in _____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Slow-growth economy, fast-growth economy",
            "b) Fast-growth economy, slow-growth economy",
            "c) Fast-growth economy, fast-growth economy",
            "d) Slow-growth economy, slow-growth economy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Kairyo is a Western philosophy. Kairyo refers to improvements through innovation, and does not allow constant improvement. Improvements happen in one or two great jumps.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 332,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an aspect of Kaizen philosophy?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer orientation",
            "b) Adaptability to changing environment",
            "c) Good labor management relations",
            "d) Increasing waste"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Kaizen works well in slow-growth economy and Kairyo works well in fast-growth economy. Kaizen is a Japanese philosophy. Kairyo is a Western philosophy.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 333,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an aspect of Kaizen philosophy?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process driven",
            "b) Quality awareness, quality control",
            "c) Standardization",
            "d) Ineffective leadership"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Kaizen requires little investment but great effort to maintain it. It is a continuous improvement process in small incremental steps. Kairyo requires large investment, but little effort to maintain it.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 334,
        "Question": "According to Kaizen philosophy, which of the following does not belong to the team dynamics?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Problem solving",
            "b) Communication skills",
            "c) Conflict resolution",
            "d) Creating conflicts"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Customer orientation, adaptability to changing environment, and good labor management relations are some of the aspects of Kaizen philosophy. Kaizen philosophy also focuses on reducing waste.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 335,
        "Question": "Which of the following does Kaizen improvement process not focus on?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5S",
            "b) Poka-Yoke",
            "c) Just-in-time principles",
            "d) Improvement by innovation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Process driven, quality awareness, quality control, standardization, and effective leadership are some of the aspects of Kaizen philosophy. Kaizen philosophy also focuses on Total employee involvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 336,
        "Question": "Poka-yoke is also known as _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Mistake-proofing",
            "b) Mistake",
            "c) Proofreading",
            "d) Mistake and proofreading"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Poka-yoke is also known as mistake-proofing. It is a Japanese term. It is considered as a quality improvement mechanism.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 337,
        "Question": "What do Yokeru and Poka mean respectively?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Avoid, inadvertent errors",
            "b) Inadvertent errors, avoid",
            "c) Inadvertent mistakes, avoid",
            "d) Inadvertent errors, inadvertent mistakes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Yokeru means ‘avoid’ and Poka means ‘inadvertent errors’. It is a part of the Japanese term Poka-yoke. Poka-yoke is considered as a quality improvement mechanism.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 338,
        "Question": "Poka-yoke______ an error as soon as it is being made and _______ it from reaching the next operation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Promotes, promotes",
            "b) Detects, prevents",
            "c) Prevents, detects",
            "d) Promotes, prevents"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Poka-yoke detects an error as soon as it is being made and prevents it from reaching the next operation. It is a Japanese term. It is considered as a quality improvement mechanism.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 339,
        "Question": "Who formalized the concept of Poka-yoke?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Dr. Shigeo Shingo",
            "b) Deming",
            "c) Crosby",
            "d) Juran"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Dr. Shigeo Shingo formalized the concept of Poka-yoke. It is a Japanese term. It is considered as a quality improvement mechanism.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 340,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of mistake proofing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Prevents error occurrence",
            "b) Prevents defect occurrence",
            "c) Little or no formal training",
            "d) Cost ineffective"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The advantages of mistake proofing are that it prevents error occurrence, prevents defect occurrence, and requires little or no formal training. It is cost effective in nature. It is also easy to implement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 341,
        "Question": "An operator in a manufacturing company is faced with the challenge of using a poka-yoke device. It is difficult to operate and requires continuous attention. What can you infer from the following scenario?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The operator must read the operation manual",
            "b) Poka-yoke device should be easy to install and usable to all",
            "c) The operator is lacking operational skills",
            "d) The operator must be dismissed from service"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Poka-yoke device should be easy to install and usable to all. It should not require continuous attention and must be low cost also.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 342,
        "Question": "Who can develop a poka-yoke device?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Founder",
            "b) Co-Founder",
            "c) Manager",
            "d) Anyone in the organization"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Auto shut off on iron is an example of a Poka-yoke mechanism. It is a great concept because we don’t need any operator to perform the action. It is also a safety enhancing feature as an iron in switched on position is injurious.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 343,
        "Question": "The use of electrical sensors to activate warning signals is an example of ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Poka-yoke mechanism",
            "b) Use of electronics",
            "c) Use of electrical devices",
            "d) Inform the police"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A car won’t start unless transmission is in neutral/park position. This is an example of poka-yoke mechanism. It is also a safety enhancing feature as it will prevent the occurrence of accidents.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 344,
        "Question": "Poka-yoke is a strategy for implementing the policy of _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Zero defects",
            "b) Four defects",
            "c) Seven defects",
            "d) Eight defects"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Anyone in the organization can develop a poka-yoke device. All it needs is just a little empowerment of employees. This is the beauty of this method.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 345,
        "Question": "________ and _______ are two major types of inspection for detecting errors.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sampling inspection, 100% inspection",
            "b) Sampling inspection, 99% inspection",
            "c) Sampling inspection, 98% inspection",
            "d) Sampling inspection, 97% inspection"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Poka-yoke is also known as mistake-proofing. The use of electrical sensors to activate warning signals is an example of poka-yoke mechanism.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 346,
        "Question": "Just-in-time is a strategy for implementing the policy of ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Zero defects",
            "b) Four defects",
            "c) Seven defects",
            "d) Eight defects"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Poka-yoke is a strategy for implementing the policy of zero defects. Dr. Shigeo Shingo formalized the concept of Poka-yoke. It is considered as a quality improvement mechanism.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 347,
        "Question": "The use of sensors on roller coaster tracks is an example of ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Poka-yoke mechanism",
            "b) Use of electronics",
            "c) Use of electrical devices",
            "d) Inform the police"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Sampling inspection and 100% inspection are two major types of inspection for detecting errors. In sampling inspection, a few products are examined for defects. In 100% inspection, even a single defect is not tolerated.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 348,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an example of use of poka-yoke in business processes?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Use of sensors in a car",
            "b) Checklists",
            "c) Color coding on products",
            "d) Color coding in the work area"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Just-in-time is a strategy for implementing the policy of zero effects. It is the principle of making what is needed, when it is needed in the amount needed.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 349,
        "Question": "The quality of the product is substantially affected by _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Supplier quality",
            "b) Supplier fund",
            "c) Supplier money",
            "d) Supplier name"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In modern days, high quality and zero-defect products are greatly desired. Hence, suppliers are treated as partners in the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 350,
        "Question": "Which of the following should not be included in a non-adversarial contract between customer and supplier?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality",
            "b) Quantity",
            "c) Delivery method",
            "d) Threat to quit"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Continuous quality improvement cannot be translated into reality without treating suppliers as partners. A commitment to continuous quality improvement needs the support of the suppliers.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 351,
        "Question": "Who gave the ten principles for customer/supplier relations?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ishikawa",
            "b) Deming",
            "c) Crosby",
            "d) Taguchi"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In modern days, supplier quality is very important as defects are desired to be resolved in the initial stages of production. So, a good supplier will supply good raw materials or good intermediate materials.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 352,
        "Question": "Both _____ and _____ are fully responsible for the control of quality.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Organization, supplier",
            "b) Organization, ambassador",
            "c) Supplier, ambassador",
            "d) Ambassador, organization founder"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Quality, quantity, and delivery method should be included in a non-adversarial contract between customer and supplier. The threat should never be a part of the relationship between customer and supplier.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 353,
        "Question": "Which of the following business activities must be performed by customers and suppliers so that a friendly and satisfactory relationship is maintained between them?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Procurement only",
            "b) Production and inventory planning only",
            "c) Clerical work and systems only",
            "d) Procurement, production and inventory planning, clerical works and systems"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Ishikawa gave the ten principles for customer/supplier relations. In modern days, high quality and zero-defect products are greatly desired. Hence, suppliers are treated as partners in the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 354,
        "Question": "Which of the following concept can be used for continually exchanging information between suppliers and customers in order to improve the product or service quality?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Multifunctional teams",
            "b) Product ambassador",
            "c) Service ambassador",
            "d) There is no such concept"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Both organization and supplier are fully responsible for the control of quality. A non-adversarial contract between supplier and organization is essential for delivering high quality and zero-defect products.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 355,
        "Question": "_______ is continuing relationship between a buying firm and supplying firm.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Supplier partnering",
            "b) Supplier characteristics",
            "c) Supplier",
            "d) Supplier traits"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Supplier partnering is continuing relationship between a buying firm and supplying firm. Suppliers play a crucial role in setting up quality development. A buyer and a supplier need to have a good relationship for sustained development.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 356,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a part of supplier buyer relationship?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Commitment over an extended period",
            "b) Exchange of information",
            "c) Acknowledgement of the risk and rewards of the relationship",
            "d) How to earn more profit by deception"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Commitment over an extended period, exchange of information, and acknowledgement of the risk and rewards of the relationship are the key traits of supplier buyer relationship. Supplier buyer relationship is crucial for organizational progress.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 357,
        "Question": "The Japanese partnering concept is _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Keiretsu",
            "b) Seiri",
            "c) Seiton",
            "d) Seiketsu"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The relationship between supplier and buyer should have trust and dedication to common goals and objectives. Both of them should have an understanding of each party’s expectations and values.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 358,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of supplier buyer relationship?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Improved quality",
            "b) Reduced cost",
            "c) Increased productivity",
            "d) Decreased efficiency"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The Japanese partnering concept is Keiretsu. The important key here is to develop long term relationships with a few key suppliers. Seiri, Seiton, and Seiketsu belong to the 5S methodology.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 359,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of supplier buyer relationship?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increased efficiency",
            "b) Increased market share",
            "c) Decreased opportunity for innovation",
            "d) Improved quality"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Continuous improvement of products or services is a consequence of good supplier buyer relationship. Continuous improvement is needed in the modern competitive environment for any organization to excel.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 360,
        "Question": "Why is long term commitment important in supplier buyer relationship?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Long term commitment will enable employees to relax initially",
            "b) Long term commitment will enable managers to relax initially",
            "c) Long term commitment is needed to plan for continuous improvement",
            "d) Long term commitment is needed to plan for intermittent improvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Improved quality, reduced cost, and increased productivity are benefits of supplier buyer relationship. Increased efficiency is also an added benefit of supplier buyer relationship.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 361,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a consequence of mutual trust between suppliers and buyers?",
        "Options": [
            "a) A ‘win-win’ situation for both the partners is created",
            "b) Resources are effectively combined",
            "c) Knowledge is effectively combined",
            "d) Knowledge is not effectively combined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Increased efficiency, increased market share, and improved quality are benefits of supplier buyer relationship. Increased opportunity for innovation is also an added benefit of supplier buyer relationship.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 362,
        "Question": "Shared vision is also known as ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Mutual strategic planning",
            "b) Strategic planning",
            "c) Mutual planning",
            "d) Planning"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Long term commitment between supplier and buyer is needed to plan for continuous improvement. During this time, trust can also be incorporated in the relationship between the buyer and supplier.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 363,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a key element in supplier customer partnering?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Long-term commitment",
            "b) Mutual trust",
            "c) Shared vision",
            "d) Isolated vision"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The direct consequence of mutual trust between suppliers and buyers is that a ‘win-win’ situation for both the partners is created, resources are effectively combined, and knowledge is effectively combined. All these lead to an effective and strong relationship between buyer and supplier.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 364,
        "Question": "What do you mean by supplier sourcing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Source of suppliers",
            "b) Details of suppliers",
            "c) Address of suppliers",
            "d) Selecting suppliers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Supplier sourcing is the process of selecting suppliers that provide the best goods or services. It is an integral part of the supply chain process.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 365,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a type of supplier sourcing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sole sourcing",
            "b) Multiple sourcing",
            "c) Single sourcing",
            "d) Twin sourcing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The three types of supplier sourcing are sole sourcing, multiple sourcing, and single sourcing. Sourcing is the process of selecting suppliers that provide the best goods or services.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 366,
        "Question": "_______ is the practice of utilizing only one supplier for the organization.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sole sourcing",
            "b) Multiple sourcing",
            "c) Single sourcing",
            "d) Twin sourcing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Sole sourcing is the practice of utilizing only one supplier for the organization. The organization is forced to use only one supplier.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 367,
        "Question": "What is the reason for the forced situation of sticking to only one supplier for the organization in sole sourcing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Patents",
            "b) Raw material location",
            "c) Only one organization producing the item",
            "d) Two organizations producing the item"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Patents, raw material location, and only one organization producing the item are the reasons for the forced situation of sticking to only one supplier for the organization in sole sourcing. The other types of supplier sourcing are multiple sourcing and single sourcing.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 368,
        "Question": "________ is the practice of utilizing two or more suppliers for an item.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sole sourcing",
            "b) Multiple sourcing",
            "c) Single sourcing",
            "d) Twin sourcing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Multiple sourcing is the practice of using two or more suppliers for an item. The other types of sourcing are solo sourcing and single sourcing.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 369,
        "Question": "What is the idea behind multiple sourcing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Better quality",
            "b) Higher costs",
            "c) Better service",
            "d) Lower costs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Better quality, better service, and lower costs are the ideas behind multiple sourcing. The other types of sourcing are solo sourcing and single sourcing.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 370,
        "Question": "_______ is the practice of utilizing only one supplier for an item when several sources are available.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sole sourcing",
            "b) Multiple sourcing",
            "c) Single sourcing",
            "d) Twin sourcing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Single sourcing is the practice of utilizing only one supplier for an item when several sources are available. The other types of sourcing are solo sourcing and multiple sourcing.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 371,
        "Question": "________ leads to the outcome of long-term partnering relationship.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sole sourcing",
            "b) Multiple sourcing",
            "c) Single sourcing",
            "d) Twin sourcing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Single sourcing is the practice of utilizing only one supplier for an item when several sources are available. This act imposes trust on the supplier and the supplier in return identifies the importance of it.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 372,
        "Question": "Two suppliers A and B deliver the same raw materials for production company Z. The price offered by supplier A is less compared to the price offered by supplier B. Which supplier should the company choose?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Supplier A",
            "b) Supplier B",
            "c) Supplier A & Supplier B",
            "d) Depends on other factors like quality"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Two suppliers A and B cannot be solely compared on the basis of price. If quality of raw material supplied by supplier A is poor, then the company may even choose supplier B.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 373,
        "Question": "Two suppliers A and B deliver the same raw materials for production company Z. The price offered by supplier A is less compared to the price offered by supplier B. The quality of both the raw materials is the same. Which supplier should the company choose considering other factors remaining the same for both of them?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Supplier A",
            "b) Supplier B",
            "c) Supplier A & Supplier B",
            "d) None of them"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: When both the suppliers offer raw materials of the same quality, the production company will choose supplier A as it is offering less price. This, though, is valid only when other factors are considered the same for both the suppliers.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 374,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the primary factor on which the supplier is selected by an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cost",
            "b) Quality",
            "c) Delivery reliability",
            "d) Language barrier"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Cost, quality, and delivery are the important primary factors on which the supplier is selected by an organization. Language barrier is not a primary factor but can influence the choice of supplier selection.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 375,
        "Question": "________ suggested the ten conditions for selection and evaluation of suppliers.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ishikawa",
            "b) Taguchi",
            "c) Juran",
            "d) Deming"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Cost, quality, and delivery are the important primary factors on which the supplier is selected by an organization. Additionally, supplier selection criteria include factors such as management compatibility, goal congruence, and strategic decision of the supplier firm.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 376,
        "Question": "The supplier selection and evaluation stage in which the supplier list is drawn up on the basis of raw information from catalogues, advertisements, and brochures is known as ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Survey stage",
            "b) Enquiry stage",
            "c) Negotiation and selection stage",
            "d) Experience stage"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Survey stage, enquiry stage, negotiation and selection stage, and experience stage are the four stages in supplier selection and evaluation. Identifying the right supplier is important for an organization’s progress.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 377,
        "Question": "In which of the following stages of supplier selection and evaluation, vendor’s present customers are enquired about the performance and promptness in delivery of the vendor?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Survey stage",
            "b) Enquiry stage",
            "c) Negotiation and selection stage",
            "d) Experience stage"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Ishikawa suggested the ten conditions for selection and evaluation of suppliers. Proper supplier selection and evaluation is vital for an organization’s progress.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 378,
        "Question": "In which of the following stage in supplier selection and evaluation, standard enquiry forms are sent to the vendors, asking them to present their detailed information?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Survey stage",
            "b) Enquiry stage",
            "c) Negotiation and selection stage",
            "d) Experience stage"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: During enquiry stage, standard enquiry forms are sent to the vendors, asking them to present their detailed information. This is done before finalizing the vendor.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 379,
        "Question": "In ________detailed analysis of the vendor is made after raw information is acquired from the survey stage.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Survey stage",
            "b) Enquiry stage",
            "c) Negotiation and selection stage",
            "d) Experience stage"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: During enquiry stage, detailed analysis of the vendor is made after raw information is acquired from the survey stage. Standard enquiry forms are sent to the vendors. At the same time the vendor’s present customers are asked about the vendor’s performance and promptness in delivery.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 380,
        "Question": "Which of the following factors are considered during direct negotiations with the vendors in the negotiation and selection stage of supplier selection and evaluation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Payment terms only",
            "b) Quality control procedures only",
            "c) Supply procedures only",
            "d) Payment terms, quality control procedures, and supply procedures"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Payment terms, quality control procedures, and supply procedures are the important factors that are considered during direct negotiations with the vendors in the negotiation and selection stage of supplier selection and evaluation. Consequently, a final list of approved vendors is drawn up.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 381,
        "Question": "In which stage of supplier selection and criteria, performance of the supplier is evaluated based on quality and promptness in delivery?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Survey stage",
            "b) Enquiry stage",
            "c) Negotiation and selection stage",
            "d) Experience stage"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: During experience stage, performance of the supplier is evaluated based on quality and promptness in delivery. The other stages of supplier selection and criteria are survey stage, enquiry stage, and negotiation and selection stage.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 382,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a part of the history card?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Date of supply of materials",
            "b) Inspection",
            "c) Procedure adopted",
            "d) No.of fans in vendor’s office"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Frequent rejections upset the production schedule. Such vendors should be dropped from the list of available vendors because it may incur to heavy losses in the buyer’s company.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 383,
        "Question": "Which of the following is incorrect with respect to Ishikawa’s ten conditions for selection and evaluation of suppliers?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The supplier should have a stable management system",
            "b) The supplier should not breach the corporate secrets",
            "c) The supplier should not have a track record of customer satisfaction and organization credibility",
            "d) The supplier should have an effective quality system"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Late deliveries may cause stoppages in production. Due to this large inventories have to be kept in stock. Both these cases are not desirable and therefore such vendors’ performance must be questioned.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 384,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of supplier certification process?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Elimination of receiving inspection",
            "b) Creation of a customer-supplier partnership",
            "c) Reduces number of suppliers",
            "d) Increases number of suppliers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Supplier selection process is followed by supplier certification process. Supplier certification process assures that the supplier’s product is produced, packaged, and shipped in a controlled manner.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 385,
        "Question": "According to the supplier certification criteria, the customer and the supplier shall agree upon specifications that are __________, ________, and ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Mutually developed, justifiable, not ambiguous",
            "b) Mutually developed, justifiable, ambiguous",
            "c) Personally developed, justifiable, not ambiguous",
            "d) Personally developed, justifiable, ambiguous"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Supplier certification process starts only after the supplier begins shipment of the product to the organization. Supplier certification process assures that the supplier’s product is produced, packaged, and shipped in a controlled manner.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 386,
        "Question": "According to the supplier certification criteria, for a significant period the supplier should have ______ product-related lot rejection.",
        "Options": [
            "a) No",
            "b) Five",
            "c) Six",
            "d) More"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Elimination of receiving inspection, creation of a customer-supplier partnership, and reducing the number of suppliers are the benefits of supplier certification process. Supplier certification reduces overhead costs by reducing the number of suppliers.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 387,
        "Question": "According to the supplier certification criteria, the supplier _______ timely inspection and test data for documentation.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Should provide",
            "b) Should not provide",
            "c) May provide",
            "d) Need not provide"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to the supplier certification criteria, the customer and the supplier shall agree upon specifications that are mutually developed, justifiable, and not ambiguous. The supplier certification process has been given by the supplier technical committee of ASQ.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 388,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a factor involved in supplier rating?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality",
            "b) Price",
            "c) Performance",
            "d) Performance Incapability"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to the supplier certification criteria, for a significant period the supplier should have no product-related lot rejection. Rejected materials affect the production process hence should be at the minimum level.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 389,
        "Question": "Supplier rating system is also known as _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Scorecard system",
            "b) Score system",
            "c) Card system",
            "d) Score and Card system"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to the supplier certification criteria, the supplier should provide timely inspection and test data for documentation. Supplier certification process assures that the supplier’s product is produced, packaged, and shipped in a controlled manner.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 390,
        "Question": "Supplier rating provides overall rating of _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Supplier performance",
            "b) Supplier contact details",
            "c) Number of products delivered",
            "d) Number of products rejected"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Quality, price, and performance are factors involved in supplier rating. In addition to all these factors, performance capability also acts as a factor involved in supplier rating.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 391,
        "Question": "Maintaining and improving the growth of the customer-supplier relationship is known as _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Relationship Development",
            "b) Customer Development",
            "c) Supplier Development",
            "d) Customer Satisfaction"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Maintaining and improving the growth of the customer-supplier relationship is known as relationship development. Relationship development is crucial for proper establishment of customer-supplier relationships.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 392,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a phase of quality inspection?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 100% inspection",
            "b) Sampling inspection",
            "c) 99% inspection",
            "d) Inspection audit"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: 100% inspection, sampling inspection, and inspection audit are the different phases of quality inspection. In addition to this, identity check is the fourth phase of quality inspection.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 393,
        "Question": "In 100% inspection phase, _______ are inspected.",
        "Options": [
            "a) All the items",
            "b) Some of the items",
            "c) Most of the items",
            "d) 99% of the items"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In 100% inspection phase, all the items that are delivered by the supplier to the customer is inspected. 100% inspection is one of the four phases of quality inspection.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 394,
        "Question": "At the audit phase, the customer has complete confidence in the supplier and initiates _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) 100% inspection",
            "b) Sampling inspection",
            "c) Inspection audit",
            "d) Identity checks"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Successful inspection during 100% inspection phase may make the customer switch to sampling inspection during the next round of delivery from the supplier. This is because in 100% inspection all the delivered materials are inspected.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 395,
        "Question": "Proper training in quality, team work, and other management aspects is necessary for _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customers",
            "b) Suppliers",
            "c) Customers and suppliers",
            "d) It is not necessary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Success in sampling inspection may make the customer switch to auditing. Auditing here refers to auditing the supplier’s performance. Sampling inspection and inspection through auditing are the different phases of the quality inspection.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 396,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a form of invitation given to the supplier by the customer?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Seminars",
            "b) Workshops",
            "c) Courses",
            "d) Ledger"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: At the audit phase, the customer has complete confidence in the supplier and initiates identity checks. This reduces the time taken for the conventional inspection process and production runs continuously without any interruptions.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 397,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a way of developing partnering relationship between customer and supplier?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Inspection",
            "b) Training",
            "c) Team Approach",
            "d) Recognition only"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Proper training in quality, team work, and other management aspects is necessary for both customers and suppliers. This is because they are interdependent and miscommunications can hinder progress. Hence, proper knowledge is vital for both of them.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 398,
        "Question": "Which of the following is incorrect with respect to strengthening customer-supplier relationship?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reward and recognition concept",
            "b) Team meetings should be held at both partners’ workplace",
            "c) Both of them should be trained in quality, team work, and other management concepts",
            "d) Reward and recognition should be abolished"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  Seminars, workshops, courses and exhibition are different ways in which customers invite the suppliers. This forms a part of the training process. It also is a way to establish mutual trust between both of them.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 399,
        "Question": "Quality circle is also known as _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality Control Circle",
            "b) Quality Rectangle",
            "c) Quality Square",
            "d) Quality Ellipse"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Quality circle is also known as Quality Control Circle. It is a small voluntary group of employees and their supervisors comprising of around 6 to 10 members.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 400,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an alternative name of quality circle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Human resources circle",
            "b) Productivity circle",
            "c) Excellence circle",
            "d) Loss circle"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Quality circle is a participative management system. In quality circle, workers make suggestions and improvements for the betterment of the company.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 401,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an attribute of Quality Circle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It is a form of participation management",
            "b) It is a human resource development technique",
            "c) It is a problem solving technique",
            "d) It is not a human resource development technique"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Human resources circle, productivity circle, and excellence circle are the other alternative names of quality circle. Quality circles are also known by the names Small groups and Action circles.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 402,
        "Question": "Quality circle _______ job involvement.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Neglects",
            "b) Demotes",
            "c) Promotes",
            "d) Accuses"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Quality circle identifies analyses and solves quality, cost reduction and any other problem in their work area. They meet regularly and discuss organizational methods that will help in improving the performance of their work life.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 403,
        "Question": "Quality circles _______ problem solving capability.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Create",
            "b) Delete",
            "c) Stop",
            "d) Eradicates"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The following are the attributes of Quality Circle. It is a form of participation management, it is a human resource development technique, and it is a problem solving technique.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 404,
        "Question": "Quality circle develops _______ awareness for safety.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Greater",
            "b) Lesser",
            "c) No",
            "d) Diminishing"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Quality circle promotes job involvement. It is a small voluntary group of employees and their supervisors comprising of around 6 to 10 members. The employees are from the same work area or doing similar work.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 405,
        "Question": "An objective of quality circle team is to ______ errors and _______ quality.",
        "Options": [
            "a) reduce, enhance",
            "b) increase, enhance",
            "c) reduce, demean",
            "d) increase, demean"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: An objective of quality circle team is to improve employee’s morale by closer identity of employee objectives with the organization’s objectives. This is because upliftment of employee’s morale is important and instills greater employee participation.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 406,
        "Question": "An objective of quality circle team is to _______ cost reduction.",
        "Options": [
            "a) promote",
            "b) stop",
            "c) prevent",
            "d) cease"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: An objective of quality circle team is to reduce errors and enhance quality. Reduction in errors improves system efficiency and enhancement in quality focuses on continuous improvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 407,
        "Question": "An objective of quality circle team is to _______ machines and equipment downtime.",
        "Options": [
            "a) reduce",
            "b) increase",
            "c) promote",
            "d) augment"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: An objective of quality circle team is to promote cost reduction. Improving the system performance at minimum cost and no compromise in quality is the ultimate aim of any continuously improving organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 408,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a tool used by the quality circle team?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Brainstorming",
            "b) Pareto analysis",
            "c) Histograms",
            "d) No. of employees in an organization"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: An objective of quality circle team is to reduce machines and equipment downtime. Downtime refers to the time when a machine or equipment is not available for use. This halts productivity. Reducing downtime is therefore an utmost focus of quality circle.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 409,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the optimum number of employees in a quality circle team?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 600-1000",
            "b) 6000-10000",
            "c) 6-10",
            "d) 60-100"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Brainstorming, pareto analysis and histograms are some of the tools used by the quality circle team. These tools are used to identify the various problems that the organization faces from time to time.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 410,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a factor looked at by the quality circle team when it focuses on personal well-being of an employee?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Working conditions",
            "b) Safety",
            "c) Work relations",
            "d) Productivity related problem"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Cause-effect diagram is one of the tools used by the quality circle team. The other tools used by the quality circle team are brainstorming, pareto analysis, and histograms.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 411,
        "Question": "An objective of quality circle team is to build an attitude of ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Problem creation",
            "b) Problem prevention",
            "c) Problem augmentation",
            "d) Problem development"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The optimum number of employees in a quality circle team is in between 6-10. The team should meet frequently and update itself with the existing performance level of the organization and find out the scope for improvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 412,
        "Question": "Which of the following elements is not part of the structure of quality circle in an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Top management",
            "b) Steering committee",
            "c) Non-members",
            "d) Student"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Top management, steering committee, leader, non-members, coordinator, facilitator, and members are the elements part of the structure of the quality circle in an organization. All these elements are crucial for the efficient functioning of the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 413,
        "Question": "Who amongst the following is responsible for arrangement of steering committee meeting?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Top management",
            "b) Coordinator",
            "c) Student",
            "d) Teacher"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The top-level management in an organization influences the successful implementation of the concept of the quality circle. They are not directly connected with the formal structure of the quality circle.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 414,
        "Question": "Who amongst the following is responsible for organizing training programs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Top management",
            "b) Coordinator",
            "c) Student",
            "d) Teacher"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Coordinator is responsible for arrangement of steering committee meeting. Generally, a senior manager within the organization acts as a coordinator.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 415,
        "Question": "Who amongst the following is responsible for conveying quality policy to its employees and encourage them to form quality circles?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Top management",
            "b) Coordinator",
            "c) Student",
            "d) Teacher"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Coordinator is responsible for organizing training programs. He is also responsible for proper documentation of various activities.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 416,
        "Question": "_______ should be lenient enough to financially support quality circle projects.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Top management",
            "b) Coordinator",
            "c) Student",
            "d) Teacher"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Top management is responsible for conveying quality policy to its employees and encourages them to form quality circles. They are not directly a part of the formal quality circle structure.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 417,
        "Question": "Who amongst the following is a senior person in a specific area whose task is to act as a mentor for effective operation of quality circles?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Top management",
            "b) Coordinator",
            "c) Facilitator",
            "d) Steering Committee"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Top management should be lenient enough to financially support quality circle projects. They are not directly a part of the formal quality circle structure.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 418,
        "Question": "_____ is a group of members working under the chairmanship of the CEO with functional heads as members.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Top management",
            "b) Coordinator",
            "c) Facilitator",
            "d) Steering Committee"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Facilitator is a senior person in a specific area whose task is to act as a mentor for effective operation of quality circles. She/he also elucidates the functioning of quality circles in his/her area in steering committee meetings.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 419,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the role of quality circle members?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Attend all possible meetings",
            "b) Participate actively in the group process",
            "c) Contribute to find solutions to problems",
            "d) Conduct meeting regularly"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: To attend all possible meetings, to participate actively in the group process, and to contribute to find solutions to problems are some of the important roles of quality circle members. A quality circle leader conducts meeting regularly.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 420,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the role of the facilitator?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Work closely with steering committee",
            "b) Maintain circle records",
            "c) Evaluates circle activities",
            "d) Moderate in meetings"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A quality circle leader moderates in meeting. He/she also has the role of conducting meeting regularly to review organization performance and focus on achieving continuous improvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 421,
        "Question": "Who amongst the following plays the role of ensuring adequate training opportunities to the facilitator(s), leaders, and members?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Steering committee",
            "b) Members",
            "c) Coordinator",
            "d) Facilitator"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A quality circle leader is responsible for keeping the cohesiveness in the quality circle group. He/she is responsible for taking care of the task behavior of the group, and team maintenance.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 422,
        "Question": "Who amongst the following plays the role of recognizing the contributions of the facilitator(s), leaders, and members?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Steering committee",
            "b) Members",
            "c) Coordinator",
            "d) Facilitator"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: To work closely with steering committee, to maintain circle records, and to evaluate circle activities are the roles of the facilitator. The role of a quality circle leader is to moderate in meetings.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 423,
        "Question": "Who amongst the following prepares the budget for the functioning of quality circle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Steering committee",
            "b) Members",
            "c) Coordinator",
            "d) Facilitator"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Steering committee plays the role of ensuring adequate training opportunities to the facilitator(s), leaders, and members. It takes important decisions at the organizational level.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 424,
        "Question": "Who amongst the following helps in solving problems encountered in the implementation of quality circle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Steering committee",
            "b) Members",
            "c) Coordinator",
            "d) Facilitator"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Steering committee plays the role of recognizing the contributions of the facilitator(s), leaders, and members. It takes important decisions at the organizational level.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 425,
        "Question": "In which step of quality circle operation cycle do we identify a number of problems?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Problem identification",
            "b) Problem selection",
            "c) Problem analysis",
            "d) Present solution to management"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Problem identification is the first step of quality circle operation cycle. In this step we identify a number of problems that are bothering the proper functioning of the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 426,
        "Question": "In which step of quality circle operation cycle do we prioritize and decide the problem to be dealt with first?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Problem identification",
            "b) Problem selection",
            "c) Problem analysis",
            "d) Present solution to management"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Problem selection is the second step of quality circle operation cycle. In this step we prioritize and decide the problem to be dealt with first.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 427,
        "Question": "In which step of quality circle operation cycle do we clarify and analyze the problem?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Problem identification",
            "b) Problem selection",
            "c) Problem analysis",
            "d) Present solution to management"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Problem analysis is the third step of quality circle operation cycle. In this step problems are clarified and analyzed.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 428,
        "Question": "In which step of quality circle operation cycle do we identify and evaluate causes and generate alternative solutions to the problem?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Problem identification",
            "b) Problem selection",
            "c) Problem analysis",
            "d) Generate alternative solutions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘Generate alternative solutions’ is the fourth step of quality circle operation cycle. In this step we identify and evaluate causes and generate alternative solutions to the problem.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 429,
        "Question": "In which step of quality circle operation do we compare the alternative solutions to the problem on the basis of return on investment?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Problem identification",
            "b) Problem selection",
            "c) Problem analysis",
            "d) Select the most appropriate solution"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘Select the most appropriate solution’ is the fifth step of quality circle operation cycle. In this step we compare the alternative solutions to the problem on the basis of return on investment.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 430,
        "Question": "In which step of the quality circle operation cycle does the management test the final solution before full scale implementation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Problem identification",
            "b) Problem selection",
            "c) Problem analysis",
            "d) Implementation of solution"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The step to prepare a plan of action is the sixth step in the quality circle operation cycle. In this step, a plan of action is prepared for the best solution selected out of the given alternatives for the given problem.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 431,
        "Question": "Participation fades away when there is lack of support from ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Top management",
            "b) Bottom management",
            "c) Intermediate management",
            "d) Customers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Participation is not always voluntary in all cases in quality circle. Ideally, participation should be voluntary in a quality circle.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 432,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a tangible gain of quality circle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Better quality",
            "b) Productivity improvement",
            "c) Higher safety",
            "d) Enriched quality of work life"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There is no involvement of trade unions in quality circles. Quality circle is also known as Quality Control Circle. It is a small voluntary group of employees and their supervisors comprising of around 6 to 10 members.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 433,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a tangible gain of quality circle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Greater cost effectiveness",
            "b) Better housekeeping",
            "c) Increased profitability",
            "d) Attitudinal changes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The top management drives the morale of the employees. If there is a lack of support from the top management, the participation in quality circle starts to fade away.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 434,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a tangible gain of quality circle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Waste reduction",
            "b) Reduced absenteeism",
            "c) Reduced grievances",
            "d) Harmony, mutual trust"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Better quality, productivity improvement, and higher safety are the tangible gains of quality circle. Enriched quality of work life is an intangible gain of quality circle.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 435,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an intangible gain of quality circle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Effective team working",
            "b) Better human relations",
            "c) Participative culture",
            "d) Waste reduction"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Greater cost effectiveness, better housekeeping, and increased profitability are the tangible gains of quality circle. Attitudinal changes are an intangible gain of quality circle.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 436,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an intangible gain of quality circle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Human resource development",
            "b) Promotion of job knowledge",
            "c) Greater sense of belonging",
            "d) Greater cost effectiveness"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Waste reduction, reduced absenteeism, and reduced grievances are the tangible gains of quality circle. Harmony and mutual trust are intangible gains of quality circle.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 437,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of quality circles’ effects on individuals’ characteristics?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It enables the individual to improve personal capabilities",
            "b) It increases the individuals’ self-respect",
            "c) It helps workers change certain personality characteristics",
            "d) It increases the conflict stemming from the working environment"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  Effective team working, Better human relations, and Participative culture are the intangible gains of quality circle. Waste reduction is a tangible gain of quality circle.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 438,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of quality circles’ effects on individuals’ relation with others?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It increases the respect of the supervisor for the workers",
            "b) It increases workers’ understanding of the difficulties faced by the supervisors",
            "c) It increases management’s respect for workers",
            "d) It change some workers’ negative attitudes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation:  Human resource development, Promotion of job knowledge, and a Greater sense of belonging are the intangible gains of quality circle. Greater cost effectiveness is a tangible gain of quality circle.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 439,
        "Question": "Process deployment flow is another term for ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Flow chart",
            "b) Matrices",
            "c) Determinants",
            "d) Arrows"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The given figure represents the Terminator symbol used during the construction of a flow chart. The other symbols are Action, Decision, Arrows, and Link.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 440,
        "Question": "Tally sheet is another term for _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Flow chart",
            "b) Matrices",
            "c) Determinants",
            "d) Checksheets"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The given figure represents the Action symbol used during the construction of a flow chart. The other symbols are Terminator, Decision, Arrows, and Link.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 441,
        "Question": "The type of checksheet used to collect information on process variability is called ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process distribution check sheet",
            "b) Defective item check sheet",
            "c) Defect location check sheet",
            "d) Defect factor check sheet"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The given figure represents the Decision symbol used during the construction of a flow chart. The other symbols are Terminator, Action, Arrows, and Link.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 442,
        "Question": "The type of check sheet which specifies the variety of defects with their frequency of occurrence is called _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process distribution check sheet",
            "b) Defective item check sheet",
            "c) Defect location check sheet",
            "d) Defect factor check sheet"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The given figure represents the Arrows symbol used during the construction of a flow chart. It shows the direction of flow of the process. The other symbols are Terminator, Action, Decisions, and Link.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 443,
        "Question": "The type of check sheet which identifies where defects occur in a product is called _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process distribution check sheet",
            "b) Defective item check sheet",
            "c) Defect location check sheet",
            "d) Defect factor check sheet"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The given figure represents the Link symbol used during the construction of a flow chart. It shows the direction of flow of the process. The other symbols are Terminator, Action, Decisions, and Arrows.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 444,
        "Question": "The type of check sheet used to monitor the input parameters that can affect the occurrence of defects in a process is called _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process distribution check sheet",
            "b) Defective item check sheet",
            "c) Defect location check sheet",
            "d) Defect factor check sheet"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Process deployment flow is another term for flow chart. It is also called as flow diagram. It is a sequential representation of processes involved in an organization by the use of standard symbols.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 445,
        "Question": "The frequency distribution of a numerical data can be graphically represented by a ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Histogram",
            "b) Telegram",
            "c) Monogram",
            "d) Anagram"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The histogram is a graphical representation of the frequency distribution of a numerical data. It is a bar chart/diagram. The data is represented in the form of rectangles of varying heights and equal widths.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 446,
        "Question": "Which of the following type of histogram represents a normal distribution?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Bell-shaped",
            "b) Comb",
            "c) Skewed",
            "d) Plateau"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Bell-shaped histogram represents a normal distribution. It has a symmetrical shape with a peak in the middle.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 447,
        "Question": "Pareto diagram is named after ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Vilfredo Pareto",
            "b) William Deming",
            "c) Joseph Juran",
            "d) Philip Crosby"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Pareto diagram is named after Vilfredo Pareto. He was an Italian economist. It is used to find out the ‘vital few’ from the ‘trivial many’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 448,
        "Question": "Which of the following tool can be used as a risk assessment technique from activity level to system level?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Pareto diagram",
            "b) Demand forecasting",
            "c) Benchmarking",
            "d) Job Scheduling"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Pareto diagram tool can be used as a risk assessment technique from activity level to system level. It is used when one has to prioritize problems based on relative importance.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 449,
        "Question": "Pareto analysis is also known by _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) 80/20 rule",
            "b) Demand forecasting",
            "c) Benchmarking",
            "d) Job Scheduling"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Pareto analysis is also known by 80/20 rule. It means by focusing on 20% work we can get 80% benefit. Pareto diagram is named after Vilfredo Pareto.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 450,
        "Question": "Which of the following type of histogram represents two normal distributions with two peaks in the middle?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Double-peaked",
            "b) Bell-shaped",
            "c) Plateau",
            "d) Edged peak"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Double-peaked histogram represents two normal distributions with two peaks in the middle. It indicates that more than one distribution at work.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 451,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a disadvantage of using histogram?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Exact values cannot be read as data is divided in different categories",
            "b) Can be used only with continuous data",
            "c) Two data sets are difficult to compare",
            "d) Relative frequency of occurrences can be found out"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The following are the disadvantages of using histogram: Exact values cannot be read as data is divided in different categories, it can be used only with continuous data, and two data sets are difficult to compare. Relative frequency of occurrences can be found out which is considered to be an advantage of using histogram.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 452,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a type of histogram?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Isolated peak",
            "b) Comb",
            "c) Truncated",
            "d) Pie Chart"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Isolated peak, comb, and truncated are different types of histogram. Pie Chart is another statistical tool like histogram to represent data.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 453,
        "Question": "Which of the following type of histogram looks like a normal distribution whose some part has been removed leading to an asymmetrical shape?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Isolated peak",
            "b) Comb",
            "c) Truncated",
            "d) Pie Chart"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Truncated histogram looks like a normal distribution whose some part has been removed. It leads to the truncated histogram having an asymmetrical shape.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 454,
        "Question": "Which of the following type of histogram looks like a normal distribution with a large peak at one end?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Isolated peak",
            "b) Comb",
            "c) Edged peak",
            "d) Pie Chart"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Edged peak histogram looks like a normal distribution with a large peak at one end. It indicates errors in data recording. The histogram is a graphical representation of the frequency distribution of a numerical data.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 455,
        "Question": "Cause and effect diagram is also known as _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Fishbone diagram",
            "b) Fish diagram",
            "c) Cause diagram",
            "d) Effect diagram"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Cause and effect diagram is also known as the fishbone diagram. It is due to the structural shape of the diagram. It was developed by Ishikawa in 1943.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 456,
        "Question": "Cause and effect diagram is also known as _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Fishbone diagram",
            "b) Ishikawa diagram",
            "c) Both Ishikawa diagram and Fishbone diagram",
            "d) Cause diagram only"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Cause and effect diagram is also known as both Ishikawa diagram and Fishbone diagram. Ishikawa diagram is the man who developed it and fishbone diagram due to its appearance.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 457,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a cause of poor solder joints after studying the cause and effect diagram?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Inadequate training",
            "b) Solder contamination",
            "c) Temperature of solder bit",
            "d) Customer complaint"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Cause and effect diagram can be used in research, manufacturing, marketing, office operations, and services. It is used to find the root cause of a problem after thorough brainstorming.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 458,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a cause of poor marks of class 12 students in board exams after studying the cause and effect diagram?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Improper teaching",
            "b) Lack of seriousness of students due to distractions",
            "c) Too much focus on competitive exams",
            "d) Extremely hot climate in the area"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Cause and effect diagram can be used to educate and train personnel in decision-making and corrective-action activities. It analyses all the possible causes of the existing problems. Hence, the problems are rectified.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 459,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a cause of rising health problems in young children in an area after studying the cause and effect diagram?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Poor water quality",
            "b) Increase in contaminant level",
            "c) Harmful substances released by industries",
            "d) Elders scolding the children"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Inadequate training, solder contamination, and temperature of solder bit are the potential causes of a poor solder joint. Poor solder joints can result in customer dissatisfaction resulting in a customer complaint.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 460,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a cause of engineering students switching to pure management career (according to the views of engineering students)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Better salary",
            "b) Their parents forced them",
            "c) Interest was not developed in the core subjects during their course",
            "d) Pure management is less laborious"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Improper teaching, lack of seriousness of students due to distractions, and too much focus on competitive exams are the potential causes of poor marks of class 12 students in board exams. Hot climate can affect the health of the students but is not the reason for poor performance of class 12 students.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 461,
        "Question": "Scatter diagram is graphical component of ____________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Regression analysis",
            "b) Demand",
            "c) Supply",
            "d) Profit"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Scatter diagram is graphical component of regression analysis. It shows the relationship between dependent and independent variable.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 462,
        "Question": "A scatter diagram represents the relationship between _________ and ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cause, effects",
            "b) Cause, problem",
            "c) Effects, output",
            "d) Production, productivity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A scatter diagram represents the relationship between cause and effects. Cause is independent variable and Effects is the dependent variable.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 463,
        "Question": "________ is one of the most widely used tools in the statistical process control.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Control chart",
            "b) Parabola",
            "c) Hyperbola",
            "d) Ellipse"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Control chart is one of the most widely used tools in statistical process control. It was invented by Walter A. Shewhart.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 464,
        "Question": "A histogram gives _____ nature of process variability.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Static",
            "b) Dynamic",
            "c) Negative",
            "d) Positive"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Control chart for characteristics is used for quantifiable data. It can be used for quantifiable data such as number of defects, typing errors in a report etc.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 465,
        "Question": "The horizontal lines above and below the centre line in control chart are known as _________ and ________ respectively.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Upper control limit, lower control limit",
            "b) Lower control limit, upper control limit",
            "c) Upper control limit, medium control limit",
            "d) Lower control limit, medium control limit"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Control chart for variables is used for measurable data. It can be used for measurable data such as time, length, temperature, weight, pressure etc.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 466,
        "Question": "If a sample drawn from the process lies inside the upper control limit and lower control limit, it means the ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process is in control",
            "b) Process is out of control",
            "c) Process is partially in control",
            "d) Process is partially out of control"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A histogram gives static picture of process variability. Control chart shows the dynamic performance of the process.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 467,
        "Question": "If a sample drawn from the process lies outside the upper control limit and lower control limit, it means the __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process is in control",
            "b) Process is out of control",
            "c) Process is partially in control",
            "d) Process is partially out of control"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The horizontal lines above and below the centre line in control chart are known as upper control limit and lower control limit respectively. The middle line is known as the centre line.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 468,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a use of control chart?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To evaluate process stability",
            "b) To show source of variations",
            "c) To identify when the process will go out of control",
            "d) To decrease productivity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If a sample drawn from the process lies inside the upper control limit and lower control limit, it means the process is in control. The UCL and LCL are generally set at 3 standard deviations above and below of the sample means.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 469,
        "Question": "Which of the following is also known as KJ diagram?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Affinity diagram",
            "b) Relationship diagram",
            "c) Tree diagram",
            "d) Matrix diagram"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Affinity diagram is also known as KJ diagram. It is one of the new seven management tools. The others are relationship diagram, tree diagram, matrix diagram, matrix data analysis, decision tree, and arrow diagram.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 470,
        "Question": "Who devised the term ‘affinity diagram’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Deming",
            "b) Taguchi",
            "c) Crosby",
            "d) Jiro Kawakita"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Jiro Kawakita devised the term ‘affinity diagram’. It is also known as KJ diagram. It is one of the new seven management tools.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 471,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a use of affinity diagram?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To determine logical priorities",
            "b) To create new concepts",
            "c) To calculate mean of the numerical data",
            "d) To provide a visual representation of large amount of ideas"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: To determine logical priorities, to create new concepts, and to provide a visual representation of large amount of ideas are the uses of affinity diagram. Affinity diagram is also known as KJ diagram.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 472,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a use of relationship diagram?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To identify key problem from a list of important problems",
            "b) To identify the root causes of existing problems",
            "c) To identify key factors needed to make a decision",
            "d) To calculate the variance of the numerical data"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The relationship diagram is a tool for finding causes to a problem. The basic logic is same as cause and effect diagram. Relationship diagram is also known as interrelationship diagram.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 473,
        "Question": "The seven basic quality tools focus on the __________ aspect and the new seven management tools focus on the ______ aspect.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quantitative, numerical",
            "b) Numerical, quantitative",
            "c) Quantitative, qualitative",
            "d) Qualitative, quantitative"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Relationship diagram clarifies the relationship between cause and effect and also between the various causes. Relationship diagram is also known as interrelationship diagram.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 474,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a new seven management tool?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Affinity diagram",
            "b) Tree diagram",
            "c) Matrix diagram",
            "d) Histogram"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: To identify key problem from a list of important problems, to identify the root causes of existing problems, and to identify key factors needed to make a decision are the uses of relationship diagram. The relationship diagram is a tool for finding causes to a problem.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 475,
        "Question": "Quality table is also known as _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Relationship diagram",
            "b) Tree diagram",
            "c) Matrix diagram",
            "d) Arrow diagram"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The tree diagram is break down of a topic into its component elements, showing the logical and sequential links between these elements in a systematic manner. It outlines the complete spectrum of paths and tasks that must be carried out to achieve a goal.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 476,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a type of matrix diagram?",
        "Options": [
            "a) L shaped",
            "b) T shaped",
            "c) Roof shaped",
            "d) Ground shaped"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Quality table is also known as matrix diagram. Matrix diagram is a tool which depicts the relation between ‘factors’ in the form of a table or matrix.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 477,
        "Question": "_______ matrix diagram is used to relate two groups of items to each other (or one group to itself).",
        "Options": [
            "a) T-shaped",
            "b) L-shaped",
            "c) Y-shaped",
            "d) Roof-shaped"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Matrix diagram is the starting point in building the house of quality. It is a tool which depicts the relation between ‘factors’ in the form of a table or matrix.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 478,
        "Question": "______ matrix diagram is used to relate three groups of items; each group is related to the other two in a circular fashion.",
        "Options": [
            "a) T-shaped",
            "b) L-shaped",
            "c) Y-shaped",
            "d) Roof-shaped"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: L, T and Roof shaped are different types of matrix diagram. The other forms of matrix diagram are Y, C and X shaped.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 479,
        "Question": "_____ matrix diagram is used to relate four group of items; each group is related to two others in a circular fashion.",
        "Options": [
            "a) T-shaped",
            "b) X-shaped",
            "c) Y-shaped",
            "d) Roof-shaped"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: L-shaped matrix diagram is used to relate two groups of items to each other (or one group to itself). The number of groups present in L-shaped matrix diagram is 2.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 480,
        "Question": "_____ matrix diagram is used to relate three groups of items all together simultaneously in 3-D.",
        "Options": [
            "a) T-shaped",
            "b) X-shaped",
            "c) Y-shaped",
            "d) C-shaped"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Y-shaped matrix diagram is used to relate three groups of items; each group is related to the other two in a circular fashion. The number of groups present in Y-shaped matrix diagram is 3.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 481,
        "Question": "Which one of the following is the only new seven management tool that uses numerical data and produces numerical results?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Affinity diagram",
            "b) Tree diagram",
            "c) Matrix Data Analysis diagram",
            "d) Relationship diagram"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In Matrix Data Analysis Chart (MDAC), numerical data is used whereas in Matrix Diagram symbols are used to indicate the existence and strength of a relationship. MDAC is one of the new seven management tools.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 482,
        "Question": "In a matrix data analysis diagram, two different brands are compared. Brand 1 is having the coordinates (40,6) and Brand 2 is having the coordinates (40,-6). X-axis is the cost of the item and Y-axis is customer satisfaction. Which brand would you prefer?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Brand 2",
            "b) Brand 1",
            "c) Both are equally preferred",
            "d) Can’t be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Matrix Data Analysis diagram is the only new seven management tool that uses numerical data and produces numerical results. It is also known as MDAC. It is different from the matrix diagram where symbols are used to indicate the strength and existence of a relationship.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 483,
        "Question": "Process decision programme chart is also known as _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Affinity diagram",
            "b) Relationship diagram",
            "c) Decision tree",
            "d) Matrix diagram"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Matrix Data Analysis diagram is used in ‘Principle Component Analysis’. It is one of the new seven management tools. The other new management tools are affinity diagram, relationship diagram, tree diagram, matrix diagram, decision tree, and arrow diagram.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 484,
        "Question": "Which one of the following is not an area of application of PDPC?",
        "Options": [
            "a) New product development",
            "b) Building equipment",
            "c) Decision making involved in a new task",
            "d) Decision making where planning is not involved"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Brand 1 and Brand 2 have the same x-component i.e. 40. So, the cost of the item is equal for both the brands. But, Brand 2 has a negative y-component i.e. -6 whereas Brand 1 has a positive y-component i.e. 6. So, Brand 1 has a positive customer satisfaction and Brand 2 has a negative customer satisfaction. Therefore, Brand 1 is preferred.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 485,
        "Question": "Which among the following are best known arrow diagrams?",
        "Options": [
            "a) CPM and matrix data analysis diagram",
            "b) PERT and matrix data analysis diagram",
            "c) CPM, PERT and matrix data analysis diagram",
            "d) CPM and PERT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Process decision programme chart is also known as decision tree. It is one of the new seven management tools. The other new management tools are affinity diagram, relationship diagram, tree diagram, matrix diagram, matrix data analysis diagram, and arrow diagram.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 486,
        "Question": "CPM is the abbreviation for ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Critical Process Method",
            "b) Critical Procurement Method",
            "c) Critical Powerful Method",
            "d) Critical Path Method"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: New product development, Building equipment, and Decision making involved in a new task require meticulous planning. PDPC is used as a planning tool to outline every conceivable and likely occurrence in planning.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 487,
        "Question": "PERT is the abbreviation for ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Project Evaluated and Review Technique",
            "b) Project Evaluation and Response Technique",
            "c) Program Evaluation and Response Technique",
            "d) Program Evaluation and Review Technique"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: CPM and PERT are the best known arrow diagrams. Arrow diagram is one of the new seven management tools. The other new management tools are affinity diagram, relationship diagram, tree diagram, matrix diagram, matrix data analysis diagram, and decision tree.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 488,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an output of arrow diagram?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To show the paths to complete a project",
            "b) To find the shortest time possible for the project",
            "c) To calculate the mean, median and mode of a sample data",
            "d) To display graphically simultaneous activities"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: CPM is the abbreviation for Critical Path Method. It is an example of arrow diagram. It is used as a project management tool for scheduling project activities.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 489,
        "Question": "Who developed the concept of ‘TRIZ’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) GenrichAltshuller",
            "b) Deming",
            "c) Crosby",
            "d) Juran"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The concept of ‘TRIZ’ was developed by GenrichAltshuller. It is a Russian acronym which is translated as Theory of Inventive Problem Solving.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 490,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an emotional based method for increasing innovation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Brainstorming",
            "b) Synectics",
            "c) Lateral thinking",
            "d) TRIZ"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: TRIZ is based on logic and data, and not based on intuition or brainstorming. It is a creative problem solving methodology. It was developed by the Russian scientist GenrichAltshuller.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 491,
        "Question": "Which of the following is incorrect with respect to TRIZ?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It reduces the number of trial and error iterations",
            "b) It is based on logic and data",
            "c) It is emotion based",
            "d) It is empirical based"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Brainstorming, synectics, lateral thinking, and mind mapping are emotional based methods for increasing innovation. TRIZ is an empirical based method for increasing innovation.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 492,
        "Question": "Which of the following is incorrect with respect to TRIZ?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Useful for new product analysis",
            "b) Useful for failure prediction",
            "c) Useful for failure analysis",
            "d) Can’t be used in new product analysis"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: According to TRIZ, one has to find the solution for the existing problem from the existing set of solutions. Somewhere, someone may have solved the problem already or something similar. The task is to find that solution from the given set of solutions.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 493,
        "Question": "Which of the following is false about TRIZ?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It saves time",
            "b) It saves money",
            "c) It increases risk",
            "d) It reduces risk"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: TRIZ reduces the number of trial and error iterations for solving a problem. It is based on logic and data. It is empirical based.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 494,
        "Question": "What does IFR mean?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ideal Final Result",
            "b) Initialize Final Result",
            "c) Ideal Final Report",
            "d) Initialize Final Report"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: TRIZ can be used for new product analysis. It can be used for failure prediction. It can also be used in failure analysis. Basically, it can be used to work on any type of problem.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 495,
        "Question": "The quality loss function is given by L(x) = k(x-N)2. What does ‘k’ stand for?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Tolerance",
            "b) Quality loss coefficient",
            "c) Nominal value of given product",
            "d) Quality characteristic of selected product"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Taguchi methods aim at improving the quality of manufactured goods. They are statistical methods developed majorly by Genichi Taguchi.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 496,
        "Question": "Which among the following is the correct formula for evaluating the quality loss coefficient ‘k’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) k=c+d",
            "b) k=c/d",
            "c) k=c/d2",
            "d) k=c-d"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The constant of proportionality ‘k’ is also known as quality loss coefficient. The quality loss function is a quadratic equation given by Taguchi.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 497,
        "Question": "If the specifications of a product are 10±3 for a particular quality characteristic and the average repair cost is ₹200, what is the value of the quality loss coefficient?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 20.23",
            "b) 22.23",
            "c) 24.23",
            "d) 26.23"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation:  k=c/d2 represents the correct formula for evaluating the quality loss coefficient ‘k’. Here, c=loss associated with the specification limit and d=deviation of the specification from the targeted value.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 498,
        "Question": "In the case of smaller-the-better characteristics, what is the value of ideal target (N)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0",
            "b) 50",
            "c) 100",
            "d) 200"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Here, d=3, and c=₹200. So, putting the respective values of ‘d’ and ‘c’ in the  formula k=c/d2  we get k = 22.23. Here, k=quality loss coefficient, c=loss associated with the specification limit and d=deviation of the specification from the targeted value.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 499,
        "Question": "The quality loss function is given by L(x) = k(x-N)2. What does ‘N’ stand for?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Tolerance",
            "b) Quality loss coefficient",
            "c) Nominal value of given product",
            "d) Quality characteristic of selected product"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the case of smaller-the-better characteristics, the value of ideal target (N) is 0. It is a special case often used in manufacturing of products.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 500,
        "Question": "Which parameter represents the slope of quality loss function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Tolerance",
            "b) Quality loss coefficient",
            "c) Nominal value of given product",
            "d) Quality characteristic of selected product"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In the quality loss function, ‘N’ represents the nominal value of given product. For example, if the specification of a product is 10±3 mm then 10 mm is the nominal value of the given product.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 501,
        "Question": "Which among the following does not fit into the category of loss described by Taguchi?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Failure to function",
            "b) Maintenance and repair cost",
            "c) Customer dissatisfaction",
            "d) Employee lay-off"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Traditional approach focuses on specification limits and Taguchi’s approach focuses on target value. In traditional approach, a product falling within the given specification limits is considered as a good product. In Taguchi’s approach, a product deviating from the target value will incur loss.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 502,
        "Question": "If tolerance is  ±0.25 mm and the quality loss coefficient is 2520, then which of the following represents the quality loss function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) L=2520*(0.25)2",
            "b) L=2520*0.25",
            "c) L=2520/0.25",
            "d) L=2520-0.25"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The quality loss function is given by L(x) = k(x-N)2. The slope of quality loss function is given by quality loss coefficient. It can be determined by the relation k=c/d2.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 503,
        "Question": "What is not benchmarking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Systematic search for best practices",
            "b) Systematic search for innovative ideas",
            "c) Systematic search for highly effective operating procedures",
            "d) Systematic search for imitating competitors"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Benchmarking is the process of systematically searching for best practices, innovative ideas, and highly effective operating procedures. All these need to be done to survive and grow in this competitive industry.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 504,
        "Question": "Benchmarking is used by organizations as a ________ tool.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Intermittent improvement",
            "b) Discontinuous improvement",
            "c) Continuous improvement",
            "d) Sporadic improvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Defining a proper metric for performance comparison is important in benchmarking. The target value must be what the best-in-class achieves. Then, organization compares its performance with the target value.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 505,
        "Question": "Company A manufactures 10 defective products on an average out of 1000 products manufactured. Company B manufactures 5 defective products on an average out of 1000 products manufactured. Which company must be chosen for benchmarking and by whom?",
        "Options": [
            "a) B should choose A as benchmark",
            "b) A should choose B as benchmark",
            "c) Both are equally efficient",
            "d) Concept of benchmarking is not applicable here"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Benchmarking requires managers who understand the reasons for performance variation. Proper understanding will help the organization come closer to the target value achieved by the best-in-class.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 506,
        "Question": "Benchmarking involves ________ between the performance level of the organization with its benchmark.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increasing the gap",
            "b) Reducing the gap",
            "c) Opening the gap",
            "d) Broadening the gap"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Benchmarking is used by organizations as a continuous improvement tool. It is the process of systematically searching for best practices, innovative ideas, and highly effective operating procedures.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 507,
        "Question": "Benchmarking is used extensively in __________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Manufacturing organizations only",
            "b) Service organizations only",
            "c) Manufacturing and service organizations",
            "d) Government institutions only"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: A should choose B as benchmark as A is manufacturing more defective products compared to B. A must reduce its average number of defects from 10 out of 1000 manufactured products.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 508,
        "Question": "Proper selection of the best-in-class for benchmarking is _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Crucial",
            "b) Doesn’t hold great importance",
            "c) Least important",
            "d) Not important"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Benchmarking involves reducing the gap between the performance level of the organization with its benchmark. It is used as a continuous improvement tool.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 509,
        "Question": "In which form of benchmarking is comparison of a business process done with a similar process within the organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Internal benchmarking",
            "b) Competitive benchmarking",
            "c) Functional benchmarking",
            "d) Generic benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In Internal benchmarking, comparison of a business process is done with a similar process within the organization. Comparable sites, branches, sections, departments within the business can be chosen for benchmarking.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 510,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of internal benchmarking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Low cost",
            "b) High cost",
            "c) Relatively easy",
            "d) Deeper understanding of all the processes of the organization"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Internal benchmarking is comparison of a business process that is done with a similar process within the organization. It is low cost, relatively easy and it leads to in-depth understanding of all the processes of the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 511,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a challenge to internal benchmarking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Low performance improvement",
            "b) Internal bias",
            "c) It may not provide best-in-class comparison",
            "d) High performance improvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Internal benchmarking may lead to low performance improvement and it might not provide best-in-class comparison. Internal bias may also be an additional challenge. Hence, we must wisely use internal benchmarking as a comparison tool.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 512,
        "Question": "In which form of benchmarking is direct comparison with competitor done of a product, service, process or method?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Internal benchmarking",
            "b) Competitive benchmarking",
            "c) Functional benchmarking",
            "d) Generic benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In competitive benchmarking, direct comparison with competitors is done of a product, service, process or method. This form of benchmarking is efficient in knowing where your organization stands compared to your competitors.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 513,
        "Question": "In which form of benchmarking is comparison of similar or identical practices within same or immediate industry is done?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Internal benchmarking",
            "b) Competitive benchmarking",
            "c) Functional benchmarking",
            "d) Generic benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In competitive benchmarking, direct comparison with competitors is done of a product, service, process or method. Therefore, if mutual consensus is there to grow together between two competitors, a partnership can also happen.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 514,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a challenge to functional benchmarking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Variation in corporate culture",
            "b) Takes more time than internal benchmarking",
            "c) Common functions are difficult to find",
            "d) Takes less time compared to internal benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Trade secrets may be a challenge in competitor benchmarking. This can lead to improper comparison and may yield to improper results. Competitors can also capitalize on your weakness which may also pose a threat to your organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 515,
        "Question": "In which form of benchmarking unrelated business processes or functions that can be utilized are studied?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Internal benchmarking",
            "b) Competitive benchmarking",
            "c) Functional benchmarking",
            "d) Generic benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In functional benchmarking, comparison of similar or identical practices within same or immediate industry is done. This provides information about industry trends. The improvement rate of the organization becomes better too.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 516,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of generic benchmarking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Non-competitive",
            "b) Lack of innovation",
            "c) Non-threatening",
            "d) High potential towards discovery"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In functional benchmarking, comparison of similar or identical practices within same or immediate industry is done. Variation in corporate culture is a major challenge to functional benchmarking. It takes more time compared to internal benchmarking as common functions are difficult to find.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 517,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of process benchmarking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) To make the process effective",
            "b) To make the process efficient",
            "c) To make the process faster",
            "d) To make the process ineffective"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The advantage of process benchmarking is to make the process effective, efficient, and faster. It leads to process optimization. Process improvement is a major step organization’s take towards continuous improvement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 518,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a type of comparison made through strategic benchmarking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Business approaches comparison",
            "b) Business strategy comparison",
            "c) Number of managers in each company",
            "d) Business model comparison"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Process benchmarking can be used in customer complaint processes. It is used to make a process more efficient, effective and fast. It can also be used in order and fulfilment process.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 519,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a technique used during performance benchmarking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reverse engineering",
            "b) Analysis of operating statistics",
            "c) Direct product or service comparison",
            "d) To understand business strategy"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Strategic benchmarking shows long term benefits. It examines how companies compete and is rarely industry-focused.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 520,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not put under focus during performance benchmarking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Elements of cost",
            "b) Technical quality",
            "c) Number of employees in organization",
            "d) Product or service features"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The comparisons made in strategic benchmarking are that of business approaches, business strategy, and business model. It helps you identify the best business strategies of best companies.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 521,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an example of functional performance benchmarking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Employee net promoter score",
            "b) Number of managers in organization",
            "c) Staff engagement surveys",
            "d) Brand awareness"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Reverse engineering, direct product or service comparison,and analysis of operating statistics are the different techniques that are used during performance benchmarking. The other important types of benchmarking are process benchmarking and strategic benchmarking.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 522,
        "Question": "Revenue growth and customer satisfaction can be assessed through _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Performance benchmarking",
            "b) Process benchmarking",
            "c) Strategic benchmarking",
            "d) Poka Yoke"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Elements of cost, technical quality, and product or service features are some of the performance characteristics put under focus during performance benchmarking. The other important performance characteristics are speed and reliability.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 523,
        "Question": "What does FMEA stand for?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Failure Modes and Effects Analysis",
            "b) Failure Modes and Effective Analysis",
            "c) Failure Modes and Affective Analysis",
            "d) Failure Modes and Efficient Analysis"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: FMEA stands for Failure Modes and Effects Analysis. It is also known as risk analysis. It displays systematically the causes, effects, and possible actions regarding observed failures.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 524,
        "Question": "What is RPN?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Risk Potential Number",
            "b) Risk Priority Number",
            "c) Risk Preference number",
            "d) Risk Preventive Number"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: To anticipate failures and prevent them from happening is the objective of FMEA. FMEA lists down the failures, their causes, their effects, and possible recommended actions regarding the observed failures.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 525,
        "Question": "Find the odd one out related to the FMEA team.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Assembly engineer",
            "b) Manufacturing engineer",
            "c) Quality engineer",
            "d) Process variability data"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: RPN stands for the Risk Priority Number. Items with high RPN require additional quality planning action. It is the product of Severity, Occurrence and Detection rankings.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 526,
        "Question": " Find the odd one out related to the data inputs required to prepare FMEA.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Product and process specifications",
            "b) Reliability data",
            "c) Customer priority data",
            "d) Quality engineer"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The analysis of potential failures of product or service due to component or subsystem unreliability is involved in design FMEA. Design FMEA and Process FMEA are the two broad categories of FMEA.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 527,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of FMEA?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increase in customer satisfaction",
            "b) Prioritize product/process deficiencies",
            "c) Maximize late changes and associated cost",
            "d) Document and track actions taken to reduce risk"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Assembly engineer, manufacturing engineer, and quality engineer are important members of the FMEA team. The other important members of the FMEA team are the Materials engineer, Service engineer, suppliers, and the customers.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 528,
        "Question": "A particular product has been given the following rankings for calculating RPN while preparing FMEA chart, S=10, O=2, D=2. What is the value of RPN?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 20",
            "b) 10",
            "c) 40",
            "d) 2"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Product and process specifications, reliability data, and customer priority data are important data inputs to prepare FMEA. The other important data inputs to prepare FMEA are process variability data, process descriptions, and inspection data.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 529,
        "Question": "According to common industry scale, what does severity ranking (S) 1 indicate?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Very serious effect",
            "b) No effect",
            "c) Sometimes serious effect",
            "d) The value doesn’t exist"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Increased customer satisfaction, Prioritization of product/process deficiencies, and documentation and tracking of the actions taken to reduce risk are some of the important benefits of FMEA. It leads to minimization of late changes and associated cost.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 530,
        "Question": "According to common industry scale, what does occurrence ranking (O) 1 indicate?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Not likely",
            "b) Highly likely",
            "c) Certain to happen",
            "d) The value doesn’t exist"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The RPN is the product of Severity, Occurrence and Detection rankings. Therefore, RPN=S*O*D, or RPN=10*2*2=40.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 531,
        "Question": "According to common industry scale, what does detection ranking (D) 1 indicate?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Can’t be determined",
            "b) Uncertainty in detection",
            "c) The value doesn’t exist",
            "d) Certainly detectable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The correct order of proceeding is by first specifying possibilities. It is followed by quantification of risk. Correcting high risk causes and re-evaluation of risk follows next. The re-evaluation of risk involves the recalculation of the risk priority number (RPN).\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 532,
        "Question": "Discrete data is also known as ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Continuous data",
            "b) Disputed data",
            "c) Variable data",
            "d) Attribute data"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Information is processed data. Data are raw observations that are collected randomly. Information is meaningful data and is presented in an ordered manner.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 533,
        "Question": "Number of scrap items in a factory is _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Continuous data",
            "b) Disputed data",
            "c) Discrete data",
            "d) Variable data"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Discrete data is also known as Attribute data. They are countable in nature. For example, the number of defective products in a production cycle is an example of attribute data.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 534,
        "Question": "Variable data is also known as ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Continuous data",
            "b) Disputed data",
            "c) Discrete data",
            "d) Attribute data"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Number of scrap items in a factory is discrete data. It can be counted and given a number, for example 36 or 45. It is not a specified number. Discrete data is also known as Attribute data.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 535,
        "Question": "The data set for measuring length of an object which is 50 cm includes five readings which are 40 cm, 40 cm, 41 cm, 40.5 cm, and 41 cm. What can be the conclusion made by this study?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data is precise and accurate",
            "b) Data is precise but not accurate",
            "c) Data is neither precise nor accurate",
            "d) Data is not precise but accurate"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Variable data is also known as continuous data. Lengths, width, height of an object are examples of variable data. They are gathered by taking actual measurements.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 536,
        "Question": "The data set for measuring width of an object which is 50 cm includes five readings which are 49.5 cm, 49.5 cm, 50.5 cm, 50.3 cm, and 49.7 cm. What can be the conclusion made by this study?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data is precise and accurate",
            "b) Data is precise but not accurate",
            "c) Data is neither precise nor accurate",
            "d) Data is not precise but accurate"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: As the data set has values which are close to each other, the data set is precise. But it is not accurate as the target value is 50 cm and there is a huge difference between data set values and the target value.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 537,
        "Question": "The data set for measuring height of an object which is 80 cm includes five readings which are 40.5 cm, 81 cm, 72 cm, 48 cm, 50 cm. What can be the conclusion made by this study?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data is precise and accurate",
            "b) Data is precise but not accurate",
            "c) Data is neither precise nor accurate",
            "d) Data is not precise but accurate"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: As the data set values are close to target value therefore the data set is both accurate and precise. Precision is closeness of the data set values to each other and accuracy is the closeness of the data set values to the chosen target value.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 538,
        "Question": "If the diameter of a shaft is measured as 60 mm, 62 mm, 63 mm, 61 mm, 60 mm. What is the mean diameter that can be considered for calculation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 61.1 mm",
            "b) 61.2 mm",
            "c) 61.3 mm",
            "d) 61.4 mm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The data set values are neither close to each other nor are they close to the chosen target value (80 cm). Therefore, the data set values are neither accurate nor precise.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 539,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a measure of central tendency?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Range",
            "b) Mean",
            "c) Median",
            "d) Mode"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The mean is calculated as the sum of observed values divided by the number of observed values. The sum of the observed values is 306. The number of observed values is 5. Therefore, the mean diameter of the shaft is 306/5=61.2 mm.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 540,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a measure of dispersion?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Range",
            "b) Mean deviation",
            "c) Mean",
            "d) Standard deviation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Mean, median, and mode are the three measures of central tendency. They describe the centre values of the observed data. Mean is also known as arithmetic average.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 541,
        "Question": "The peak of a curve is located at (4,4). Four students located the peak of the curve to be at (3,4), (5,4), (4,3), and (4,5). What can be the conclusion made by this study?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data is precise and accurate",
            "b) Data is precise but not accurate",
            "c) Data is neither precise nor accurate",
            "d) Data is not precise but accurate"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The mean is not a measure of dispersion. Mean is a measure of central tendency. Measures of dispersion are also known as measures of precision. The spread of the observations around the centre is termed as dispersion.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 542,
        "Question": "If the diameter of a shaft is measured as 80 mm, 81 mm, 82 mm, 83 mm, 84 mm. What is the median of the observed values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 80 mm",
            "b) 81 mm",
            "c) 84 mm",
            "d) 82 mm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: As the students located the peak of the curve near to the point (4,4) which is the ideal target value, the data set is uniform. But the values of the peak of the curve for any one student is not close to his/her friends, hence the data set is not precise.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 543,
        "Question": "If the diameter of a shaft is measured as 80 mm, 81 mm, 82 mm, 83 mm, 84 mm, 85 mm. What is the median of the observed values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 80 mm",
            "b) 81 mm",
            "c) 84 mm",
            "d) 82.5 mm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The diameter of the shaft is measured as 80 mm, 81 mm, 82 mm, 83 mm, 84 mm. The number of observations is odd (5). The median is ((5+1)/2)th value. Therefore, the median is 82 mm.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 544,
        "Question": "If the observed diameter of a shaft is 20 mm, 21 mm, 23 mm, 22.5 mm, 24 mm. What is the mode of the observed data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 21 mm",
            "b) There is no mode",
            "c) 22.5 mm",
            "d) 20 mm"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The diameter of a shaft is measured as 80 mm, 81 mm, 82 mm, 83 mm, 84 mm, 85 mm. The number of observations is even (6). The median is the average of (6/2)th and ((6/2)+1)th value. Therefore, the median is average of 82 mm and 83 mm, which is 82.5 mm.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 545,
        "Question": "The height of a tank measured by five engineers is 5 m, 4 m, 4.5 m , 4.5 m, 5 m. What is the mode of the calculated values?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 4.5 m",
            "b) 4 m",
            "c) 5 m",
            "d) 4.5 m and 5 m"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The observed diameter of a shaft is 20 mm, 21 mm, 23 mm, 22.5 mm, 24 mm. As all the values occur once, there is no mode in the observed data set values. Mode is defined as the value which occurs most the number of times.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 546,
        "Question": "Measures of precision are also known as ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Measures of central tendency",
            "b) Measures of dispersion",
            "c) Measures of accuracy",
            "d) Measures of statistics"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Measures of precision are also known as measures of dispersion. They determine the spread of the observations around the center. Range, mean deviation and standard deviation are the three measures of dispersion.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 547,
        "Question": "Given for an asymmetrical distribution, median=20, mean=22, what is the mode?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 12",
            "b) 14",
            "c) 16",
            "d) 18"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: For symmetrical distribution, mean=median=mode. For asymmetrical distribution, mode=3*median-2*mean. So, if two parameters are known, the third one can be evaluated.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 548,
        "Question": "Find the range of the following observations: 1,2,4,7,8,13.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 11",
            "b) 12",
            "c) 13",
            "d) 14"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: For an asymmetrical distribution, mode=3*median-2*mean. Here, median=20 and mean=22. So, mode = 3(20)-2(22)=60-44=16.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 549,
        "Question": "What is the mean deviation from the mean of the following observation:9,9,2,3,6,9,4?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2.50",
            "b) 2.62",
            "c) 2.40",
            "d) 2.57"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Range is the difference between the highest and lowest observation in a series. Here, the highest observation is 13 and the lowest observation is 1. So, range=13-1=12.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 550,
        "Question": "The standard deviation is 110 and the mean is 770. What is the coefficient of variation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 15",
            "b) 14.29",
            "c) 13.37",
            "d) 12"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The mean of the given observation is (9+9+2+3+6+9+4)/7=6. Mean deviation from mean = (|6-9|+|6-9|+|6-2|+|6-3|+|6-6|+|6-9|+|6-4|)/7 = (3+3+4+3+0+3+2)/7=2.57.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 551,
        "Question": "If the coefficient of variation of a data set A is 40 and for data set B it is 60, which data set is more consistent?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data set A",
            "b) Data set B",
            "c) Both are equally consistent",
            "d) Neither of them is consistent"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The square of the standard deviation is variance. For example, if the variance of a given set of observations is 66.2, the standard deviation would be \\(\\sqrt{66.2}\\)=8.13.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 552,
        "Question": "If the variance of the data 2, 4, 5, 6, 8, 17 is 23.33. Then, what is the variance of 4, 8, 10, 12, 16, 34?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 40",
            "b) 42.55",
            "c) 46.66",
            "d) 49"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The coefficient of variation is given by (SD/mean)*100. So, the coefficient of variation, in this case, is (110/770)*100 = 14.29.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 553,
        "Question": "A set of observations x1, x2, x3, x4, has a standard deviation = 6. Each of these observations is added with a constant k. What is the new standard deviation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 10",
            "b) 8",
            "c) 6",
            "d) 4"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The coefficient of variation represents the variability of a given set of observations. Therefore, the data set with less coefficient of variation is more consistent. Hence, data set A is more consistent compared to data set B.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 554,
        "Question": "The collection of all the results of an operation can be called as __________ in statistics.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Population",
            "b) Sample",
            "c) Sampling",
            "d) Random"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The collection of all the results of an operation can be called as ‘population’ in statistics. ‘Population’ is also known as ‘Universe’ in statistics. The inclusion of all observations in a data set can be referred to as ‘population’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 555,
        "Question": "The subset of a population is known as ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Population",
            "b) Sample",
            "c) Sampling",
            "d) Random variable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The subset of a population is known as ‘sample’ data. For example, people living in a state can be referred to as a ‘population’, but the number of English speaking people from that population can be referred to as a ‘sample’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 556,
        "Question": "The process of sample selection in statistics is known as _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Mean",
            "b) Median",
            "c) Sampling",
            "d) Random variable"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The process of sample selection in statistics is known as ‘sampling’. The sample selection should be judicious and must reflect and resemble the entire population.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 557,
        "Question": "The Gaussian curve is also known as ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Poisson curve",
            "b) Weibull curve",
            "c) Normal curve",
            "d) Exponential curve"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Sampling can be used when it is impossible to measure the entire population. It can be also be used when measuring the whole population is expensive.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 558,
        "Question": "If the standard deviation is zero, what comment can we make on the type of normal curve formed?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data spread around the mean value is more",
            "b) Data spread around the mean value is less",
            "c) Data spread around the mean value is more in the negative x-axis only",
            "d) No curve is formed"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The Gaussian curve is also known as the normal curve. It is symmetrical and has a bell-shaped distribution. The mean, mode, and median have the same value.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 559,
        "Question": "There are two normal curves with the same mean value. The standard deviation of curve 1 is more than curve 2, what can we comment on the two normal curves?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Curve 1 is flatter than Curve 2",
            "b) Curve 1 is peaked than Curve 2",
            "c) Curve 1 is similar to Curve 2",
            "d) Curve 1 and Curve 2 cannot be compared"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: If the standard deviation is zero, there is no curve formed. All the values are identical to the mean value. The ‘Normal curve’ is also known as the ‘Gaussian curve’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 560,
        "Question": "Numerical data measured directly from a sample is known as _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sampling",
            "b) Statistic",
            "c) Population",
            "d) Parameter"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: There are two normal curves with the same mean value. Curve 1 is flatter than Curve 2. The data is more spread out in Curve 1. Curve 2 data spread is narrower compared to Curve 1.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 561,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a type of sampling technique?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stratified sampling",
            "b) Cluster sampling",
            "c) Judgment sampling",
            "d) Sample sampling"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘Parameter’ is a true population estimated by a ‘statistic’ and is often unknown. ‘Parameter’ is difficult and expensive to be measured directly.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 562,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a factor that affects the occurrence of ‘random causes of variation’ in any manufacturing process?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Human variability",
            "b) Minor variations in raw materials",
            "c) Working conditions fluctuations",
            "d) Differences among machines"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘Random causes of variations’ in any manufacturing process are inevitable. They are also known as ‘common causes of variations’ of a manufacturing process. Yet another name is ‘chance causes of variations’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 563,
        "Question": "‘Assignment causes of variation’ of any manufacturing process are also known as _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Random causes of variations",
            "b) Common causes of variations",
            "c) Chance causes of variations",
            "d) Special causes of variations"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Human variability from one operation cycle to another, minor variations in raw materials, and fluctuations in working conditions are some of the factors that affect the occurrence of ‘random causes of variation’. Lack of adequate supervision skills can also be a factor affecting the occurrence of ‘random causes of variation’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 564,
        "Question": "A stable process in any manufacturing process exhibits only ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Assignable causes of variations",
            "b) Special causes of variations",
            "c) Chance cause of variations",
            "d) A stable process cannot be predicted"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ‘Assignment causes of variation’ of any manufacturing process are also known as ‘special causes of variations’. The other type of variation in any manufacturing process is known as ‘chance causes of variation’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 565,
        "Question": "The x̅-charts and R-charts monitor ____ and ____ of any manufacturing process.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Precision, accuracy",
            "b) Accuracy, precision",
            "c) Variation, accuracy",
            "d) Precision, variation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘Assignment cause of variation’ in any manufacturing process can be easily traced and detected. Also, they are larger in magnitude. It is important to trace and eliminate them to keep the process statistically in-control.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 566,
        "Question": "The x̅-charts and R-charts are also known as ________ and _______ respectively.",
        "Options": [
            "a) average-charts, range-charts",
            "b) median-charts, average-charts",
            "c) range-charts, median-charts",
            "d) median-charts, range-charts"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: A stable process in any manufacturing process exhibits only ‘chance causes of variation’. ‘Random causes of variations’ and ‘common causes of variations’ are other names given to ‘chance causes of variations’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 567,
        "Question": "In the jargon of statistical process control, USL and LSL are known as _______ and _____ respectively.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Upper specification limit, Lower specification limit",
            "b) Upper specification limit, Limit specification limit",
            "c) Up specification limit, Limit specification limit",
            "d) Up specification limit, Lower specification limit"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the jargon of statistical process control, USL and LSL are known as Upper specification limit and Lower specification limit respectively. Specification limits are usually determined from customer requirements.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 568,
        "Question": "Specification limits are also known as ________ of the product.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Mode",
            "b) Median",
            "c) Tolerances",
            "d) Allowances"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Specification limits are also known as tolerances of the product. There are two types of specification limits known as upper specification limit and lower specification limit.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 569,
        "Question": "Natural tolerance is also known as _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Specification limits",
            "b) Control limit",
            "c) Process capability",
            "d) Mean"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If a product falls in the range of USL-LSL then it is meeting the expectation of the customer. Specification limits are also known as the tolerance of the product. There is not much we can do about the specification limits but we can monitor the control limits.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 570,
        "Question": "The upper specification limit of a product is 20.05 mm and the lower specification limit of the same product is 19.95 mm. The standard deviation is 0.25 mm. What is the value of the process capability index Cp?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.0424",
            "b) 0.8324",
            "c) 0.0234",
            "d) 0.0667"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Tolerance limits are the voice of the customer. While the control limits are the voice of the process. Specification limits are defined by the customer while the control limits are calculated from data.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 571,
        "Question": "What is the interpretation of Cp>1?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The process cannot meet the specification",
            "b) The process will meet the specification",
            "c) The process is just meeting the specification",
            "d) No interpretation is possible"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Natural tolerance is also known as process capability. Process capability is also known as 6σ. It compares process output with customer specification limits.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 572,
        "Options": [
            "a) A-i, B-ii, C-iii",
            "b) A-i, B-iii, C-ii",
            "c) A-ii, B-i, C-iii",
            "d) A-ii, B-iii, C-i"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The process capability index Cp is given by the formula Cp=(USL-LSL)/6σ. So, Cp=(20.05-19.95)/(6*0.25)=0.0667. It is widely utilized in product design phase and pilot production phase.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 573,
        "Question": "What is the interpretation of Cpk=Cp?",
        "Options": [
            "a) The process is out of control",
            "b) The process is customer-centric",
            "c) The process is centered",
            "d) The process is costly"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The interpretation of Cp>1 is that the process will meet the specification. The numerator shows the specification limits determined from the customer and the denominator is the process capability. The ratio, greater than 1 implies that process capability lies within the specification limits.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 574,
        "Question": "The control chart that determines the fraction of rejected parts as non-conforming is ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) R-chart",
            "b) S-chart",
            "c) P-chart",
            "d) C-chart"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The control chart that determines the fraction of rejected parts as non-conforming is P-chart. It belongs to the category of control charts for attributes.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 575,
        "Question": "The total number of parts in ten samples of equal size is 1200. What is the average sample size?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 120",
            "b) 12",
            "c) 1.2",
            "d) 1200"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The total number of parts in ten samples of equal size is 1200. The average sample size is 1200/10=120. It is useful in calculating the control limits.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 576,
        "Question": "The total number of defect count is 200 and the total number of parts in ten samples of equal size is 1500. What is the fraction defective?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.131",
            "b) 0.134",
            "c) 0.137",
            "d) 0.140"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The total number of defect count is 200 and the total number of parts in ten samples of equal size is 1500. The fraction defective is calculated as 200/1500 = 0.134.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 577,
        "Question": "The control chart for defects is called as _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) R-chart",
            "b) S-chart",
            "c) P-chart",
            "d) C-chart"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The p-chart is used when subgroup size is variable. The np chart is used when the subgroup size is constant. The np chart is preferred because it saves time in the calculation for each subgroup.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 578,
        "Question": "What is the basis for C-chart?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Normal distribution",
            "b) Poisson distribution",
            "c) Weibull distribution",
            "d) Exponential distribution"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The control chart for defects is called as C-chart. It records the number of defects in the sample. It is an important control chart for attributes.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 579,
        "Question": "The control chart that measures the number of non-conformities is ____ and the one that measures the number of non-conformities per unit is ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) R-chart, S-chart",
            "b) C-chart, U-chart",
            "c) P-chart, R-chart",
            "d) R-chart, P-chart"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The basis for C-chart is the Poisson distribution. C-chart counts the number of defects in the sample. Here, the letter ‘C’ refers to ‘count’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 580,
        "Question": "Who is considered to be the father of Six Sigma?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Bill Smith",
            "b) Deming",
            "c) Crosby",
            "d) Taguchi"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Bill Smith is considered the father of Six Sigma. He was an engineer at Motorola. Motorola was one amongst the first company to win the Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 581,
        "Question": "DPMO stands for ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Defects per meter opportunities",
            "b) Defects per million opportunities",
            "c) Defects per month of opportunities",
            "d) Defects per millimeter of opportunities"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Six Sigma allows only 3.4 defects per million opportunities. Major companies like Motorola and General Electric have successfully implemented Six Sigma.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 582,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of using Six Sigma?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process improvement",
            "b) Product improvement",
            "c) Defect reduction",
            "d) A decrease in customer satisfaction"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: DPMO stands for defects per million opportunities. The objective of Six Sigma is to approach zero defects and allows only 3.4 defects per million opportunities.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 583,
        "Question": "The combination of Six Sigma and lean manufacturing is known as ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lean Sigma",
            "b) Lean Two Sigma",
            "c) Lean Six Sigma",
            "d) Lean Three Sigma"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Process improvement and product improvement are the direct benefits of incorporating Six Sigma. This leads to a reduction in defects and improves customer satisfaction.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 584,
        "Question": "What is the percentage accuracy in the six sigma process?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 99.8%",
            "b) 99.1%",
            "c) 99.05%",
            "d) 99.99966%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The combination of Six Sigma and lean manufacturing is known as Lean Six Sigma. It is a combination of two continuous improvement methods.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 585,
        "Question": "In which among the following is the Six Sigma process not applicable?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Healthcare",
            "b) Business administration",
            "c) Selecting the best employee of the year",
            "d) Supply Chain"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The percentage accuracy in the six sigma process is 99.99966%. The six sigma process allows only 3.4 defects per million opportunities.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 586,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a six sigma belt level ranking?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Yellow Belt",
            "b) Pink Belt",
            "c) Green Belt",
            "d) Black Belt"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The six sigma process is applicable in healthcare, business administration, supply chain and in many other industrial sectors. The process of six sigma was pioneered by Bill Smith.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 587,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not part of the ‘Define’ activity in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Identification of project",
            "b) Identification of champion",
            "c) Identification of project owner",
            "d) Identification of founder of the business"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Six Sigma follows the DMAIC model. D stands for Define, M stands for Measure, A stands for Analyze, I stands for Improve, C stands for Control.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 588,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not belong to the ‘Define’ activity in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Determination of customer requirements",
            "b) Determination of CTQs",
            "c) Validating the measurements",
            "d) Mapping the process"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The identification of the project, the identification of the champion, the identification of project owners are major activities involved in ‘Define’ activity in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma. The founder of the business, if he/she is heading the business responsibility, also is an integral part of the ‘Define’ activity.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 589,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a tool used in the ‘Define’ process in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Project charter and plan",
            "b) Check sheet",
            "c) Effort/impact analysis",
            "d) Process mapping"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Determination of customer requirements, Determination of CTQs, and Mapping the process are important activities that belong to the ‘Define’ activity in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma. Validating the measurements is a ‘Measure’ activity.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 590,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a tool used in the ‘Measure’ process in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality Function Deployment",
            "b) Measurement Systems Analysis",
            "c) Process capability",
            "d) Tree diagram"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Defining the problem, objective, goals, and benefits belong to the ‘Define’ activity in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma. Apart from these, defining stakeholder/resource analysis is also an integral activity of the ‘Define’ activity in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 591,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not part of the ‘Measure’ activity in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Determining operational definitions",
            "b) Establishing performance standards",
            "c) Developing the project plan",
            "d) Developing data collection and sample plan"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Project charter and plan, Effort/impact analysis, and process mapping are the tools used in the ‘Define’ process in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma. In addition to this, tree diagram is also used in the ‘Define’ process in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 592,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a tool used in the ‘Analyze’ process in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality Function Deployment",
            "b) Histogram",
            "c) Pareto Diagram",
            "d) Run chart"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Quality Function Deployment, Measurement Systems Analysis, and Process capability are the tools used in the ‘Measure’ process in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma. In addition to this, check sheet is also used in the ‘Measure’ process in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 593,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not part of the ‘Improve’ activity in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Determination of solution effectiveness using data",
            "b) Implementing solution",
            "c) Developing solution alternatives",
            "d) Closing project and communicating results"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Determining operational definitions, establishing performance standards, and developing data collection and sample plans are major activities involved in ‘Measure’ activity in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma. In addition to this, validating the measurements is also an important ‘Measure’ activity.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 594,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a tool used in the ‘Improve’ process in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Design of Experiments",
            "b) Brainstorming",
            "c) Statistical Process Control",
            "d) Failure Mode Effect Analysis"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Histogram, Pareto Diagram, and Run chart are important tools used in the ‘Analyze’ process of the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma. In addition to this, the scatter graph and statistical analysis of data are also important tools used in the ‘Analyze’ process of the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 595,
        "Question": "What does the letter ‘D’ and ‘V’ refer to in the DMADV model?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Data, Verify",
            "b) Design, Validate",
            "c) Data, Validate",
            "d) Design, Verify"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Determination of solution effectiveness using data, Implementing solution, and Developing solution alternatives are integral activities of the ‘Improve’ activity in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma. Closing project and communicating results are part of the ‘Control’ activity in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 596,
        "Question": "OCAP refers to ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) On Control Action Plan",
            "b) Out of Control Action Plan",
            "c) Out of Concern Action Plan",
            "d) Out of Control Assessment Plan"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Design of Experiments, Brainstorming, and  Failure Mode Effect Analysis are important tools used in the ‘Improve’ process in the DMAIC Model of Six Sigma. Statistical Process Control is used as a tool in the ‘Control’ process in the  DMAIC Model of Six Sigma.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 597,
        "Question": "The Six Sigma model used for improving the existing process/product is _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) DMAIC",
            "b) DMAAD",
            "c) DMADV",
            "d) DMAAX"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The letters ‘D’ and ‘V’ refer to ‘Design’ and ‘Verify’ in the DMADV model. It is the application of six sigma on a new process/product.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 598,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a technique used to capture customer requirements for the QFD approach?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Market surveys",
            "b) Customer surveys",
            "c) Cash receipt",
            "d) Customer complaints"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The approach of QFD in product design leads to customer-driven products (processes or services) as it is a customer-centric approach. QFD means Quality Function Deployment.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 599,
        "Question": "Which tool is used to break down the complex customer needs into key customer needs in QFD approach?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Voice of customers",
            "b) Affinity diagram",
            "c) Poka Yoke",
            "d) 5S"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: QFD has a complete focus on the ‘voice of the customer’. The idea conceptualization and the product design using the QFD approach translate customer requirements into the products that are delivered to the customers. QFD is also quintessential to the service industry nowadays.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 600,
        "Question": "HOQ refers to _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Headquarters",
            "b) High Quality",
            "c) House of Quality",
            "d) Head of Quality"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Market surveys, customer surveys, and customer requirements are various techniques used to capture customer requirements for the QFD approach. In addition to this, direct discussions or interviews are also techniques that are commonly used to get insights into customer requirements.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 601,
        "Question": "What does the relationship matrix in the House of Quality represent?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Correlation between customer requirements and technical descriptors",
            "b) Correlation between good and bad customers",
            "c) Correlation between the organization’s profit and loss",
            "d) Correlation between good and bad investors"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Affinity diagram is used quite often to break down the complex customer needs into key customer needs in the QFD approach. Both ‘spoken’ customer needs and ‘unspoken’ customer needs are then planned into action by the planning team.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 602,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an item included in the prioritized customer requirements in the House of Quality?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer importance rating",
            "b) Customer benchmarking",
            "c) Sales point",
            "d) Technical benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: HOQ refers to the House of Quality. It is a primary planning tool used in the QFD approach. It converts the voice of the customer into product design characteristics.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 603,
        "Question": "The interrelationship between technical descriptors in the House of Quality is given by _____",
        "Options": [
            "a) Relationship matrix",
            "b) Trade-off matrix",
            "c) Customer matrix",
            "d) Customer requirement matrix"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The relationship matrix in the House of Quality represents the correlation between customer requirements and technical descriptors. It lies at the center of the House of Quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 604,
        "Question": "The technical descriptors are the ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Voice of the customer",
            "b) Voice of the manager",
            "c) Voice of the owner",
            "d) Voice of the organization"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The customer importance rating, customer benchmarking, and sales point are some of the items included in the prioritized customer requirements in the House of Quality. Some of the other items included are scale-up-factor, target value.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 605,
        "Question": "In which part of the House of Quality ‘product design characteristics’ can be located?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer requirements",
            "b) Prioritized customer requirements",
            "c) Technical descriptors",
            "d) Prioritized technical descriptors"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The interrelationship between technical descriptors in the House of Quality is given by the trade-off matrix. Similar and/or conflicting technical descriptors are identified.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 606,
        "Question": "In which part of the House of Quality ‘degree of technical difficulty’ can be located?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer requirements",
            "b) Prioritized customer requirements",
            "c) Technical descriptors",
            "d) Prioritized technical descriptors"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The technical descriptors are the voice of the organization. They are formulated by the organization based on the ‘voice of the customer’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 607,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an example of customer requirements in the ‘House of Quality’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reasonable cost",
            "b) Corrosion-resistant",
            "c) Durable",
            "d) Sand casting"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Reasonable cost, corrosion-resistant, and durability are examples of customer requirements in the ‘House of Quality’.  Sand casting is an example of a ‘technical descriptor’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 608,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an example of a ‘technical descriptor’ in House of Quality?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sand casting",
            "b) Investment casting",
            "c) Reasonable cost",
            "d) Die casting"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The desire for a lightweight product is an example of customer requirements in the House of Quality. It may be desired because the product can then be carried without much work input.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 609,
        "Question": "‘Performance’ and ‘aesthetics’ in the House of Quality fall under the category of ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Technical descriptors",
            "b) Customer requirements",
            "c) Relationship matrix",
            "d) Poka Yoke"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Sand casting, investment casting, and die casting are examples of ‘technical descriptors’ in the House of Quality. These in particular refer to the type of manufacturing process that could be chosen based on the customer requirements. Reasonable cost is a customer requirement.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 610,
        "Question": "‘Material selection’ and ‘manufacturing process’ in the House of Quality fall under the category of ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Technical descriptors",
            "b) Customer requirements",
            "c) Relationship matrix",
            "d) 5S"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Performance and aesthetics fall under the category of customer requirements in the House of Quality. Some of the performance characteristics are lightweight, strength, durability. Some of the aesthetics characteristics are nice finish and aerodynamic look.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 611,
        "Question": "The categorization of the relationship between customer requirements and technical descriptors as strong, medium or weak in a House of Quality is done in the ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Technical descriptors",
            "b) Interrelationship matrix",
            "c) Relationship matrix",
            "d) 5S"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘Material selection’ and ‘manufacturing process’ in the House of Quality fall under the category of technical descriptors. These are preceded by customer requirements and often followed by a relationship matrix.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 612,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an unjustifiable customer requirement for the new product design of a toy product for children?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reasonable cost",
            "b) Lightweight",
            "c) Good taste",
            "d) Stimulate imagination"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The categorization of the relationship between customer requirements and technical descriptors as strong, medium, or weak in a House of Quality is done in the relationship matrix. Sometimes assignment scores are also added to quantify the relation.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 613,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an unjustifiable customer requirement for the House of Quality of a Pizza?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Good texture",
            "b) Aerodynamic look",
            "c) Fresh and hot delivery",
            "d) Low fats"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Reasonable cost, lightweight, and the need to stimulate imagination are justifiable customer requirements for the new product design of a toy product for children. Good to taste sounds odd here and can be associated with any food item’s House of Quality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 614,
        "Question": "The task of choosing between steel, aluminum, and titanium for a product in a House of Quality falls under the purview of ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Technical descriptors",
            "b) Customer requirements",
            "c) Relationship matrix",
            "d) Benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Good texture, fresh and hot delivery, and low fats are justifiable customer requirements for the House of Quality of a pizza. An aerodynamic look can be associated with a mechanical machine or device.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 615,
        "Question": "The task of choosing between forging, casting, and powder metallurgy for a product in a House of Quality falls under the purview of _____",
        "Options": [
            "a) Production",
            "b) Technical descriptors",
            "c) Relationship matrix",
            "d) Benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The task of choosing between steel, aluminum, and titanium for a product falls under the purview of technical descriptors. This task is technically known as the material selection process.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 616,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a task performed under the ‘part development’ phase in the QFD process?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Deployment of the QFD process down to sub-components level",
            "b) Deployment of the component deployment chart",
            "c) Relating the critical sub-component control characteristics",
            "d) Discovering customer requirements"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The product planning phase of product development using the QFD process begins with the customer requirements. The other phases involved are part development, process planning, and production planning.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 617,
        "Question": "Which of the following statement is incorrect related to the QFD process?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Improves customer satisfaction",
            "b) Promotes teamwork",
            "c) Demotes better understanding of customer demands",
            "d) Focuses on the design efforts"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The product planning phase of product development using the QFD process is actually the steps involved in building the house of quality. It involves customer requirements, technical descriptors, relationship matrix, interrelationship matrix, competitive assessments, prioritized customer requirements, and prioritized technical descriptors.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 618,
        "Question": "Which of the following is an incorrect statement related to the QFD process?",
        "Options": [
            "a) A better understanding of design interactions",
            "b) Breaks down the barrier between functions and departments",
            "c) Better documentation of the design and development process",
            "d) Maximizes the number of engineering changes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Deployment of the QFD process down to sub-components level both in terms of requirements and characteristics, deployment of the component deployment chart, and relating the critical sub-component control characteristics are tasks performed under the ‘part development’ phase in the QFD process. The list of customer requirements is studied under the ‘product planning’ phase.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 619,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a tangible benefit of the QFD process?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reduction in start-up and engineering cost",
            "b) Increase of overall costs",
            "c) Reduction in development time",
            "d) Early identification of high-risk areas"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Improving customer satisfaction by focusing on the design efforts after studying the customer requirements through teamwork are the essential characteristics of QFD. It leads to a better understanding of customer demands.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 620,
        "Question": "The use of QFD process leads to _____ efficient allocation of resources.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Less",
            "b) Very less",
            "c) More",
            "d) Equally"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The QFD process leads to a better understanding of design interactions by breaking down the barrier between functions and departments. As a result, better documentation of the design and development process occurs. It reduces the number of engineering changes required in the later stages.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 621,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an intangible benefit of the QFD process?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increase in development time",
            "b) Improvement in customer satisfaction",
            "c) Strengthens customer-company relationship",
            "d) Facilitating multidisciplinary teamwork"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Reduction in start-up and engineering cost, reduction in development time, and early identification of high-risk areas are the tangible benefits of the QFD process. In fact, there is a reduction in overall costs of design and manufacture.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 622,
        "Question": "Which of the following task is not performed during the ‘production planning’ phase of the OFD process?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Developing prototype",
            "b) Studying technical descriptors",
            "c) Launching the final product",
            "d) Tabulation of operating instructions from the process requirements"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The use of the QFD process leads to more efficient allocation of resources. It is a tangible benefit of the QFD process. QFD process is applicable in both the manufacturing and service industries.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 623,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a phase involved in product development in the QFD process?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Product planning",
            "b) Statistical planning",
            "c) Process planning",
            "d) Production planning"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The improvement in customer satisfaction by utilizing the OFD process by facilitating multidisciplinary teamwork strengthens the customer-company relationship. These are the intangible benefits of the OFD process.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 624,
        "Question": "TPM refers to ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Total Point Maintenance",
            "b) Total Part Maintenance",
            "c) Total Productive Maintenance",
            "d) Total Past Maintenance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: TPM refers to Total Productive Maintenance. It is an equipment maintenance approach that aims at achieving perfect production.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 625,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an interpretation of the term ‘perfect production’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Production without any breakdown",
            "b) Production without any defects",
            "c) Production without any accidents",
            "d) Production with 100% errors"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Production without any breakdown, production without any defects, and production without any accidents are the interpretations of the term ‘perfect production’. It is a concept that is utilized in Total Productive Maintenance.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 626,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a tool used to implement and optimize TPM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Employee empowerment",
            "b) Census",
            "c) Benchmarking",
            "d) Documentation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘Total’ in Total Productive Maintenance refers to all the individuals in maintenance and production working together. TPM refers to the holistic approach of aiming perfect production.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 627,
        "Question": "TQM focuses on ______ and TPM focuses on ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equipment, Quality",
            "b) Both on equipment",
            "c) Quality, equipment",
            "d) Statistics, Equipment"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Employee empowerment, benchmarking, and documentation, are examples of some of the tools used in TPM. These tools are also used in Total Quality Management.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 628,
        "Question": "In which of the following type of maintenance technique, repair is made after machine or equipment failure?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Breakdown maintenance",
            "b) Routine maintenance",
            "c) Poka Yoke",
            "d) Benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: TPM aims at keeping the plant and the equipment at the highest production level. It is achieved through cooperation between all the divisions of the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 629,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a stitch-in-time technique aiming at avoiding breakdowns?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Forecasting",
            "b) Routine maintenance",
            "c) Poka Yoke",
            "d) Benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: TQM focuses on quality and TPM focuses on equipment. Both of them need the support of top management and also active employee participation.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 630,
        "Question": "Which of the following maintenance technique is carried out prior to the occurrence of failure or breakdown of equipment?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Breakdown maintenance",
            "b) Routine maintenance",
            "c) Preventive maintenance",
            "d) Benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In breakdown maintenance, the repair is made after machine or equipment failure. It is also known as corrective maintenance.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 631,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a type of maintenance technique?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Breakdown maintenance",
            "b) Routine maintenance",
            "c) Predictive maintenance",
            "d) 5S"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Routine maintenance is a stitch-in-time technique aiming at avoiding breakdowns. It is also known as scheduled maintenance.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 632,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a type of loss examined by TPM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Down-time loss",
            "b) Speed loss",
            "c) Defect loss",
            "d) Forecasting loss"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Downtime loss, speed loss, and defect loss are the different types of loss examined by TPM. These are important to identify to improve equipment effectiveness.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 633,
        "Question": "MP in Total Productive Maintenance refers to ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Main program",
            "b) Main part",
            "c) Maintenance prevention",
            "d) Major part"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: TQM focuses on achieving autonomous maintenance. It allows the people who are operating the equipment to take responsibility of the maintenance tasks.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 634,
        "Question": "Which of the following loss refers to the gradual deterioration in equipment cycle times?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increased speed",
            "b) Reduced speed",
            "c) Maximum speed",
            "d) Optimum speed"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: MP in Total Productive Maintenance refers to maintenance prevention. It is an aim at moving towards zero maintenance. It is of utmost importance due to its impact on reducing costs in production incurred by the organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 635,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a loss that TPM focuses on reducing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Equipment breakdown",
            "b) Defects and rework",
            "c) Idling and minor stoppages",
            "d) Optimized equipment cycle time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Breakdowns lead to long interruptions. They are considered as a loss that TPM tries to eliminate. The repairs are also expensive and therefore breakdowns must be avoided.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 636,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a goal shared by TPM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Zero defects",
            "b) Maximum productivity",
            "c) Minimum productivity",
            "d) Zero breakdowns"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The gradual deterioration in equipment cycle times is referred to as ‘reduced speed’ loss. It needs to be corrected by identifying potential causes of reduction in equipment cycle time.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 637,
        "Question": "Which pillar of TPM focuses on routine maintenance?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Training and Education",
            "b) Just-in-time",
            "c) 5S",
            "d) Autonomous maintenance"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Equipment breakdown, defects, reworks, idling and minor stoppages are some of the losses that TPM focuses to reduce. Start-up losses, setup and changeover losses are also accounted for by TPM.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 638,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of autonomous maintenance?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sense of ownership in operators",
            "b) Increases operator knowledge of equipment",
            "c) Ensures clean and lubricated equipment",
            "d) Demotes customer satisfaction"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Zero defects, maximum productivity, and zero breakdowns are the goals shared by TPM. Everyone starting from the top management to the equipment operators is responsible for equipment maintenance.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 639,
        "Question": "Which of the following loss refers to the equipment’s inability to get to steady state quickly after a change?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Breakdown",
            "b) Start-up loss",
            "c) Defects and rework",
            "d) Benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Autonomous maintenance focuses on routine maintenance. Routine maintenance includes cleaning, lubricating, and inspection operations performed by the operators.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 640,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the most reasonable time taken by an organization to implement TPM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Two days",
            "b) Three years",
            "c) Five days",
            "d) Fifty years"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Autonomous maintenance aims at bringing in a sense of ownership in operators. It increases operator knowledge of equipment. It also ensures clean and lubricated equipment. It enforces routine maintenance activities.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 641,
        "Question": "Which of the pillar of TPM schedules maintenance based on predicted and/or measured failure rates?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Autonomous maintenance",
            "b) Planned maintenance",
            "c) Focused improvement",
            "d) Benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Planned maintenance is the pillar of TPM which schedules maintenance based on predicted and/or measured failure rates. It significantly reduces unplanned downtime.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 642,
        "Question": "Which of the following technique is used in quality maintenance?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Benchmarking",
            "b) Employee empowerment",
            "c) Root cause analysis",
            "d) Forecasting"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Planned maintenance leads to a reduction in inventory through better control of wear-prone and failure-prone parts. It is part of the traditional TPM whose foundation is 5S.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 643,
        "Question": "Which of the following pillar of TPM focuses on small groups of employees for incremental improvements in equipment operation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Autonomous maintenance",
            "b) Planned maintenance",
            "c) Quality maintenance",
            "d) Focused improvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Root cause analysis is used in quality maintenance. It eliminates recurring sources of quality defects. Quality maintenance is one of the pillars of traditional TPM.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 644,
        "Question": "Which pillar of TPM utilizes practical knowledge and understanding of the manufacturing equipment in improving the design of new equipment?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Autonomous maintenance",
            "b) Early equipment management",
            "c) Quality maintenance",
            "d) Focused improvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Quality maintenance reduces the number of defects. The important task under this pillar of TPM is to design error detection and prevention into the manufacturing process.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 645,
        "Question": "New equipment designed using the concept of early equipment management will have ____",
        "Options": [
            "a) More startup issues",
            "b) Extremely high startup issues",
            "c) Fewer startup issues",
            "d) Same startup issues as before"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Focused improvement is the pillar of TPM that focuses on small groups of employees for incremental improvements in equipment operation. These groups work together in a proactive manner and often belong to cross-functional teams.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 646,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a health, safety, and environment (HSE) related measure taken at workplace?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Wearing PPE kits for workers",
            "b) Prohibition of use of mobile phones",
            "c) Washing hands before operating any equipment",
            "d) Providing increment in the salary of an employee"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Early equipment management is the pillar of TPM that utilizes practical knowledge and understanding of the manufacturing equipment in improving the design of new equipment. This knowledge is gained through TPM itself.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 647,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an outcome of implementing strict health, safety, and environment-related measures in an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Eliminating health risks",
            "b) Eliminating safety risks",
            "c) Accident-free workplace",
            "d) Increasing safety risks"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: New equipment designed using the concept of early equipment management will have fewer startup issues. Maintenance is simple and robust due to employee involvement and practical review.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 648,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an example of administrative operation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Order processing",
            "b) Drilling a hole in a workpiece",
            "c) Order scheduling",
            "d) Order procurement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Wearing PPE kits for workers, the prohibition of the use of mobile phones, and washing hands before operating any equipment, are all steps and measures related to HSE. An example is the oil and gas industry where strict HSE measures are implemented.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 649,
        "Question": "What does an OEE score of 100% refer to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Perfect production",
            "b) World-class",
            "c) Fairly typical",
            "d) Poor"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Eliminating health risks, eliminating safety risks, and providing an accident-free workplace are the outcomes of implementing strict health, safety, and environment-related measures in an organization. It results in creating a safe and healthy working environment.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 650,
        "Question": "OEE takes into account _____",
        "Options": [
            "a) Availability loss",
            "b) Availability loss and Quality loss",
            "c) Availability loss and Performance loss",
            "d) Availability loss, Performance loss, and Quality loss"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Order processing, scheduling, and procurement are administrative operations that must be improved while TPM is also utilized. TPM can be applied in administrative functions to remove waste in administrative functions.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 651,
        "Question": "In which of the following stages of TPM is the announcement to the top management about the decision to introduce TPM made?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Preliminary implementation stage",
            "b) TPM implementation stage",
            "c) Stabilization stage",
            "d) Preparation stage"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘Preparation stage’ is the first stage in TPM development. There are in total of four major stages in TPM development. The other stages are preliminary implementation stage, TPM implementation stage, and stabilization stage.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 652,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a technique to educate everyone in the organization starting from managers to general workers about TPM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Seminars only",
            "b) Slide presentations only",
            "c) Seminars, slide presentations, retreats",
            "d) Retreats only"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In the ‘preparation stage’, the announcement to the top management about the decision to introduce TPM is made. It is introduced through an internal meeting and must be published in a newsletter or bulletin.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 653,
        "Question": "Which of the following must not be focused on when formulating TPM policies and goals?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Result-oriented",
            "b) Attainable",
            "c) Measurable",
            "d) Unrealistic"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Seminars, slide presentations, retreats are the different ways in which education about TPM can be provided in an organization. Seminars can be offered to the managers while slide presentations can be offered to the general workers.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 654,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a part of holding TPM kick-off?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Announcing to top management about the decision to introduce TPM",
            "b) Invite client companies",
            "c) Invite affiliated companies",
            "d) Invite subcontracting companies"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: While formulating TPM policies and goals care must be taken to make them result-oriented, specific, measurable, attainable, and realistic. The TPM policies and goals must be clear to everyone involved in TPM implementation.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 655,
        "Question": "In which stage in TPM development is the step to improve the effectiveness of each piece of equipment taken?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Preparation stage",
            "b) Preliminary inspection stage",
            "c) TPM implementation stage",
            "d) Stabilization stage"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Inviting client companies, inviting affiliated companies, and inviting subcontracting companies are important tasks performed when holding TPM kick-off. It is part of the preliminary implementation stage.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 656,
        "Question": "In which stage of TPM development the focus is to set higher TPM goals?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Preparation stage",
            "b) Preliminary inspection stage",
            "c) TPM implementation stage",
            "d) Stabilization stage"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In the TPM implementation stage, the step to improve the effectiveness of each piece of equipment taken. In this step, we need to select model equipment and form project teams.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 657,
        "Question": "In which stage of TPM development is the development of the early equipment management program carried out?",
        "Options": [
            "a) TPM implementation stage",
            "b) Preliminary inspection stage",
            "c) Preparation stage",
            "d) Stabilization stage"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In the stabilization stage of TPM development, the focus is to set higher TPM goals. The TPM levels must be raised and TPM needs to be perfectly implemented.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 658,
        "Question": "In which stage of TPM development a scheduled maintenance program for the maintenance department developed?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Stabilization stage",
            "b) Preliminary inspection stage",
            "c) Preparation stage",
            "d) TPM implementation stage"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: In the TPM implementation stage of TPM development, the development of the early equipment management program is carried out. The design, commission, and control of the maintenance prevention program carried out.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 659,
        "Question": "If availability is 85%, performance efficiency is 50%, and the rate of quality products is 98%, then find out the overall equipment effectiveness?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 42%",
            "b) 50%",
            "c) 32%",
            "d) 60%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Overall equipment effectiveness = Availability * Performance efficiency * Rate of quality products = 0.85 * 0.50 * 0.98 = 42%.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 660,
        "Question": "What is the quality score if an asset produces 15000 units out of which 500 are defective?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 92.67%",
            "b) 94.67%",
            "c) 96.67%",
            "d) 98.67%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Quality score = Number of usable units/Total units = 14500/15000 = 96.67%. It is a useful parameter in the calculation of OEE.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 661,
        "Question": "A machine that was supposed to run for 10 hours suffers a breakdown and runs only for 9 hours. Calculate availability.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 89%",
            "b) 90%",
            "c) 91%",
            "d) 92%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Availability=Total run time/Total planned production time = 9/10 = 90%. It is a useful parameter in the calculation of OEE.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 662,
        "Question": "If the loading time is 400 minutes and downtime is 60 minutes, calculate availability.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 81%",
            "b) 83%",
            "c) 85%",
            "d) 87%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Availability = ((Loading Time – Down Time)/Loading Time)*100 = ((400-60)/400)*100 = 85%. Availability, Performance Efficiency, and Quality score are required to calculate OEE.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 663,
        "Question": "If the theoretical cycle time per unit is 0.5 minutes/unit, the number of units is 400, and the operating time is 400 minutes, calculate performance efficiency.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 20%",
            "b) 30%",
            "c) 40%",
            "d) 50%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Performance efficiency is given by the formula:\n((Theoretical cycle time per unit * Number of units)/Operating Time)*100=(0.5*400*100)/400=50%.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 664,
        "Question": "If the overall equipment effectiveness is 40%, availability 82%, quality score 96%, calculate the performance efficiency?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 50.8%",
            "b) 60.8%",
            "c) 70.8%",
            "d) 40.8%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Overall equipment effectiveness = Availability * Performance efficiency * Rate of quality products. Therefore, performance efficiency = (0.40/(0.82*0.96))=50.8%.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 665,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of implementing TPM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Improved equipment reliability",
            "b) Reduced equipment downtime",
            "c) Increased equipment downtime",
            "d) Lower maintenance and production costs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Improved safety is one of the benefits of implementing TPM. The goals of TPM are to aim at zero breakdowns and zero defects.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 666,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of implementing TPM?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Enhanced job satisfaction",
            "b) Zero defects",
            "c) Improved teamwork between operators and maintenance team",
            "d) A decrease in equipment reliability"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: TPM ensures an improved return on investment. The approach of TPM to achieve perfect production through equipment maintenance increases equipment productivity.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 667,
        "Question": "______ is an indicator of the measurement of success in any organization.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Poka-Yoke",
            "b) 5S",
            "c) Performance Measures",
            "d) Benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Performance Measures is an indicator of the measurement of success in any organization. It is quantitative data that measures continuous quality improvement activity in any organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 668,
        "Question": "Which of the following is incorrect according to the seven objectives of performance measures identified by Ray F. Boedecker?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Determination of processes that need improvement",
            "b) Indicating process gains and losses",
            "c) Comparing goals with actual performance",
            "d) Hiding information for making informed decisions"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to Ray F. Boedecker, establishing a baseline measure and revealing trends is one of the objectives of ‘performance measures’. Performance measures are required in any organization to quantify success.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 669,
        "Question": "Which one of the following is not a functional element considered during the performance measure of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customers",
            "b) Poka-yoke",
            "c) Production",
            "d) Suppliers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Determination of processes that need improvement, indicating process gains and losses, and comparing goals with actual performance are few of the seven objectives of performance measures identified by Ray F. Boedecker. It also includes providing information to make informed decisions.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 670,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an indicator of the ‘customer’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Number of customers’ complaints",
            "b) Number of warranty claims",
            "c) Number of suggestions per employee",
            "d) Revenue growth"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to Ray F. Boedecker, providing information for individuals and team evaluation is one of the objectives of ‘performance measures’. To determine the overall performance of the organization is also one of the objectives of the performance measure identified by Ray F. Boedecker.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 671,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a determinant of the ‘customer’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Number of suggestions implemented",
            "b) Customer satisfaction index",
            "c) Percentage returns by customers",
            "d) Service rating"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Customers, production, and suppliers are few of the functional elements considered during the performance measure of an organization. Some of the other functional elements considered during the performance measure of an organization are research and development, human resources, marketing/sales, and administration.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 672,
        "Question": "‘Time to resolve complaints’ is an indicator of which functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customers",
            "b) Production",
            "c) Suppliers",
            "d) Research and Development"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Number of customers’ complaints, the number of warranty claims, and the number of suggestions per employee are some of the indicators of the ‘customer’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. Revenue growth is an indicator of the ‘production’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 673,
        "Question": "Labor productivity is equal to ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Result/material costs",
            "b) Result/labor costs",
            "c) Result/capital costs",
            "d) Revenue growth"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Number of suggestions implemented. Customer satisfaction index and percentage returns by customers are some of the indicators of the ‘customer’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. Service rating is an indicator of the ‘suppliers’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 674,
        "Question": "Effectiveness is equal to _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer satisfaction index",
            "b) Actual result/expected result",
            "c) Revenue growth",
            "d) Result/labor costs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘Time to resolve complaints’ is an indicator of the ‘customer’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. ‘Mean time to repair’ is another example of an indicator of the ‘customer’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 675,
        "Question": "Efficiency is equal to _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Expected costs/actual costs",
            "b) Meantime to repair",
            "c) Labor productivity",
            "d) Actual result/expected result"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Labor productivity is equal to result/labor costs. It is a key indicator of the ‘production’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 676,
        "Question": "Throughput time is equal to ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Processing time+Inspection time",
            "b) Processing time+Inspection time+Movement time",
            "c) Processing time+Inspection time+Movement time+Waiting time",
            "d) Processing time+Inspection time+Waiting time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Throughput time is equal to Processing time+Inspection time+Movement time+Waiting time. It is an important determinant in the ‘production’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 677,
        "Question": "Manufacturing cycle effectiveness is equal to ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Number of failures",
            "b) Processing time/Throughput time",
            "c) Processing time",
            "d) Throughput time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: % rejects and % scrap are important determinants in the ‘production’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. The other functional elements are customers, suppliers, research and development, human resources, marketing/sales, and administration.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 678,
        "Question": "Failure rate is equal to ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) (Number of failures/Total number of products tested)*100",
            "b) Number of failures",
            "c) Total number of products tested",
            "d) Number of breakdowns"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Manufacturing cycle effectiveness is equal to processing time/throughput time. It is an important determinant in the ‘production’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 679,
        "Question": "Quality grade is equal to ___________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Production quantity",
            "b) Number of defects",
            "c) ((Production quantity – Number of defects)/Production quantity)*100",
            "d) Customer satisfaction index/number of defects"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Failure rate is equal to (Number of failures/Total number of products tested)*100. The failure rate is an important determinant in the ‘production’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 680,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a determinant of the ‘suppliers’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Service rating",
            "b) On-time delivery",
            "c) Quality performance",
            "d) Number of breakdowns"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Quality grade is equal to ((Production quantity-Number of defects)/Production quantity)*100. Quality grade is an important determinant in the ‘production’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 681,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an indicator of the ‘suppliers’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) SPC charts",
            "b) Billing accuracy",
            "c) Average lead time",
            "d) Lead time for product development"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Service rating, on-time delivery, and quality performance are few of the determinants of the ‘suppliers’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. The number of breakdowns is an indicator of the ‘production’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 682,
        "Question": "‘Just-in-time delivery target’ is an indicator of which functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Research and development",
            "b) Suppliers",
            "c) Human resources",
            "d) Customers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: SPC charts, billing accuracy, and average lead time are few of the determinants of the ‘suppliers’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. Lead time for product development is an indicator of the ‘production’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 683,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an indicator of the ‘research and development’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) New product time to market",
            "b) The time needed to launch a new product",
            "c) Design change orders",
            "d) Revenue growth"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘Just-in-time delivery target’ is an indicator of the ‘suppliers’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. The other functional elements are customers, production, research and development, human resources, marketing/sales, and administration.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 684,
        "Question": "‘Cost estimating errors’ is an indicator of which functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Research and development",
            "b) Production",
            "c) Human resources",
            "d) Customers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: New product time to market, the time needed to launch a new product, and design change orders are few of the determinants of the ‘research and development’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. Revenue growth is an indicator of the ‘production’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 685,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a determinant of the ‘human resources’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Percentage of personnel turnover",
            "b) Percentage of absence due to illness",
            "c) Employee satisfaction index",
            "d) Average lead time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The percentage of personnel turnover, the percentage of absence due to illness, and employee satisfaction index are some of the determinants of the ‘human resources’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. ‘Average lead time’ is an indicator of the ‘suppliers’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 686,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an indicator of ‘human resources’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Number of training hours per employee",
            "b) Number of active teams",
            "c) Number of suggestions/grievances",
            "d) Material productivity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The number of training hours per employee, the number of active teams, and the number of suggestions/grievances are some of the indicators of the ‘human resources’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. ‘Material productivity’ is an indicator of the ‘production’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 687,
        "Question": "The percentage of safety incidents and the percentage of environmental incidents are indicators of which functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Research and development",
            "b) Suppliers",
            "c) Human resources",
            "d) Customers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The percentage of safety incidents and the percentage of environmental incidents are indicators of the ‘human resources’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. The other functional elements are customers, production, research and development, suppliers, marketing/sales, and administration.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 688,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an indicator of ‘marketing/sales’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sales growth",
            "b) Failure rate",
            "c) Market growth",
            "d) The percentage of delivery completed"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Sales growth, market growth, and the percentage of delivery completed are indicators of the ‘marketing/sales’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. ‘Failure rate’ is an indicator of the ‘production’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 689,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a determinant of the ‘marketing/sales’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Sales expense to revenue",
            "b) New customers",
            "c) Order accuracy",
            "d) Quality grade"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Sales expense to revenue, new customers, and order accuracy are some of the determinants of the ‘marketing/sales’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. ‘Quality grade’ is an indicator of the ‘production’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 690,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a determinant of the ‘administration’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Revenue growth",
            "b) Throughput time",
            "c) Revenue per employee",
            "d) Expense to revenue"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Revenue growth, revenue per employee, and expense to revenue are some of the determinants of the ‘administration’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. ‘Throughput time’ is an indicator of the ‘production’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 691,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an indicator of ‘administration’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Number of breakdowns",
            "b) Cost of poor quality",
            "c) Percentage of payroll distribution on time",
            "d) Office equipment up-time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Cost of poor quality, percentage of payroll distribution on time, and office equipment up-time are some of the determinants of the ‘administration’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. ‘Number of breakdowns’ is an indicator of the ‘production’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 692,
        "Question": "Billing accuracy and invoicing speed are indicators of which functional element while measuring the performance of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Administration",
            "b) Suppliers",
            "c) Human resources",
            "d) Customers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Billing accuracy and invoicing speed are indicators of the ‘administration’ functional element while measuring the performance of an organization. The other functional elements are customers, production, research and development, suppliers, marketing/sales, and human resources.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 693,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a criterion of the performance measures?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Simple",
            "b) Few in number",
            "c) Developed by users",
            "d) Irrelevance to customers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The performance measures must be simple and should focus on having a few numbers of key measures. They must be developed by users and must be relevant to customers.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 694,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a performance measure criterion?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Continuous improvement",
            "b) Cost",
            "c) Transparency",
            "d) Misaligned"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The performance measures must focus on continuous improvement. It must have transparency with proper cost consideration. They must be perfectly aligned with the organization’s goals.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 695,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not fit in the criteria of ‘added value’ in a typical strategic measurement system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increase in revenue per employee",
            "b) Increase in gross added value",
            "c) Increase in net added value",
            "d) % reduction of rejects and scraps"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Increase in revenue per employee, increase in gross added value, and an increase in net added value fit in the criteria of ‘added value’ in the typical strategic measurement system. ‘Added value’ along with productivity, throughput time, and quality form important criteria in a typical strategic measurement system of an organization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 696,
        "Question": " Which of the following does not fit in the criteria of ‘throughput time’ in a typical strategic measurement system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reduction in throughput time",
            "b) Increase in manufacturing cycle effectiveness",
            "c) Reduction in the number of breakdowns",
            "d) Increase in revenue per employee"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Reduction in throughput time, increase in manufacturing cycle effectiveness, and reduction in the number of breakdowns fit in the criteria of ‘throughput time’ in a typical strategic measurement system. ‘Increase in revenue per employee’ is an important indicator in the criteria ‘added value’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 697,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an indicator of ‘throughput time’ in a typical strategic measurement system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increase in availability",
            "b) Increase in invoicing speed",
            "c) Increase in gross added value",
            "d) Reduction in time between order and delivery"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Increase in availability, increase in invoicing speed, and reduction in time between order and delivery are a few of the important indicators of ‘throughput time’ in a typical strategic measurement system. ‘Increase in gross added value’ is an important indicator in the criteria ‘added value’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 698,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an indicator of ‘productivity’ in a typical strategic measurement system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increase in productivity",
            "b) Reduction in throughput time",
            "c) Increase in the effectiveness",
            "d) Increase in the efficiency"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Increase in productivity, an increase in the effectiveness, and an increase in efficiency are a few of the important indicators of ‘productivity’ in a typical strategic measurement system. ‘Reduction in throughput time’ is an important indicator in the criteria ‘throughput time’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 699,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a measure of ‘productivity’ in a typical strategic measurement system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increase in availability",
            "b) Increase in revenue growth",
            "c) Increase in sales and market growth",
            "d) % reduction in personnel turnover"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Increase in revenue growth, increase in sales and market growth, and % reduction in personnel turnover are a few of the important indicators of ‘productivity’ in a typical strategic measurement system. ‘Increase in availability’ is an important indicator in the criteria ‘throughput time’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 700,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a measure of ‘quality’ in a typical strategic measurement system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) % increase in quality grade",
            "b) % reduction in failure rate",
            "c) % reduction in the cost of poor quality",
            "d) Increase in invoicing speed"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: % increase in quality grade, % reduction in failure rate, and % reduction in the cost of poor quality are a few of the important indicators of ‘quality’ in a typical strategic measurement system. ‘Increase in invoicing speed’ is an important indicator in the criteria ‘throughput time’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 701,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an indicator of ‘quality’ in a typical strategic measurement system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reduction in the number of customer complaints",
            "b) % reduction in rejects and scraps",
            "c) % reduction of safety and environmental incidents",
            "d) Reduction in the number of breakdowns"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Reduction in the number of customer complaints, % reduction in rejects and scraps, and % reduction of safety and environmental incident are a few of the important indicators of ‘quality’ in a typical strategic measurement system. ‘Reduction in the number of breakdowns’ is an important indicator in the criteria ‘throughput time’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 702,
        "Question": "Which organization gives the Rajiv Gandhi National Quality Award?",
        "Options": [
            "a) BIS",
            "b) SEBI",
            "c) IRDAI",
            "d) PFRDA"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The Rajiv Gandhi National Quality Award is given by BIS. BIS stands for the Bureau of Indian Standards.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 703,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a criterion included in awarding the Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Leadership",
            "b) Strategic Planning",
            "c) Customer and Market Focus",
            "d) Benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Leadership, Strategic Planning, and Customer and market focus are some of the criteria included in the Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award. It was established in the year 1987.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 704,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a factor included in awarding the Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Information and Analysis",
            "b) Human Resource Focus",
            "c) Process Management",
            "d) Poka Yoke"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Information and analysis, human resource focus, and process management are some of the criteria included in the Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award. It is intended for organizations that demonstrate quality excellence and establish best practice standards.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 705,
        "Question": "Which country gives The Deming Prize?",
        "Options": [
            "a) U.S.A.",
            "b) India",
            "c) Japan",
            "d) South Africa"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Business results in one of the criteria in awarding the Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award. Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award was established in the year 1987.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 706,
        "Question": "In which year was Deming Prize first open for foreign companies?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1950",
            "b) 1960",
            "c) 1984",
            "d) 2000"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The Deming Prize is given by Japan. It is sponsored by Japanese Union of Scientists and Engineers. It was first awarded in 1951.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 707,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an example of an International Quality Award?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Oscars",
            "b) The Deming Prize",
            "c) The European Quality Award",
            "d) Asia-Pacific Area Golden Quality Award"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Deming Prize is named after William Deming. The Japanese consider him an important quality guru and named the award after him.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 708,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an example of a National Quality Award?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Malcolm Baldrige Award",
            "b) UK Excellence Award",
            "c) Golden Peacock Awards",
            "d) The Deming Prize"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The Deming Prize was first open for foreign companies in 1984. Florida Power & Light was the first U.S. Company to receive the award in 1989.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 709,
        "Question": "At which level is the Rajiv Gandhi Quality award given?",
        "Options": [
            "a) National",
            "b) Regional",
            "c) Trade or professional bodies",
            "d) By other companies"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The Deming Prize, the European Quality Award, and Asia-Pacific Area Golden Quality Award are examples of International Quality Awards. Quality awards are given to acknowledge organizations that demonstrate quality excellence and establish best practice standards.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 710,
        "Question": "Which of the following must not be a characteristic of a quality system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It must be well-understood",
            "b) Products or services actually do satisfy customer expectations",
            "c) Emphasis on problem prevention",
            "d) It must be ineffective"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to ISO, the quality system is the organizational structure, responsibilities, procedures, processes, and resources for implementing quality management. ISO refers to the International Organization for Standardization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 711,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of implementing a quality system that conforms to ISO standards?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Improvement in employee involvement",
            "b) Improvement in housekeeping",
            "c) Improvement in customer satisfaction",
            "d) Inefficient decision making"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The characteristics of a quality system must be that it must be well-understood, products or services actually do satisfy customer expectations, and emphasis on problem prevention. It must be effective too.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 712,
        "Question": "Which of the following cannot be considered a reason for implementing a quality system that conforms to ISO standards?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Improvement in safe working",
            "b) Reduction in customer complaints",
            "c) Increased inspection efforts",
            "d) Decreased inspection efforts"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: A quality system is involved in all phases from initial identification to final satisfaction of requirements and meeting customer satisfaction. It is applied to all activities that focus on the quality of product/service.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 713,
        "Question": "Which of the following represents India in ISO?",
        "Options": [
            "a) PFRDA",
            "b) FSSAI",
            "c) BIS",
            "d) BCCI"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Improvement in employee involvement, improvement in housekeeping, and improvement in customer satisfaction are some of the advantages of implementing a quality system that conforms to ISO standards. Decision making based on facts and data also improves.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 714,
        "Question": "Which is the latest ISO 9001 version in the ISO 9000 family?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ISO 9001:1994",
            "b) ISO 9001:2000",
            "c) ISO 9001:2008",
            "d) ISO 9001:2015"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Improvement in safe working, reduction in customer complaints, and a decrease in inspection efforts are some of the reasons for implementing a quality system that conforms to ISO standards. Quality costs also reduce.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 715,
        "Question": "Which of the following is/are the advantage(s) of using the ISO 9001 standard?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Organizing processes",
            "b) Improving the efficiency of processes",
            "c) Continuous improvement",
            "d) Organizing processes, improving the efficiency of processes, and continuous improvement"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: BIS represents India in ISO. It is known as the Bureau of Indian Standards. It is the National Standards Body of India and is a founding member of the ISO.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 716,
        "Question": "Which is the only standard in the ISO 9000 family to which organizations can certify?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ISO 9000",
            "b) ISO 9001",
            "c) ISO 14000",
            "d) ISO 9004"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The latest version of the international standard ISO 9001 is the 2015 version which is known as ISO 9001:2015. The first edition of ISO 9001 was released in 1987.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 717,
        "Question": "Which ISO standard provides guidelines for auditing management systems?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ISO 19011:2018",
            "b) ISO 9000:2015",
            "c) ISO 9001:2015",
            "d) ISO 9004:2018"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The advantages of the international standard ISO 9001 are organizing processes, improving the efficiency of processes, and continuous improvement. It can be applied to any organization regardless of size and industry.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 718,
        "Question": "Which ISO 9000 family standard provides the fundamentals and vocabulary for quality management systems?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ISO 19011:2018",
            "b) ISO 9000:2015",
            "c) ISO 9001:2015",
            "d) ISO 9004:2018"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The only standard in the ISO 9000 family to which organizations can certify is the ISO 9001. The latest version of it is the ISO 9001:2015.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 719,
        "Question": "Which is the latest ISO 9000 version in the ISO 9000 family?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ISO 9000:1987",
            "b) ISO 9000:2000",
            "c) ISO 19011:2018",
            "d) ISO 9000:2015"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The ISO 19011: 2018 provides guidelines for auditing management systems. It is applicable to organizations.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 720,
        "Question": "Which ISO standard provides guidance to achieve sustained success and the continuous improvement of an organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ISO 19011:2018",
            "b) ISO 9000:2015",
            "c) ISO 9001:2015",
            "d) ISO 9004:2018"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The ISO 9000:2015 is the standard in the ISO 9000 family that provides the fundamentals and vocabulary for quality management systems. It was first published in 1987.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 721,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a quality management principle on the basis of which ISO 9000:2015 and ISO 9001:2015 are based on?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Customer focus",
            "b) Leadership",
            "c) Customer dissatisfaction",
            "d) Evidence based decision making"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The latest ISO 9000 version in the ISO 9000 family is the ISO 9000:2015. The other standards in the ISO 9000 family are the ISO 9001:2015 and ISO 9004:2018.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 722,
        "Question": "ISO 14000 standards are for the _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Quality Management System",
            "b) Environmental Management System",
            "c) Administration",
            "d) Supply chain"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ISO 14000 standards are for the Environmental Management System. It is either at the organization and process level or product level.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 723,
        "Question": "In which year did the ISO create the ISO 14000 family of standards?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1956",
            "b) 1966",
            "c) 1978",
            "d) 1996"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: In 1996, ISO created the ISO 14000 family of standards. ISO refers to the International Organization for Standardization.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 724,
        "Question": "Which is the first environmental management system standard?",
        "Options": [
            "a) BS 7750",
            "b) ISO 9000",
            "c) ISO 9001",
            "d) ISO 9004"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: BS 7750 is the first environmental management system standard. It was published in 1992 by BSI group.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 725,
        "Question": "In which year did the current revision of ISO 14001 get published?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 2010",
            "b) 2011",
            "c) 2015",
            "d) 2016"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The current revision of ISO 14001 was published in 2015. ISO 14001 also underwent a revision in 2004.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 726,
        "Question": "Which one of the following is not within the purview of ISO 14000 family of standards?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Environmental management system",
            "b) Environment auditing",
            "c) Life-cycle assessment",
            "d) Quality management system"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Environmental management system, environment auditing, and life-cycle assessment are within the purview of ISO 14000 family of standards. In addition to this, environmental performance evaluation and environmental aspects in product standards are also considered.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 727,
        "Question": "Which one of the following does not belong to the area of Organization Evaluation Standards in ISO 14000 series?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Environmental management system",
            "b) Environmental auditing",
            "c) Environmental performance evaluation",
            "d) Environmental labels and declarations"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Environmental management system, environmental auditing, and environmental performance evaluation belong to the area of Organization Evaluation Standards in ISO 14000 series. ISO 14000 series is broadly divided into two areas, Organization Evaluation Standards and Product Evaluation Standards.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 728,
        "Question": "Which of the following pair of ISO 14000 standards fall under the category of Environmental Management System?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ISO 14001 and ISO 14004",
            "b) ISO 14010 and ISO 14001",
            "c) ISO 14011 and ISO 14001",
            "d) ISO 14011 and ISO 14004"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Environmental aspects in product standards belong to the area of Product Evaluation Standards in ISO 14000 series. Life cycle assessment also belongs to the area of Product Evaluation Standards in ISO 14000 series.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 729,
        "Question": "Which of the following pair of ISO 14000 standards fall under the category of Environmental Auditing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ISO 14001 and ISO 14004",
            "b) ISO 14010 and ISO 14011",
            "c) ISO 14011 and ISO 14001",
            "d) ISO 14012 and ISO 14004"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ISO 14001 and ISO 14004 are the pair of ISO 14000 standards which fall under the category of Environmental Management System. ISO 14001 refers to Environmental Management Systems specifications and ISO 14004 refers to Environmental Management Systems guidelines on principles, systems, and supporting techniques.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 730,
        "Question": "Which ISO 14000 series standard refers to the guidelines on Environmental Performance Evaluation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ISO 14001",
            "b) ISO 14004",
            "c) ISO 14010",
            "d) ISO 14031"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ISO 14010 and ISO 14011 are the pair of ISO 14000 standards that fall under the category of Environmental Auditing. ISO 14010 refers to general principles on environmental auditing and ISO 14011 refers to the audit procedures.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 731,
        "Question": "Which of the following pair of ISO 14000 standards fall under the category of Environmental Labelling?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ISO 14001 and ISO 14004",
            "b) ISO 14010 and ISO 14011",
            "c) ISO 14020 and ISO 14021",
            "d) ISO 14012 and ISO 14020"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ISO 14012 refers to qualification criteria for environmental auditors. It falls under the category of Environmental Auditing.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 732,
        "Question": "Which of the following pair of ISO 14000 standards belong to the category of Environmental Labelling?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ISO 14022 and ISO 14023",
            "b) ISO 14001 and ISO 14004",
            "c) ISO 14001 and ISO 14021",
            "d) ISO 14012 and ISO 14020"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: ISO 14031 refers to the guidelines on Environmental Performance Evaluation. It falls under the category of environmental performance evaluation.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 733,
        "Question": "Which of the following pair of ISO 14000 standards belong to the category of Life Cycle Assessment?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ISO 14041 and ISO 14023",
            "b) ISO 14041 and ISO 14004",
            "c) ISO 14040 and ISO 14041",
            "d) ISO 14040 and ISO 14020"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ISO 14020 and ISO 14021 are the pair of ISO 14000 standards that fall under the category of Environmental Labelling. ISO 14020 refers to the basic principles for environmental labelling and ISO 14021 refers to the self-declaration of environmental claims.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 734,
        "Question": "Which of the following pair of ISO 14000 standards fall under the category of Life Cycle Assessment?",
        "Options": [
            "a) ISO 14041 and ISO 14023",
            "b) ISO 14041 and ISO 14004",
            "c) ISO 14042 and ISO 14043",
            "d) ISO 14040 and ISO 14020"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ISO 14022 and ISO 14023 are the pair of ISO 14000 standards that fall under the category of Environmental Labelling. ISO 14022 refers to the symbols and ISO 14023 refers to the testing and verification.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 735,
        "Question": "The reliability of the entire system is called ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Partial reliability",
            "b) Isolated reliability",
            "c) Closed reliability",
            "d) System reliability"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Reliability is a measure of how quality changes over time. Quality shows us how well the product or service performs its intended function, but reliability shows how well the product or service retain its original level of quality over a period of time.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 736,
        "Question": "System reliability for components kept in series _______ as the number of components increases.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increases",
            "b) Decreases",
            "c) Remains unchanged",
            "d) Cannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Reliability is the probability of a system or service to perform its intended function satisfactorily over a specific period of time under specific conditions. The keywords are probability, intended function, satisfactorily, specific period of time, and specific conditions.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 737,
        "Question": "System reliability for components kept in parallel ______ as the number of components increases.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increases",
            "b) Decreases",
            "c) Remains unchanged",
            "d) Cannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The reliability of the entire system is called system reliability. A system is the collection of items such as subsystems, components, units, blocks etc.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 738,
        "Question": "In series configuration of five components, the entire system will fail if ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) any two components fail",
            "b) any three components fail",
            "c) any one of the components fail",
            "d) any four components fail"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: System reliability for components kept in series decreases as the number of components increases. In this case, the system reliability is always less than the lowest value of reliability of any component.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 739,
        "Question": "In parallel configuration of five components, the entire system will fail if _____",
        "Options": [
            "a) any two components fail",
            "b) any three components fail",
            "c) all the components fail",
            "d) any one components fail"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: System reliability for components kept in parallel increases as the number of components increases. In this case, the system reliability is always more than the highest value of reliability of any component.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 740,
        "Question": "The life-test sample plans that are terminated when a pre-assigned number of failures occur in the sample is _____",
        "Options": [
            "a) Failure-terminated",
            "b) Time-terminated",
            "c) Operation-terminated",
            "d) Sequential"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In series configuration of five components, the entire system will fail if any one of the components fail. The entire system will work satisfactorily only if all the components work without fail.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 741,
        "Question": "What does the graph of ‘bathtub curve’ represent?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Failure rate v/s Mean",
            "b) Failure rate v/s Time",
            "c) Failure rate v/s Distance",
            "d) Failure rate v/s Velocity"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: In parallel configuration of five components, the entire system will fail if all the components fail. The system will work satisfactorily even when any one of the parallel components fail.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 742,
        "Question": "A system consists of four components in series with two components having reliability of 0.9 and two others having reliability of 0.8 at the end of one year. What is the system reliability at the end of one year?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.9000",
            "b) 0.8000",
            "c) 0.7000",
            "d) 0.5184"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The reliability of the system at the end of one year is given by R(s)=R1*R2*R3*R4. So, R(s)=0.9*0.9*0.8*0.8=0.5184.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 743,
        "Question": "A production line is using five robots for its daily operations. If each robot has a reliability of 0.95, what is the total system reliability?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.7737",
            "b) 0.9500",
            "c) 0.9000",
            "d) 1.0000"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The reliability of the system is given by R(s)=R1*R2*R3*R4*R5. So, R(s)=0.95*0.95*0.95*0.95*0.95, or R(s)=0.7737.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 744,
        "Question": "If the system reliability of five robots in a production line is 0.95, what is the individual reliability?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.9354",
            "b) 0.6535",
            "c) 0.9897",
            "d) 0.8143"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The system reliability of five robots in a production line is 0.95. The reliability of the system is given by R(s)=R1*R2*R3*R4*R5. Therefore, R(x)5=0.95, or R(x)=0.9897.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 745,
        "Question": "A system consists of four components in parallel with two components having reliability of 0.9 and two others having reliability of 0.8 at the end of one year. What is the system reliability at the end of one year?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.9996",
            "b) 0.8000",
            "c) 0.7000",
            "d) 0.5180"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: System reliability for parallel components is given by R(s)=1-[(1-R1)2(1-R2)2] or, R(s)=1-[(1-0.9)2(1-0.8)2] = 0.9996.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 746,
        "Question": "For a 2-out-of-3 system, each component has reliability of 0.9. What is the reliability of the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.942",
            "b) 0.854",
            "c) 0.972",
            "d) 0.999"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: The reliability of the system is given by R(s)=P(X=2)+P(X=3), or R(s)=(3C2)(0.9)2(0.1)1+(3C3)(0.9)3(0.1)0=0.243+0.729=0.972.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 747,
        "Question": "For a 3-out-of-4 system, each component has reliability of 0.97. What is the reliability of the system?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.9148",
            "b) 0.9248",
            "c) 0.9448",
            "d) 0.9947"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The reliability of the system is given by R(s)=P(X=3)+P(X=4), or R(s)=(4C3)(0.97)3(0.03)1+(4C4)(0.97)4(0.03)0=0.1095+0.8852=0.9947.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 748,
        "Question": "If the failure rate of the system is 0.000128 units, what is the mean time to fail?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 7812.5 units",
            "b) 7830.5 units",
            "c) 4530.5 units",
            "d) 9821.5 units"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: If the failure rate of the system is given by MTTF = 1/λs=1/0.000128, or MTTF=7812.5 units. MTTF refers to the mean time to fail.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 749,
        "Question": "If the failure rate is 6.67 x 10-6 failures/hr, calculate reliability for a period of 1000 hours.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 98.45%",
            "b) 99.34%",
            "c) 97.56%",
            "d) 94.67%"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reliability is given by R(t)=e-λt. Here, t=1000 hours and λ=6.67×10-6 failures/hr. So, reliability=99.34%.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 750,
        "Question": "If the time to fail for 3 components are 807, 820, and 810, calculate mean time to failure.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 808.34",
            "b) 810.34",
            "c) 812.34",
            "d) 814.34"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: If the time to fail for 3 components are 807, 820, and 810, then\nMTTF=(807+820+810)/3=812.34 hrs. MTTF refers to the mean time to fail.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 751,
        "Question": "If the reliability is 0.3012 and the period of 1000 hours, calculate failure rate per hour.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 0.0010",
            "b) 0.0012",
            "c) 0.0014",
            "d) 0.0016"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The reliability is given by R(t)=e-λt. If t=1000 hours, R=0.3012, then, λ=0.0012 failures/hr.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 752,
        "Question": "Who is the father of Toyota Production System (TPS)?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Ohno",
            "b) Deming",
            "c) Crosby",
            "d) Taguchi"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The father of Toyota Production System is Ohno. The concept of Toyota Production System is popularly known as Lean Manufacturing in North America.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 753,
        "Question": "Mura and Muri refer to _____ and _____ respectively.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Unevenness, waste",
            "b) Unevenness, overburden",
            "c) Overburden, waste",
            "d) Overburden, poka-yoke"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: ‘Muda’ refers to waste in Japan. The seven types of wastes were categorized by Taiichi Ohno.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 754,
        "Question": "Inspection and safety testing are examples of Muda ____",
        "Options": [
            "a) Type 4",
            "b) Type 3",
            "c) Type 2",
            "d) Type 1"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Mura and Muri refer to unevenness and overburden respectively. The concept of Lean has been developed around eliminating the three types of deviations showing inefficient allocation of resources.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 755,
        "Question": "Which of the following terms in the seven types of wastes categorized by Ohno considers the movement of product between manufacturing processes as no value-addition task, expensive and can cause damage to the product?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Overproduction",
            "b) Waiting",
            "c) Transportation",
            "d) Excessive inventory"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Muda Type 1 refers to non-value-added activities in the processes that are important for the end customer. Muda Type 2 refers to non-value-added activities in the processes that are unnecessary for the end customer.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 756,
        "Question": "Which of the following terms in the seven types of wastes categorized by Ohno considers the waiting of one process to begin while the other one gets over?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Overproduction",
            "b) Waiting",
            "c) Transportation",
            "d) Excessive inventory"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Inspection and safety testing are examples of Muda Type 1. They do not add any value to the final product but are necessary for the end customer.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 757,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not belong to the seven types of wastes categorized by Ohno?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Inappropriate processing",
            "b) Excess inventory",
            "c) Unnecessary motion",
            "d) Quality"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: ‘Transportation’ refers to the movement of product between manufacturing processes as no value-addition task, expensive and can cause damage to the product. It should be avoided as much as possible.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 758,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a visual and/or audible communication system that calls for support or attention in a process whenever needed?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Poka-yoke",
            "b) Benchmarking",
            "c) Andon",
            "d) Muda"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘Waiting’ refers to the waiting of one process to begin while the other one gets over. Operations flow must be smooth and continuous.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 759,
        "Question": "Which philosophy tells us that we need to go out of the office and visit the plant floor where the real action occurs?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Benchmarking",
            "b) FMEA",
            "c) Gemba",
            "d) Andon"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Inappropriate processing, excess inventory, and unnecessary motion belong to the seven types of wastes categorized by Ohno. Defects also belong to the seven types of wastes categorized by Ohno.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 760,
        "Question": "Which of the following refers to ‘Level Scheduling’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Andon",
            "b) Muda",
            "c) Heijunka",
            "d) Muri"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Heijunka is a Japanese word that refers to ‘Level Scheduling’. It reduces lead time and inventory.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 761,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of Heijunka?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Predictability",
            "b) Flexibility",
            "c) Stability",
            "d) Uncertainty"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Predictability, Flexibility, and Stability are the benefits of Heijunka. It helps in avoiding inefficiencies in manufacturing by putting production close to customer demand.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 762,
        "Question": "Calculate Takt Time when there are 500 minutes in work day and the customer demand is 500 units a day.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 1 minute",
            "b) 2 minutes",
            "c) 3 minutes",
            "d) 4 minutes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Takt Time = Net available work time / Customer demand, or, Takt time=500/500=1 minute. Takt Time is an important parameter measured in lean manufacturing.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 763,
        "Question": "Which of the following is the meaning of the word HoshinKanri which is extensively used in strategic planning?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Visual communication",
            "b) Policy deployment",
            "c) Audio communication",
            "d) Benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: HoshinKanri refers to policy deployment. It is utilized for ensuring that the strategic goals of the company is driven by progress and action at every level within the company.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 764,
        "Question": "In HoshinKanri, the tactics are laid out by ________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Top management",
            "b) Middle management",
            "c) Supervisors",
            "d) Team Leaders"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: HoshinKanri eliminates wastes that originate from poor communication and inconsistent direction. It is a progress and action driven strategic planning method.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 765,
        "Question": "Which of the following wastes is not eliminated by implementation of continuous flow?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Inventory",
            "b) Waiting time",
            "c) Transport",
            "d) Quality"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The implementation of HoshinKanri begins with a strategic plan. It is developed by top management. The plan should focus on effectiveness. It can be evolutionary or revolutionary.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 766,
        "Question": "Continuous flow is a technique of manufacturing where work-in-process smoothly flows through production with ______ buffers between various steps of the manufacturing process.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Minimal or no",
            "b) Maximum",
            "c) Sometimes minimal",
            "d) Cannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In HoshinKanri, the tactics are laid out by middle management. Supervisors and team leaders at the plant floor level work out the operational details needed in implementing tactics.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 767,
        "Question": "Bottleneck analysis ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reduces throughput",
            "b) Decreases throughput",
            "c) Improves throughput",
            "d) Cannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The implementation of continuous flow leads to elimination of wastes like inventory, waiting time, and transport. Quality is a desired characteristic.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 768,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not related with JIT implementation?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Pull System",
            "b) Push System",
            "c) Zero inventory",
            "d) Zero lead time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Yes, JIT is a long-term approach to process improvement. It requires enormous commitment and it takes a lot of time before it gets implemented correctly.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 769,
        "Question": "MRP is a ____ system and JIT is a _____ system.",
        "Options": [
            "a) pull, pull",
            "b) push, push",
            "c) push, pull",
            "d) pull, push"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: JIT is a pull system. On successful implementation of JIT, the production system inherits the concepts of zero inventory and zero lead time.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 770,
        "Question": "Which of the following are not results of successful implementation of JIT?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Improved quality",
            "b) Sporadic improvement of productivity",
            "c) Elimination of waste",
            "d) Reduction in cost of operations"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: MRP is a push system and JIT is a pull system. JIT refers to Just-in-time and MRP refers to Materials Requirement Planning.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 771,
        "Question": "According to conventional approach, inventory is ______ and according to JIT, inventory is ______",
        "Options": [
            "a) necessary, unnecessary",
            "b) unnecessary, necessary",
            "c) necessary, necessary",
            "d) unnecessary, unnecessary"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: On successful implementation of JIT, a production system has improved quality, waste elimination, and reduction in cost of operations. It also achieves continuous improvement of productivity.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 772,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a principle of JIT manufacturing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Total Quality Management",
            "b) Production Management",
            "c) MRP",
            "d) Supplier Management"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to conventional approach, inventory is necessary and according to JIT, inventory is unnecessary. JIT refers to the Just-in-Time manufacturing approach.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 773,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of JIT?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Reduction in throughput time",
            "b) Improvement in quality",
            "c) Improvement in productivity",
            "d) High reliance on suppliers"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to JIT, balanced production is efficient. It considers faster production than necessary as a waste.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 774,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a disadvantage of JIT?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Danger of lost sales",
            "b) Danger of disrupted production",
            "c) Less time for quality control",
            "d) Greater flexibility"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Total quality management, production management, and supplier management are principles of JIT manufacturing. In addition, inventory management and human resource management are also essential.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 775,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of JIT?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Greater flexibility",
            "b) Workforce participation",
            "c) May lose bulk-buying discounts",
            "d) Simplified scheduling and control"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Reduction in throughput time, improvement in quality, and improvement in productivity are benefits of JIT. High reliance on suppliers is a disadvantage of JIT.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 776,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of JIT?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Time-based competition",
            "b) Increased ordering costs",
            "c) Streamline manufacturing operations",
            "d) Reduced cost of scrap"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Danger of lost sales, danger of disrupted production due to non-arrival of supplies, less time for quality control on arrival of material are the disadvantages of JIT. JIT provides greater flexibility which is an advantage.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 777,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of JIT?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Better utilization of personnel",
            "b) Reduced space requirements",
            "c) High transaction costs",
            "d) Reduced inventory"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Greater flexibility, workforce participation, and simplified scheduling and control are the advantages of JIT. The aspect of losing bulk-buying discounts is a disadvantage of JIT.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 778,
        "Question": "Which of the following means ‘visual cards’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Poka-yoke",
            "b) 5S",
            "c) Muda",
            "d) Kanban"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Kanban means visual cards. It is a visual aid that triggers action. Kanban is utilized in lean manufacturing and just-in-time manufacturing.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 779,
        "Question": "C-Kanban is also known as _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) P- Kanban",
            "b) Production Kanban",
            "c) Withdrawal Kanban",
            "d) Poka-Yoke"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: C-Kanban is also known as Withdrawal Kanban. ‘C’ stands for conveyance in C-Kanban.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 780,
        "Question": "Calculate number of Kanbans if the hourly demand is 200 units, lead time is 12 hours, container capacity is 144 units, and variation in lead time is 15%.",
        "Options": [
            "a) 23",
            "b) 22",
            "c) 21",
            "d) 20"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Withdrawal Kanban is also known as Move Kanban. Conveyance Kanban, Withdrawal Kanban and Move Kanban all mean the same.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 781,
        "Question": "_______ signals the need to produce more parts and ______ signals the need to deliver more parts to the next work center.",
        "Options": [
            "a) P-Kanban, C-Kanban",
            "b) P-Kanban, P-Kanban",
            "c) C-Kanban, C-Kanban",
            "d) C-Kanban, P-Kanban"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: P-Kanban is also known as Production Kanban. P-Kanban and C-Kanban are the two main types of Kanban cards.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 782,
        "Question": "Which of the following does not belong to the five principles of lean?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Identifying Value",
            "b) Mapping the value stream",
            "c) Creating flow",
            "d) Establishing push"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Number of Kanban is given by the formula DT(1+x)/C. So, number of Kanban=((200*12)(1+0.15))/144=20.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 783,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an example of visual factory tools?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Visual indicators",
            "b) Visual displays",
            "c) Visual controls",
            "d) Benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: P-Kanban signals the need to produce more parts and C-Kanban signals the need to deliver more parts to the next work center. P-Kanban and C-Kanban are the two main types of Kanban cards.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 784,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of a visual factory?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Safer workplace",
            "b) Improved productivity",
            "c) Lower profits",
            "d) Improved output"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: The five key principles of lean were given by Womack and Jones. They are identifying value, mapping the value stream, creating flow, establishing pull, and seeking perfection.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 785,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of one-piece flow used in production?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Early detection of defects",
            "b) Flexibility for customization",
            "c) Reduction of amount of work in progress",
            "d) Inflexible in meeting customer demands"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: One-piece flow is also known as single-piece flow in manufacturing. It is quite common in lean organizations.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 786,
        "Question": "Which of the following refers to the term ‘autonomation’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Poka-yoke",
            "b) Jidoka",
            "c) Andon",
            "d) 5S"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Early detection of defects, flexibility for customization, and flexibility in meeting customer demands are the advantages of one-piece flow used in production in lean organizations. It also reduces the amount of work in progress.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 787,
        "Question": "Which of the following refers to ‘automation with a human touch’?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Autonomation",
            "b) Automation",
            "c) Kaizen",
            "d) Benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: The term Jidoka refers to ‘autonomation’. It is widely used in the Toyota Production System and Lean Manufacturing.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 788,
        "Question": "The first step in applying Jidoka is _______",
        "Options": [
            "a) Discovering abnormality",
            "b) Stopping the process",
            "c) Fixing the immediate problem",
            "d) Investigating and solving the root cause"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Autonomation refers to ‘automation with a human touch’. It is also described as ‘intelligent automation’.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 789,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the aim of demand management?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Improving forecast accuracy",
            "b) Lessen investment in inventory",
            "c) Creation of effective balance between demand and supply",
            "d) Increase investment in inventory"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: The first step in applying Jidoka is discovering abnormality followed by stopping the process. After this, the immediate problem is fixed. At the end, investigation and solving the root cause is done.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 790,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a type of plant layout in which machines and equipment are arranged according to their function?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cellular layout",
            "b) Process layout",
            "c) Fixed position layout",
            "d) Combined layout"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Improving forecast accuracy, lessen investment in inventory, and creation of effective balance between demand and supply are the primary goals of demand management. It is a lean tool.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 791,
        "Question": "Which type of plant layout utilizes the merits of both process and product layout?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Product layout",
            "b) Fixed position layout",
            "c) Process layout",
            "d) Combined layout"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In process layout, machines and equipment are arranged according to their function. For example, the drilling department, paint department etc.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 792,
        "Question": "In which type of plant layout machines are grouped into cells?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Fixed position layout",
            "b) Cellular layout",
            "c) Combined layout",
            "d) Process layout"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Combined layout utilizes the merits of both process and product layout. It is also known as hybrid layout.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 793,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of cellular manufacturing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increases flexibility",
            "b) Increases transparency",
            "c) Decreases overall productivity",
            "d) Reduces changeover time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: In cellular layout, machines are grouped into cells. It is commonly used in lean organizations.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 794,
        "Question": "Which type of plant layout is also known as static layout?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Process layout",
            "b) Cellular layout",
            "c) Product layout",
            "d) Fixed position layout."
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: Cellular manufacturing increases flexibility. It introduces transparency. It reduces changeover time. In addition, it also increases productivity.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 795,
        "Question": "Cellular manufacturing _______ teamwork and communication between employees and departments.",
        "Options": [
            "a) enhances",
            "b) depreciates",
            "c) reduces",
            "d) obstructs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Product layout is generally used for standardized goods. The process layout is generally used for customized goods.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 796,
        "Question": "___ is a tool for monitoring how lean principles are working in an organization.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Poka-yoke",
            "b) Andon",
            "c) Gemba",
            "d) Lean Audit"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Lean Audit is a tool for monitoring how lean principles are working in an organization. It can help you identify wastes in the organization and the need to eliminate them.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 797,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a goal of lean audit?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Improve overall efficiency",
            "b) Increase waste",
            "c) Reduce waste",
            "d) Lower production costs"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Improving overall efficiency, reducing waste and lowering production costs are the goals of lean audit. Lean audits ideally should be performed by a third party.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 798,
        "Question": "Which lean philosophy says that things must be done right the first time and every time?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Gemba",
            "b) Right First Time",
            "c) Poka-Yoke",
            "d) Kanban"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ‘Right First Time’ is a lean philosophy that says that things must be done right the first time and every time. The implementation of this concept requires deep understanding of manufacturing processes and involves planning.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 799,
        "Question": "According to SMART goals, what does the letter ‘S’ refer to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Smart",
            "b) Standard",
            "c) Subject",
            "d) Specific"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: According to SMART goals, the letter ‘S’ stands for ‘specific’. It means that a goal must be based on actual facts and figures and must be concrete.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 800,
        "Question": "According to SMART goals, what does the letter ‘M’ refer to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Multiple",
            "b) Measurable",
            "c) Magnitude",
            "d) Medium"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: According to SMART goals, the letter ‘M’ stands for ‘measurable’. It means results must be measurable and quantified.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 801,
        "Question": "According to SMART goals, what does the letter ‘A’ refer to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Abstract",
            "b) Attainable",
            "c) Ask",
            "d) Abstain"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: According to SMART goals, the letter ‘A’ stands for attainable. It means goals must be realistic and be attainable. If they are impossible in nature, it can also hurt employee morale.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 802,
        "Question": "According to SMART goals, what does the letter ‘R’ refer to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Realistic",
            "b) Range",
            "c) Refrain",
            "d) Retain"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to SMART goals, the letter ‘R’ stands for realistic. With the given available resources and time, goals must be realistic and achievable.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 803,
        "Question": "According to SMART goals, what does the letter ‘T’ refer to?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Time-based",
            "b) Train",
            "c) Tough",
            "d) Try"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: According to SMART goals, the letter ‘T’ refers to time-based. A realistic date for task completion must be realized without being too ambitious and considering the given available resources and time.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 804,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of SMED?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Lower manufacturing cost",
            "b) Smaller lot sizes",
            "c) Lower inventory levels",
            "d) Larger lot sizes"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: SMED stands for Single-Minute Exchange of Dies. It is a system for reducing equipment changeover time.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 805,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a tool utilized to visually map the flow of production?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Gemba",
            "b) Automation",
            "c) Value Stream Mapping",
            "d) Benchmarking"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: SMED aims to convert as many changeover steps as possible to external operations. External elements refer to operations that can be completed while the equipment is running.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 806,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a workplace efficiency tool designed to combine product flow and information flow along with any other useful data?",
        "Options": [
            "a) 5S",
            "b) Seven Wastes",
            "c) Value Stream Mapping",
            "d) Poka-Yoke"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Lower manufacturing cost, smaller lot sizes, and lower inventory level are benefits of SMED. It improves responsiveness to customer demand and leads to smoother startups.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 807,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of IIoT?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Faster decision making",
            "b) Better decision making",
            "c) Better understanding of business processes",
            "d) Lack of employee motivation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: IIoT refers to the Industrial Internet of Things. It refers to all the industrial devices that contain sensors and are connected to wireless networks. It allows data accumulation and sharing.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 808,
        "Question": "IIoT can be used in manufacturing industries to understand when machines need servicing which _____ downtime.",
        "Options": [
            "a) reduces",
            "b) increases",
            "c) remain the same",
            "d) cannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Faster decision making, better decision making, and better understanding of business processes are some of the benefits of IIoT. In a progressive atmosphere like that in an agile organization workers feel very motivated.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 809,
        "Question": "IIoT can be used in utilities industries to  ______ the cost of sending staff to remote areas by self-monitoring.",
        "Options": [
            "a) decrease",
            "b) increase",
            "c) sometimes decrease",
            "d) cannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: IIoT can be used in manufacturing industries to understand when machines need servicing which reduces downtime. It can also be used in the manufacturing industry to get a better idea about production lines.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 810,
        "Question": "ERP refers to _________",
        "Options": [
            "a) Efficient Resource Planning",
            "b) Enterprise Resource Planning",
            "c) Engineering Resource Planning",
            "d) Effective Resource Planning"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: IIoT can be used in utilities industries to decrease the cost of sending staff to remote areas by self-monitoring. IIoT refers to the Industrial Internet of Things.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 811,
        "Question": "AR and VR refers to ______ respectively.",
        "Options": [
            "a) augmented reality, virtual reality",
            "b) artificial reality, virtual reality",
            "c) artificial reality, viscous reality",
            "d) augmented reality, viscous reality"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Transport companies can use IIoT to monitor their vehicle fleet. Retailers can also use IIoT to detect bottlenecks in supply chain.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 812,
        "Question": "AR and VR can ______ inspection time in industries.",
        "Options": [
            "a) decrease",
            "b) increase",
            "c) either decrease or increase",
            "d) cannot be determined"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: ERP refers to Enterprise Resource Planning. It helps in creating a lean and competitive advantage.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 813,
        "Question": "AR and VR can _____ in error detection in industries.",
        "Options": [
            "a) create hurdles",
            "b) create problems",
            "c) assist",
            "d) create bottlenecks"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: AR and VR refers to augmented reality and virtual reality respectively. These technologies are getting implemented and are considered as part of the latest trends in manufacturing.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 814,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of 3D printing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) It is faster",
            "b) It is expensive",
            "c) It is cost-effective",
            "d) It takes a lot of time"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: AR and VR can decrease inspection time in industries. AR refers to augmented reality and VR refers to virtual reality.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 815,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a term referring to the requirement of protection against ransomware and malware as more and more devices get integrated in manufacturing industries?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Cybersecurity",
            "b) 3D Printing",
            "c) Augmented Reality",
            "d) Virtual reality"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: c\nExplanation: AR and VR can assist in error detection in industries. These latest technologies are finding extensive use in different industries and help the workers in completing their tasks faster.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 816,
        "Question": "Which among the following is not a term that can be associated with a smart factory?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Automation",
            "b) Artificial intelligence",
            "c) Extremely labor intensive",
            "d) IIoT"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: 3D printing is faster, less expensive. It is also cost-effective. It is extensively used by product designers for testing and troubleshooting purposes.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 817,
        "Question": "Which of the following is a virtual representation of a real-world product or asset?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Poka-Yoke",
            "b) Andon",
            "c) Digital Twin",
            "d) 5S"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Cybersecurity refers to the requirement of protection against ransomware and malware as more and more devices get integrated in manufacturing industries. It is a major concern for companies of all types and sizes.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 818,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not associated with Agile Manufacturing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Operational Flexibility",
            "b) Bottom-up innovation",
            "c) Operator augmentation",
            "d) Slow approach"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Agile manufacturing focuses on operational flexibility, bottom-up innovation, and operator augmentation. It also emphasizes on rapid iteration.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 819,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an example of changing customer expectations which essentially leads us to focus on agile manufacturing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Product customization",
            "b) Slow delivery",
            "c) Fast delivery",
            "d) Cheaper production"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Agile Manufacturing focuses on faster response to customer demands. It does so while empowering workers to innovate.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 820,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a reason for organizations switching to agile manufacturing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Constant technological development",
            "b) Increasing complex supply chain",
            "c) Higher customer standards",
            "d) Increased manpower"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: We are having changes not only in technology but also in customer expectations. Customers expect product customization, faster delivery, and cheaper production.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 821,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a common idea between lean manufacturing and agile manufacturing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Productivity",
            "b) Empowering people",
            "c) Response to customer demands",
            "d) Reduction in waste"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Constant technological development, increasing complex supply chain, and higher customer standards are some of the reasons for organizations to switch to agile manufacturing. There are new technologies appearing every day and manufacturing experiences more disruptions.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 822,
        "Question": "______ refers to replacing workers with machines and ______ refers to enhancing workers’ capabilities through technology.",
        "Options": [
            "a) Innovation, augmentation",
            "b) Automation, augmentation",
            "c) Augmentation, automation",
            "d) Innovation, automation"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Both lean manufacturing and agile manufacturing focuses on the ideas of productivity, empowering people, and response to customer demands. They both focus on increasing quality. But, lean manufacturing alone focuses on reduction in waste. It is not a central idea in agile manufacturing. Agile manufacturing focuses on flexibility and bottom-up innovation.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 823,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of the bottom-up approach of agile manufacturing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Shop floor workers have a voice",
            "b) Low engagement",
            "c) High value products and processes",
            "d) Seamless flow of ideas"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: Automation refers to replacing workers with machines and augmentation refers to enhancing workers’ capabilities through technology. Augmentation is one of the principles of agile manufacturing.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 824,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not a reason for organizations to adopt flexible systems under agile manufacturing?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Increasing fluctuations in demand",
            "b) Economic factors",
            "c) Political factors",
            "d) Waterfall model"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: a\nExplanation: Agile manufacturing focuses on a bottom-up approach. It abandons the traditional hierarchical top-down approach and inherits the flexible bottom-up approach.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 825,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not related to an agile organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Silo mentality",
            "b) Real-time communication and work management tools",
            "c) Interactive digital work instructions",
            "d) Concept of hackathons"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: b\nExplanation: By implementation of the bottom-up approach of agile manufacturing, the shop floor workers in an organization get a voice. There is a seamless flow of ideas across all the layers of the organization. It also leads to high value products and processes.\n"
    },
    {
        "id": 826,
        "Question": "Which of the following is not found in an agile organization?",
        "Options": [
            "a) Accountability",
            "b) Transparency",
            "c) Collaborations",
            "d) Leaders ruling over employees"
        ],
        "Answer": "Answer: d\nExplanation: Increasing fluctuations in demand, labor rates, input prices along with economic factors, environmental factors, political factors, social factors and political factors are some of the reasons for organizations to adopt flexible systems under agile manufacturing. Agile concept was initially brought in to move away from the Waterfall Model.\n"
    }
]